<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Aero Blasters (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Aero Blasters</name>
		<desc>The player controls a small craft through different levels with many enemies. Every level ends with a boss and some section speed up the gameplay, offering fast obstacle courses both horizontally and vertically scrolling. Flying orange pods release many power-ups at once, enhancing the ships with new or more powerful lasers, wing men and shields. The player can also hold the fire key to charge a blast that removes all enemy bullets from the screen and deals damage to all enemies. With an unforgiving difficulty, every hit is fatal, but the game can be continued from any points as long as there are lives and credits left. The game can be played with two players cooperatively.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Aero Blasters (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Kaneko</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Akumajou_Dracula_X_-_Chi_no_Rinne_(NTSC-J)_[KMCD3005].cue</path>
		<name>AKUMAJOU DRACULA X - CHI NO RONDO</name>
		<desc>Castlevania: Rondo of Blood (Akumajou Dracula X: Chi no Rondo) is a 2-D side-scrolling platformer with a gothic horror theme.  Released in 1993, this game features the ability to save a player's progress, advances the plot via full-screen cutscenes, and utilizes CD audio tracks instead of the PC Engine's HUCard, producing a higher quality of musical audio.

Set in the year 1792, you play as Richter Belmont, a vampire hunter.  The dark priest Shaft has kidnapped Annette Renard, Richter's main love interest, and taken her to Castlevania along with a handful of other female victims.  Wielding an ancestral whip imbued with holy powers to crush darkness, Richter heads out into the night alone to rescue the victims and deal out some justice, Belmont style.

The game is divided up into multiple stages, some hidden, where the goal is to reach the end of each and (usually) face a boss monster.  Along the way you may collect hearts from candles to power one of 6 different subweapons; the dagger, holy water, axe, cross, grimoire, and stopwatch.  Each subweapon has a specific style of use and special "Item Crash" attack, which allows for an expensive but devastating super attack.

Numerous hidden secrets may be found during the adventure, opening up pathways to new stages or leading to one of the four victims to rescue; one of which becomes a playable character after being freed.  The victims Richter is able to rescue will affect which of the multiple endings you will see.  Even if a maiden is missed, however, the player can return to any unlocked level later and take another shot at discovering any secrets they may have missed via the main menu's stage select.

Rondo of Blood has great looking graphics, serves up multiple endings, plenty of secrets to discover, offers a decent difficulty level, and a delivers a quality soundtrack.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Akumajou_Dracula_X_-_Chi_no_Rinne_(NTSC-J)_[KMCD3005]-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>10.000000</rating>
		<releasedate>10/29/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alien Crush (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Alien Crush</name>
		<desc>Imagine a living pinball machine...with aliens and outlandish worlds to throw at you. And turbo-charged, speed-of-light pinball action. You control the flippers and ball speed to defeat the Slime, the Tentacloid and Scorpion. Go for the eyes! This is full-tilt, out-of-this-world action! Surrealistic graphics plus true-to-life, earsplitting arcade pinball sound.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Alien Crush (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Aoi Blink (Japan) [En by Gaijin+Zatos v0.99b].pce</path>
		<name>Aoi Blink</name>
		<desc>Based on a TV anime series (from the grandfather of manga Osamu Tezuka), Blue Blink is a cute platformer that manages to find its place among the crowd. The game is divided up into different areas, each represented by a map screen. Within these areas, you can choose your route to the end (by exiting levels at certain points). Throughout each area you have to find a 'master key' allowing you access to the boss - this can be hard to locate at times and requires lots of shooting at blank areas of screen just in case.

Control of your character is original - on each stage you have three characters which you can choose between, with the CPU controlled ones following behind you like some bizarre congo line. The characters are preset and vary from stage to stage, and each one has different attributes. For example, some have very high jumping ability, whereas others are poor at jumping but have spread-shot weapons. Once you have found the master key and reached the final level in the area, you are entered into a boss battle, where you sit astride the titular donkey and attempt to fight your way to the next area.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Aoi Blink (Japan) [En by Gaijin+Zatos v0.99b]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>04/27/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ballistix (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Ballistix</name>
		<desc>It's chaos in the Ballistix Stadium! You're a techno-gladiator in the wildest ballgame in the galaxy. The alien claw drops the puck. You fire balls at warp-speed, blasting it towards the enemy goal. Ricochet it off walls and bumpers. Hit a splitter and balls explode in a swarming barrage! The field changes to make each level more intense. Acid pools swallow the puck. Pitch arrows propel it. Your enemy cannons it into a tunnel and it shoots out towards your goal! Get a shield to save it! Score big to enter your name in the Hall of Fame in a nonstop Ballistix frenzy.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ballistix (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Psygnosis</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battle Royale (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Battle Royale</name>
		<desc>It's wrestling mayhem out of control! Five maniacs hit the mat in a no-holds-barred, free-for-all brawl with no rules, no refs and absolutely no mercy! Team up with friends to nail opponents. Now look out! They're coming after you! Smash 'em, bash 'em and throw 'em over the ropes! The sound is so intense you'll feel every crushing hit, every cracking bone. It's furious, non-stop action for up to five players ... a winner-take-all gang fight for survival!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Battle Royale (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Incredible Technologies</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Beyond Shadowgate (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Beyond Shadowgate</name>
		<desc>As the last descendant in the "Line of Kings", Prince Erik is summoned home to regain his rightful place on his father's throne. But alas, Prince Erik is accused of his father's murder by the evil Royal Advisor Belezaar, and is thrown into the dungeon to be executed at dawn. Your mission and destiny are intertwined. Escape the dungeon and start your long journey toward the land deep within Castle Shadowgate. Your quest is to free the kingdom from the evil grips of the Warlock Lord. You will need to make good use of all the resources you can find throughout your journey. Evil abounds, and creatures great and small will try to defeat you! Use the good that comes of it because the Legend of Shadowgate rests in your hands!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Beyond Shadowgate (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>ICOM</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bikkuriman World (Japan) [En by Demiforce v1.0].pce</path>
		<name>Bikkuriman World: Gekitou Sei Senshi</name>
		<desc>Bikkuriman World: Gekitou Sei Senshi is a Role-Playing game, developed by Atlus and published by Hudson, which was released in Japan in 1990.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bikkuriman World (Japan) [En by Demiforce v1.0]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/27/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Atlus</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Blazing Lazers (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Blazing Lazers</name>
		<desc>Blazing Lazers is a top-down shooter featuring 9 levels of varied and fast-paced action. The story here is the usual save-the-world variety. You must pilot your ship against 8 super-weapons and ultimately destroy the menace once and for all.

The power-up system in Blazing Lazers deserves special mention. There are four main types of weapons, and each type of weapon can be upgraded several times to produce an incredible amount of firepower. In addition, there are secondary weapons systems that provide you with shields, homing missiles, multi-fire units, or super weapon power.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Blazing Lazers (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bloody Wolf (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bloody Wolf</name>
		<desc>Snake and Eagle, two commandos of the Bloody Wolf special forces, receive instructions from their commander to destroy the enemy's heavily armed base to rescue the President and any allies who have been reported as MIA.

Based off the 1988 arcade game, this single-player, top-down, run and gun shooter takes a nod to Contra-style gameplay, allowing one of the two mercenaries to blast their way through eight levels of enemy opposition armed with only a knife and a machine gun. 

Along the way, new weapons such as shotguns, bazookas, flash bombs and grenades grenades can be added to the arsenal, as well as health and defensive power-ups. Players can even find a motorcycle to ride in some areas, or swim through certain parts of a level.

The President and your fellow soldiers need you!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bloody Wolf (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bomberman (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bomberman</name>
		<desc>The black spaceman kidnapped Bomberman's beloved and brought her to his chambers in the castle, far beyond his reach, over the rivers, forest and mountains. Bomberman's job is to save her, battling the sea of the enemies, with only bombs at his disposal.

The range of Bomberman's bomb explosions can be upgraded with time, but if he dies, the range resets back to the minimum range and Bomberman loses his previous skills. Some updates can make Bomberman walk through the walls, increase his speed, and give him some other assets to aid him in his quest to save the woman he loves.

This top-down action-arcade game consists of nine levels per stage, each tougher than the other, and each final one consisting of the boss that will have to be dealt with. Bomberman can move horizontally and vertically and lay down bombs behind him, thus evaporating the enemies, but beware: Bomberman can block himself with his own bomb, and thus become a victim of his own bomb.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bomberman (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies Inc.</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bomberman '93 (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bomberman '93</name>
		<desc>Tension, strategy, action, excitement - Bomberman's back!

You can now battle against up to four computer-controlled maniacs by yourself for the ultimate five bomberman mode.
Choose from seven exciting new stages with loads of new power-up items like werps, conveyer belts, revolving doors and even kicking bombs!
Or for portable thrills, go head-to-head against a friend using TurboExpress for non-stop action.
The best competitive game is back, and it's more intense than ever!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bomberman '93 (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>TTI</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bomberman_'94_Taikenban_(NTSC-J)_[HCD3054].cue</path>
		<name>Bomberman '94</name>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bomberman_'94_Taikenban_(NTSC-J)_[HCD3054]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bomberman_-_Panic_Bomber_(NTSC-J)_[HCD4069].cue</path>
		<name>Bomberman: Panic Bomber</name>
		<desc>It is a "falling blocks" puzzle game based on the Bomberman franchise. The goal of the game is essentially to cause your opponent to lose by causing their gameplay field to fill to the top with objects. You do this by causing chains of bombs to explode, sending useless rubble over to your opponent's field, which they must then remove themselves. Bombs are earned by causing chains of three identical blocks to disappear. Bombs can only be blown up with an explosion from a lit bomb, which falls from the top of the screen every so often. If the player causes enough damage, they can eventually earn a giant bomb, which will remove a large amount of debris from the playing field, and cause their opponent a good deal of trouble.

The game's regular story mode revolves around Bomberman's hunt for the Golden Bomber statue. During his trek, he fights against several different odd characters, like Drifty the balloon, or Cecil the tiger. However, all that can really be earned from playing through this mode is a harder difficulty level, earned by finishing the entire story at the "hard" difficulty level.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bomberman_-_Panic_Bomber_(NTSC-J)_[HCD4069]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bonk 3 - Bonk's Big Adventure (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Bonk 3: Bonk's Big Adventure (Super CD)</name>
		<desc>Aaagh! What's that Evil King drool doing back in the Dinosaur Kingdom?! Didn't Bonk get rid of him last time? Guess not, huh? Now it's up to our skull-splitting, head-butting, rock-smashing, monster-bashing prehistoric hero Bonk to put an end to Drool's dastardly deeds once and for all! Watch Bonk grown into huge fire-breathing Bonk or shrink into the Mini-Size Bonk and take on tons of cool new enemies like RocketMan, Robo Turtle and Crazy Lady. Or how about smashing up a few Booga Boogas or Snippies along the way. It's the ultimate bash-o-rama!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bonk 3 - Bonk's Big Adventure (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/01/1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bonk 3: Bonk's Big Adventure (Turbo Chip)</name>
		<desc>Bonk's Big Adventure is the third instalment in the side-scrolling platformer series. As in previous games, the player assumes the role of a caveman named Bonk who headbutts his way through various enemies in order to defeat King Drool. Familiar moves include swinging on trees, bouncing off walls, breaking blocks and climbing walls with his teeth. Compared to the previous games, he walks and moves a little faster.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>04/02/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bonk's Adventure (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bonk's Adventure</name>
		<desc>The game's protagonist is Bonk, a strong caveboy who battles anthropomorphic dinosaurs and other prehistoric themed enemies. Bonk's mission is to rescue Princess Za (a small pink Pleisiosaur-type reptile) who has been kidnapped by the evil King Drool (a large, green, Tyrannosaurus-type dinosaur). In the Arcade version, Bonk is also assisted by a female version of himself.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bonk's Adventure (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bonk's Revenge (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bonk's Revenge</name>
		<desc>Bonk is back! Last year's video smash is bashing his way through a totally awesome new adventure! Help that radical cave dude save the Dinosaur Kingdom from the heinous King Drool III. Bigger, badder bosses. More powerful power-ups. More excellent hidden secrets. And more worlds of pre-hysterical action that'll have you cracking up while you're out cracking heads. Blast back to the Bonk Age, mankind's coolest era, and Bonk yourself out!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bonk's Revenge (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Mutech</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Boxyboy (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Boxyboy</name>
		<desc>The player controls a worker in a warehouse. Gameplay is simple: the goal of each level is to push the crates onto specific squares marked with a yellow dot. It's very easy to get boxes trapped, so the player must carefully consider the route.

Boxyboy also features a level editor for players to create and play their own levels.

In Japan, Boxyboy is known as Sokoban World and is an official part of the Sokoban series.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Boxyboy (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>3.000000</rating>
		<releasedate>03/16/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Media Rings Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bravoman (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Bravoman</name>
		<desc>The village of Nitta has been invaded by the army of Dr. Bomb, an evil scientist who is plotting to take over the world. Facing this crisis is Bravoman, who received his powers from Alpha Man to stand up against Dr. Bomb in the name of justice. The village of Nitta consists of 22 stages -- action stages that take place on the ground and shooting stages that take place underwater. Action stages use a unique control system in which the height of a jump and the distance of an attack changes depending on how long players hold down the button. Players collect the Luck Symbols that appear when they defeat enemies and give them to Lottery Man to get recovery and power-up items. Stop Dr. Bomb and bring peace to the village of Nitta and the rest of the world.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bravoman (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bubblegum Crash! - Knight Sabers 2034 (Japan) [En by Dave Shadoff+Filler+Tomaitheous v1.0].pce</path>
		<name>Bubblegum Crash</name>
		<desc>This is an adventure game based on the sequel to the superb classic cyberpunk anime Bubblegum Crisis. It puts you in the shoes of Nene from the Knight Sabers, a group of women in power suits out to sort out the problems that the AD Police can’t handle.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Bubblegum Crash! - Knight Sabers 2034 (Japan) [En by Dave Shadoff+Filler+Tomaitheous v1.0]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/06/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>NAXAT</developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cadash (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Cadash</name>
		<desc>Arise brave warrior, our services are once again needed! Baarogue the Destroyer has kidnapped the King's only daughter, Princess Sarasa, and is now bent on universal dominance! Become a powerful Fighter, a resourceful Mage, a magic-laden Priestess, or an agile Ninja in your quest to return peace to the once-tranquil land of Deerzar! Be wary on the path to your goal! Baarogue has littered it with many foes, from the re-animated Hands of Stone to the Giant Pedra- Pods of Dokra-ri. Enlist the services of a trustworthy friend to aid you, for this quest allows two brave souls to venture forth via the Turbo Tap. You must succeed, for Baarogue's dark power grows by the second, and soon no soul will be able to halt his advance!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Cadash (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Champions Forever Boxing (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Champions Forever Boxing</name>
		<desc>It's Ali, Foreman, Frazier, Holmes and Norton -- five of the world's greatest heavyweight boxing champs! Be them or battle them. Each has his actual physical traits and boxing style. Move and jab, or go toe-to-toe and unleash a flurry of punishing hooks, uppercuts and body shots. Protect yourself by blocking punches or clinching. Taunt opponents with showboat moves if you've got the guts. Fight exhibition matches or an entire 15-year career. Between round close-ups show each boxer's facial damage. Beat these five legends and become a Champion Forever!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Champions Forever Boxing (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Distinctive Software</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Taito Chase H.Q. (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Chase H.Q.</name>
		<desc>The fastest, most thrilling, 3D driving game yet! Take the wheel of your turbo-charged Porsche as you and your partner go in pursuit of dangerous criminals all driving an evil array of souped-up roadsters. TURBO BOOST! Need to catch up in a hurry? Well, just one press of your Turbo Button will leave your eyes in the back of your head! Barrelling through the city streets, along the roughest of dirt tracks and through busy tunnels - if you can hold the line! The low-life can run, but they can't hide...</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Taito Chase H.Q. (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Daiei Seisakusho</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Chew Man Fu (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Chew Man Fu</name>
		<desc>Chew-Man-Fu has gone too far! His evil curse deprives you, (and everyone else), of your beloved egg rolls and fried rice. To break his spell, roll 4 magic balls through a maze to matching colored squares. Sound easy? Hah! Chew's whole zoo is out to stop you. Prickly porcupines, wily penguins, rowdy apes and more! Use those balls to clobber 'em and smash through the walls. With 5 worlds and 550 wild rounds, the fun never stops.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Chew Man Fu (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./China Warrior (USA).pce</path>
		<name>China Warrior</name>
		<desc>Boss Kara and his evil horde has captured the entire kungfu province. You are summoned - You obediently go knowing full any of Kara's bullies could no doubt put out your lights. You must face them and their specialties one by one .. then finally Kara himself. A sip of a sacred tea releases hidden powers, but will it be enough? Play it so .... a hundred million Chinese are counting on it.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/China Warrior (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cratermaze (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Cratermaze</name>
		<desc>The evil Kublai from Zenzombie Land, has kidnapped four of your friends as you time-travelled on a magic carpet. Now you must rescue them. But run for your life! You're in a maze of monsters!

Hit them with your YOYO! Dig a hole so they'll fall in! Shoot them with your Freeze Beam! Kill them dead with your Bubble Gun! There are 60 incredible levels of action. So wear your helmet and watch your step!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Cratermaze (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cyber Core (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Cyber-Core</name>
		<desc>Cyber-core is a vertically scrolling shooter in which the player fights insects. The basic idea is traditional: shooting everything before they can shoot/touch the player: after three hits the chitin armor breaks and a life is lost. Besides flying enemies which are disposed of with the standard gun, the player also has to deal with enemies on the ground which need to be hit with one of the unlimited bomb.

The player has the choice between four insect forms which are changed by collecting the associated extra symbols. Collecting more of the same symbol upgrades the insect, but this also rises the difficulty level. Other extras include smart bombs, extra lives, armor refreshments or a protection shield. The game features the possibility to turn on rapid fire or to slow down the speed as well as big boss enemies at the end and within the levels.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Cyber Core (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>AlfaSystem Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Information Global Service</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Darkwing Duck (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Darkwing Duck</name>
		<desc>The kingpins of crime are at it again! The mysterious criminal organization F.O.W.L. has hatched a plan to take control of the peaceful city of St. Canard. Six of their most heinous henchmen are running rampant through the city and only the daring Darkwing Duck can bring them to justice! Join Darkwing as he explores the woods to weed out Bushroot's evil plan. Search the warehouses along the wharf for Mega Volt and pull the plug on an electrifying scheme. Track down all six of FOWL's crafty criminals and then prepare yourself as Darkwing squares off against the sinister Steelbeak in his fiendish floating fortress!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Darkwing Duck (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Radiance Software, Interactive Designs</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Davis Cup Tennis (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Davis Cup Tennis</name>
		<desc>Challenge 32 top-seeded international pros in explosive court action, or take on your friends with tons of real playing options and a true player's view! Command an arsenal of pinpoint serves and powerful baseline passing shots. Attack the net with topspin or dropshot volleys. Then destroy your opponent's lob and morale with your overhead smash. Play singles and doubles on grass, clay, indoors or hard-court in exhibition and worldwide tournaments. Practice against the ball machine to perfect your skills for the ultimate quest, the coveted Davis Cup!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Davis Cup Tennis (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Loriciel</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dead Moon (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Dead Moon</name>
		<desc>Alpha 27, the one planet in the galaxy that is fit for human habitation. For many years, the space observation system here was used for a wide range of research. One day, horrifying news arrived- a giant comet was hurtling toward the solar system, on its present course, it was going to colide with the moon. and then....Nothing! For some strange reason the humans and the moon seemed completely unaffected. The humans were unaware that a new nightmare had already begun. The giant comet had changed shape- it was not a comet at all, it was an alien mothership!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Dead Moon (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Natsume</developer>
		<publisher>Natsume</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Deep Blue (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Deep Blue</name>
		<desc>You command an A.N.G.E.L. Fish Attack Sub. Your mission: rid the oceans of the evil aliens in their Undersea Palace deep in the ocean depths. On top of the water, all is calm and beautiful. But as you descend toward the Palace, you won't believe your goggles! Scaled creatures snarl. Swarms of mutant fish attack. Power up! Use the Swirl Cutter! Energy Fin full-throttle ... Fire! Fire! Fire!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Deep Blue (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Pack-in-Video</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Devil's Crush - Naxat Pinball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Devil's Crush</name>
		<desc>Play video pinball that will set you on fire! Explosive graphics and demonic sound beckon you to the underworld for a devilish pinball simulation. Rebound off the She-Giant. So beautiful when she sleeps. So evil when she awakens. Burn up in the bonus rounds where dragons will roast you, skeletons will toast you and sorcerers will plan a barbecue around you. Finally, if you flip your way past them all, fight the ultimate Armageddon!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Devil's Crush - Naxat Pinball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>NAXAT Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dungeons - W (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Double Dungeons</name>
		<desc>Summoned by the King, you are the last hope of a once peaceful land. Journey deep within the earth on your quest to destroy a strange, unnatural force. With new "split screen" action you and a partner can work together to uncover the mysteries of the eerie underground labyrinth and its evil inhabitants. Face the Death Crow, Pumpkin Head, and Savage Elf in over 22 levels of chilling adventure. You won't want to travel alone - and you don't have to!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Double Dungeons - W (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>NCS</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Spirit (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Dragon Spirit</name>
		<desc>Amur, the spirit of the dragon, lives within you. As the winged creature that breathes mega-tons of fire, your mission is revealed. Rescue Princess Alicia from Zowel, Demon of Darkness. So take to the skies and destroy enemy creatures with breath and fireballs. Add dragon heads and incredible power-ups. Confront Zowel in a Super Battle of Beasts! (Careful not to breathe on Alicia).</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Dragon Spirit (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon's Curse (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Dragon's Curse</name>
		<desc>Poor Hu-Man! he just isn't his old self. Trying to escape from the evil dragon Mecha, he's transformed into the horrific Lizard Man! Get ready to kick some serious dragon tail, because 5 more are waiting to stop you. Each is more vicious than the last. And each turns Hu-Man into a different kind of total gross out! Slash 'em, burn 'em, and blow 'em away! Then capture the Salamander Cross to break the DRAGON'S CURSE.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Dragon's Curse (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Drop.Off (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Drop Off</name>
		<desc>There's no waking up from this nightmare! You'll need all your nerve and strategy to get out alive! A dream of giant apples and diamonds goes berserk when they turn into deadly demons raining down on your head! You have to shoot 'em down with a steel ball. Ricochet your shots to knock 'em off in bunches! They're coming fast, and each level is more threatening than the last! Why are those skulls laughing? Shoot first and ask questions later!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Drop.Off (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dungeon Explorer (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Dungeon Explorer</name>
		<desc>You, brave soldier, are the last hope of a once-peaceful Oddesia. Yours is a strange world full of magic, hidden dangers and potions. But you have powerful friends. Use them to recover the ORA Stone which was hidden from the conquering evil king, Natas. Deep within the ancient dungeons lies the Stone with powers of life, light, happiness. But where?</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Dungeon Explorer (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Atlus</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Order of the Griffon (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Order of the Griffon</name>
		<desc>The Vampire has escaped and has arisen again just as the Ancient Ones predicted. The Vampire controls bands of monsters who do his destructive bidding. Using the evil Iron Ring, he bends the will of the common people in an attempt to take over the world. Even the great Radlebb Keep has been conquered by the Dark Once and been bent to his evil will.
Now, with your character in the Order of the Griffon, we have a chance to defeat the evil Vampire! World peace can be restored!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Order of the Griffon (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Strategic Simulations, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Falcon (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Falcon</name>
		<desc>Fly multiple missions with varying skill levels, including both Air-to-Air and Air-to-Ground. Explosive aerial combat action as you intercept enemy aircraft or "take out" strategic ground targets - missile sites, bunkers, airfields, and buildings. View all the action in "first-person" perspective from the cockpit of your F-16 Falcon.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Falcon (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Spectrum HoloByte</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fantasy Zone (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Fantasy Zone</name>
		<desc>An evil force has overcome this beautiful land of awesome colors and peaceful people. Plundering Golden Rubicom coins, your enemy is an intergalactic band of thieves. Armed with cannon and bombs, you must recover the stolen coins to buy expanded powers. But be careful! The alien Super Boss waits in ambush. Restore order for the Federation or kiss the galaxy's favorite vacation place good-bye!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Fantasy Zone (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Final Lap Twin (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Final Lap Twin</name>
		<desc>Final Lap Twin is a hybrid racing/role-playing game released for the PC Engine in 1989 and the TurboGrafx-16 in 1990, as a spin-off to the 1987 arcade game Final Lap. The protagonist is on a quest to live up to the reputation of his racing-champion dad. He travels over the map, meeting small-time racers, and must race his car to earn money that he spends on upgrading his car, eventually facing the local racing champion. After beating the rest of the local racing champions in the various cities, the protagonist must go through a maze to find the final upgrades of the different parts of his car, and then face the world racing champion.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Final Lap Twin (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Nova Games Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Galaga '90 (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Galaga '90</name>
		<desc>Galaga is a smouldering planet that often erupts with angry mutants and misfits. As Galactic commander of the Federal Army, you have the job of making them dead. Not easy! Because they come at you in clusters like swarms of killer bees. This time, you will be flying the awesome Triple Proton Fighter that warps to new dimensions and increased firepower. Galaga goons, your graveyard awaits.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Galaga '90 (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/03/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gate_of_Thunder_(NTSC-J)_[HCD2025].cue</path>
		<name>Gate of Thunder</name>
		<desc>Gate of Thunder is a 1992 scrolling shooter by Hudson Soft and Red Entertainment for the PC Engine Super CD-ROM2. It was also a pack-in game for the TurboDuo in North America,[1] where it was bundled with Bonk's Adventure, Bonk's Revenge, and Bomberman (the last one playable only after entering a code) on the same disc. It was released on the Wii Virtual Console on October 15, 2007 in North America and on December 4, 2007 in Japan. The game is the first CD based game on the American Virtual Console.[2] It was released on the PlayStation Network on March 17, 2010 in Japan.

The player controls the spaceship Hunting Dog, piloted by a space cop named Hawk. Along with ally Esty and her ship the Wild Cat, Hawk must stop General Don Jingi and his Obellon army from taking a powerful energy source called "Starlight" from the planet of Aries.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Gate_of_Thunder_(NTSC-J)_[HCD2025]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>02/21/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft, Red Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gekisha Boy (Japan) [En by Zatos v0.99] (~Photograph Boy).pce</path>
		<name>Gekibo: Gekisha Boy</name>
		<desc>David Goldman is an amateur photographer, who always loved to take pictures. One day, he went to Los Angeles Photography School to study more about taking pictures. Everyday, David commutes on the crowded trains, but trained and learned better in the academy so he can achieve his dreams on becoming the best photographer he ever wished for. He was happy at that time, but suddenly misfortune hit him. David's parents suddenly died in a plane crash, leaving him orphaned and all alone. He loved his parents deeply and cried at their burial, thinking that they will come back. David lost his confidence and is about to leave the academy to live a lonely and sad life. However for Dean, the principal of the academy saw him and made an unexpected proposal to him. The principal said if he completed 8 tests by taking 8 special photograph shots in 8 different locations, then he's allowed to graduate in the academy. Unsure about this offer, David still accepted the test and did everything he could to pass.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Gekisha Boy (Japan) [En by Zatos v0.99] (~Photograph Boy)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>10/02/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Tomcat System</developer>
		<publisher>Irem</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ghost Manor (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Ghost Manor</name>
		<desc>With an earth-shattering explosion, horror from another dimension grips your once peaceful town. Gristly creatures prey on the innocent. The dead rise to roam the streets. All resistance falls! But hey, no problem, you have a plan! Find the secret passage to their mansion stronghold and battle past the zombies and ghouls. Now get your axe, because it's way full of demons and ghastly surprises! Ride the awesome Skull Slammer and search for their leader, the hideous Orb gamut. Discover his weakness and be a hero. If you don't, you'll be dust.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ghost Manor (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gunboat (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Gunboat</name>
		<desc>Twist down treacherous jungle waters with eight tons of firepower and the threat of a deadly ambush around every bend. Command a Navy River Patrol Boat (PBR) in the most hostile and claustrophobic action -- riverine warfare! First hone your critical combat skills with gunnery, grenade and pilot practice. Then report for duty and equip your boat with the hottest weaponry for the mission. Take out enemy craft with twin armor-piercing .50 caliber machine guns. Blast land-based positions with 40mm grenades or fire your 60mm Mortar Launcher and get ready to hit the deck!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Gunboat (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Accolade</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hit the Ice - VHL the Official Video Hockey League (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Hit the Ice</name>
		<desc>If you've ever heard the joke, "The other night I went to a fight, and a hockey game broke out," then you already know what Hit the Ice is all about. This is rough and tumble, no holds barred hockey action that will challenge your stick-handling skills as well as your head-bashing abilities. While the traditional rules of hockey apply, that doesn't mean you can't throw an elbow or a high stick when the ref isn't looking. And since this is two-on-two hockey, the action is fast and furious as you try to outscore and outslug your opponent in four-player hockey action.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Hit the Ice - VHL the Official Video Hockey League (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Taito</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SideArms - Hyper Dyne (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Hyper Dyne Side Arms Special</name>
		<desc>Hyper Dyne Side Arms Special is an Action game, developed by Capcom and published by NEC Interchannel, which was released in Japan in 1989.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/SideArms - Hyper Dyne (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/15/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Interchannel</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Impossamole (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Impossamole</name>
		<desc>For Monty Mole, a day at the beach turns into the adventure of his life when he's beamed aboard an alien spacecraft. He's transformed into Impossamole, with super powers to save their planet from the evil Vlarg! Now you're up to your cape in Vlarg's monster bosses with crack-up creatures ready to nail your tail! Power up your laser to blast the Dragon Boss. Bomb the Abominable Snowman. Then trash the Venus Moletrap before he has you for lunch. Swim, fly and blast through five wacky action-packed worlds. The fiendish Vlarg awaits your final desperate battle!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Impossamole (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Gremlin Interactive Limited</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./J.J. &amp; Jeff (USA).pce</path>
		<name>J.J. &amp; Jeff</name>
		<desc>J.J. &amp; Jeff Detective Agency are assigned the task of locating a missing rich man, and you can choose either J.J. or Jeff to go on the mission. Your partner doesn't like this one bit, so he decides to make a nuisance of himself along the way. Similar to Adventure Island, you must make your way through several levels, destroying wildlife along the way, but instead of using a hammer, you have three different ways to kill them: jump on or kick them, or when they are walking on the ground, blow gas out of them.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/J.J. &amp; Jeff (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>11/30/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jack Nicklaus' Turbo Golf (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Jack Nicklaus Turbo Golf</name>
		<desc>Jack Nicklaus: Turbo Golf is a Sports game, developed by Accolade and published by Victor Interactive Software, which was released in 1990.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Jack Nicklaus' Turbo Golf (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Accolade</developer>
		<publisher>Victor Interactive Software</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu</name>
		<desc>Jackie and his sister, Josephine, are tough on tyrants. As China's supreme kung fu champs, they guard their country against the Prince of Sorcerers, who lurks just beyond the Great Wall. It comes as no surprise when this fiend and his ghouls try yet again to seize China for themselves. But this time they're clever, casting a spell over Josephine which causes her to vanish into thin air! Jackie is in shock! How can he save his country without his sister? The two have been an unbeatable team! Meanwhile, a demon horde led by the Sorcerer storms the Great Wall and prepares to establish a fierce empire. At the urging of his revered Master, Jackie must now battle the dreaded Sorcerer and rescue Josephine. Maybe he can learn a little magic on his own, because he's going to need all the help he can get!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Keith Courage in Alpha Zones (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Keith Courage in Alpha Zones</name>
		<desc>Keith Courage in Alpha Zones is an Action game, developed and published by Hudson, which was released in 1989.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Keith Courage in Alpha Zones (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./King of Casino (USA).pce</path>
		<name>King Of Casino</name>
		<desc>The chips are down as you and your buddies travel to Vegas in this high stakes adventure. Match wits (and luck!) against the house or up to four of your friends in a game with all the glitz and glamor of a real casino. Play Poker, Blackjack, slot machines, Keno or Roulette. Choose one of 15 different casinos. You're the odds-on favorite in this high-rolling gambling simulation.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/King of Casino (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Victor Musical Industries</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Klax (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Klax</name>
		<desc>In Klax, you take control of a paddle at the end of a conveyer belt, while colored tiles flip toward you down the conveyer belt. You must collect and arrange the tiles into horizontal, vertical, or diagonal groups of three referred to as klaxes. To a clear a stage, you must meet certain goals, which can include obtaining a certain number of klaxes, creating a particular arrangement of tiles, or collecting a certain number of tiles on your paddle. See how many stages you can get through in Klax.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Klax (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Tengen</developer>
		<publisher>Tengen</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Legend of Hero Tonma (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Legend of Hero Tonma</name>
		<desc>Legend of Hero Tonma is an action game that puts players in control of the magic-user Tonma, whose role – as was typical for game heroes of the day – is to travel to another world and save the princess. Fight your way through seven stages using Tonma’s jump ability and shot power. Collect power-ups and barriers to grow in strength and pummel your enemies. Bring that strength to the end of each stage to face off against and defeat the menacing bosses that aim to keep you from the princess.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Legend of Hero Tonma (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Legendary Axe, The (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Legendary Axe II</name>
		<desc>The Axe is back ... with twice the force and twice the fury of 1988's classic TurboGrafx-16 videogame. This time it's brother against brother, locked in deadly combat. Your older brother has summoned forces of unspeakable evil to take control of the kingdom. Treachery rules! Your only hope is the legendary royal sword. But will its power be enough to overcome the Cliffs of Chaos? The Skull Dungeon? And the treacherous Crypts of Slime? Only your courage, your fighting skill, and the Legendary Axe can answer that challenge!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Legendary Axe, The (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Atlus</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Legendary Axe II, The (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Legendary Axe II</name>
		<desc>The Axe is back ... with twice the force and twice the fury of 1988's classic TurboGrafx-16 videogame. This time it's brother against brother, locked in deadly combat. Your older brother has summoned forces of unspeakable evil to take control of the kingdom. Treachery rules! Your only hope is the legendary royal sword. But will its power be enough to overcome the Cliffs of Chaos? The Skull Dungeon? And the treacherous Crypts of Slime? Only your courage, your fighting skill, and the Legendary Axe can answer that challenge!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Legendary Axe II, The (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Atlus</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Loom (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Loom</name>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Loom (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lords of Thunder (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Lords of Thunder</name>
		<desc>Lords of Thunder is a side-scrolling shooter that has you take on the role of a legendary warrior, blasting enemies to heavy-metal tunes. Your enemies are plotting to revive Zaggart, "The Dark One," who was sealed beneath the six continents of Mistral. It's up to Landis, descendant of the heroic Dyu, to stop them.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Lords of Thunder (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>RED Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Magical Chase (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Magical Chase</name>
		<desc>Ripple is a student of magic, and her teacher is a terrifying witch. Ripple is particularly afraid of her teacher right now, because she's just broken a promise she made to the witch: Ripple took a peek inside the forbidden book Sleeping Demons! No sooner had she opened the cover then out jumped six demons, all of which raced away! Unless she can catch all six demons and get them back inside the book, the witch will turn Ripple into a frog for breaking her promise! So Ripple sets off on her quest with her two Elf-Star friends, Topsy and Turvy. Good luck, Ripple!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Magical Chase (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Quest</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Military Madness (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Military Madness</name>
		<desc>Space on Earth has become limited, and mankind has looked to colonize the moon. A group known as the Axis Powers has seized control over most of the lunar surface, and it's up to you as a member of the Allied Powers to fight against them. As you move around the map (shown in a top-down 2D perspective), enemy combatants will try and stop you from achieving your goal. Once encountered, the screen shifts view points to a close-up view of the skirmish at hand.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Military Madness (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Moto Roader (USA).pce</path>
		<name>MOTOROADER MC</name>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Moto Roader (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Neutopia (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Neutopia</name>
		<desc>You are Jazeta, a berserker warrior, fearless in combat. Now you face your greatest quest: to rescue Princess Aurora from the evil Boss Dirth. Conquer a dangerous land of dungeons and demons, magic and monks. Choose which armor, what spell, which weapon you will use to capture each of the 8 medallions that bring you closer and closer to your final battle with demonic Dirth.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Neutopia (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Neutopia II (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Neutopia II</name>
		<desc>In the previous edition of Neutopia, Jazeta brought peace back to the land. But as long as evil and fear live in the human heart, the dreaded Dirth, Emperor of Darkness, will be plotting his return. The Emperor is stirring under the peaceful surface of Neutopia, bringing suffering to its people. Who will save them? Jazeta, the hero, is lost in a labyrinth in a foreign land. Can his son withstand the powers of the Emperor of Darkness to rescue the good people of Neutopia from fear and despair?</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Neutopia II (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./New Adventure Island (USA).pce</path>
		<name>New Adventure Island</name>
		<desc>On peaceful Adventure Island, the islanders are celebrating the wedding of Master Higgins and Tina, the "Miss Island Queen." Suddenly, the celebration is interrupted by the appearance of Baron Bronsky and his henchmen, who kidnap Tina and the island children. Master Higgins must set out to rescue the children and his beloved Tina in this side-scrolling action game. Throw hatchets and boomerangs, hop on skateboards and guide Master Higgins safely to the goal in each area. New Adventure Island consists of seven exciting stages. Each stage is split into four areas, with a boss waiting at the end of the final area. Defeat all the bosses and release the kidnapped children. And waiting in the castle of the final stage - the wicked Baron Bronsky. Help Master Higgins defeat him and reclaim his bride.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/New Adventure Island (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Night Creatures (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Night Creatures</name>
		<desc>Hecate, the Queen of Darkness, has feasted on your blood. Now you must destroy her or be hers forever, one of the Walking Undead. Hecate's bite has given you the power to change into a wolf, a bear, and other animals to battle hordes of monsters and ghouls who protect her. You must search for the one correct route through level after level of unspeakable terror to find her. Choose the most devastating weapons and become the animal best able to fight each fiend. Will you defeat Hecate or become her grotesque slave for eternity? Either way, the Queen of Darkness waits for you!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Night Creatures (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Manley and Associates</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ninja Spirit (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Ninja Spirit</name>
		<desc>Play as the ninja Moonlight and engage in a fierce battle to avenge his father's death and unlock the secrets of his birth. Select between the original Arcade Mode and PC-Engine MODE, which includes a life gauge. Use four types of weapons: katana, shuriken, bombs and chain and sickles to battle your way through the enemies. Pick up power-up items and switch between weapons to give you the advantage. You'll need to consider the enemy attacks and your weapon's abilities in order to deftly make it through all seven stages. Use your skills and attacks to get through the game's boundless enemies and traps. That's what ninja action is all about.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ninja Spirit (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ordyne (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Ordyne</name>
		<desc>The evil Kubota has kidnapped Dr. Tomari's fiancee, Kana, and taken the colossal nuclear reactor Ordyne. In order to reclaim them, Dr. Tomari and his assistant Felix take to their battleships and head off in pursuit. Avoid enemies and advance through seven different levels that take place on land, sea, and air. Collect crystals from defeated enemies and use them to buy items or upgrades for your ship at the Space Inn. Do you have what it takes to defeat the boss at the end of each level and ultimately reach Kubota in the final stage, Kubota World?</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ordyne (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Pac-Land (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Pac-Land</name>
		<desc>In Pac-Land, our friend Pac-Man is facing more daring adventures than ever before! In his new contest, Pac-Man comes face-to-face with ghosts on their own turf. In this 2D platforming adventure, his quiet day at home is disturbed by those nasty specters. A fairy princess has been kidnapped, and Pac-Man must leap over rivers, avoid dangerous water spouts, fly in magic shoes, dodge the Hoppers from the bushes, skip past the skulls aiming to drag you to Sand Prison -- all in the aims of reaching Monster Mansion and rescuing the princess to restore peace in Pac-Land!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Pac-Land (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Panza Kick Boxing (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Panza Kick Boxing</name>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Panza Kick Boxing (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Loriciel</developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Parasol Stars - The Story of Bubble Bobble III (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Parasol Stars: The Story of Bubble Bobble III</name>
		<desc>Break out the bandages and get ready for some finger-searing action! Join Bubby on his latest quest to save the universe, this time with a Magic Umbrella. Umbrella!? Yes, Umbrella! This powerful parasol puts the elements themselves at your command! Shock the tonnage out of the whales with Lightning! Fry the feathers off the crazed, beady-eyed birds with Fire! Or, drown the demented dinosaurs with a tidal wave of Raindrops! Need help? Your buddy Bobby is always nearby. Have a friend plug into your TurboTap and blast into two player simultaneous play. Be prepared for a quest that will take you to eight amazing planets, forcing you to uncover the secret that will unleash the Parasol Stars!

Parasol Stars is the third game in the Bubble Bobble franchise (and is often labeled "Parasol Stars: The Story Bubble Bobble III"), as well as a semi-official sequel to the second Bubble Bobble spin-off, Rainbow Island.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Parasol Stars - The Story of Bubble Bobble III (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/15/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Power Golf (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Power Golf</name>
		<desc>Swing away on 18 lush holes, enter tournaments and compete to win. Keep your head down and concentrate. Release a ton of power coming out of your backswing -- like a coiled spring! Follow through. You'll need a picture-perfect swing, flawless timing and a pro's club selection. Why, you ask? Because this is real. The traps are real, the water is real, the ball is real, and your score is real.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Power Golf (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Psychosis (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Psychosis</name>
		<desc>This is a side-scrolling shooter played in a world created from the mind of a twisted demon. Your soul has suddenly wandered into that evil world that exists in every person's heart. The only way out is to blast your way past the grotesque creatures that block your path in five "causes" (stages). You must face the dangers of this psychedelic world by making full use of three shot types and the satellite option. With power-ups, you can change your shots to a wide-coverage beam, a satellite-generated laser and more. Each shot type can be powered up to three levels. You can also block enemy fire by rotating the satellites to a desired position. How you use these features will be the key to successfully escaping this strange and surreal world</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Psychosis (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Naxat Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./R-Type (USA).pce</path>
		<name>R-Type</name>
		<desc>A desperate battle is being fought out in the limitless and unknown dimensions of space which have been contaminated and corrupted by an evil power. The evil power is the Bydo Empire, which is determined to subjugate the world. It is inhabited by weird creatures, whose very sight inspires fear. But mankind is fighting back, and sends you into battle in an incredibly sophisticated plane, the R-9 fighter. Behind the control panel of this fantastic fighting machine, you are Mankind's only defence against the enemy.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/R-Type (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Raiden (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Raiden</name>
		<desc>Go ballistic with intense arcade action! The year is 2090 and it could be our last. Alien invaders are scorching the earth with vastly superior firepower. Our only hope is Raiden, an untested supersonic fighter built with captured enemy technology, and only you are ace enough to handle it! Power up your laser for deadly accuracy or wide shots of lethal fire! Zero in with your homing missiles. Then nuke those fiends deep into space! You're on their turf now. Blast 'em and return victorious or they'll be back to finish us off!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Raiden (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Samurai-Ghost (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Samurai Ghost</name>
		<desc>This action platformer features a samurai ghost from the depths of the underworld. In a past war, Kagekiyo managed to defeat the shogun Yoritomo and his clan. However, their evil spirits were not completely destroyed, and now, in the world known as Dark Side, they seek the time of their rebirth. In order to shatter those ambitions, Kagekiyo must make his way across seven zones and head for "The Heart of the Darkside" where Yoritomo lies in wait. Use spirit weapons to power up your sword, or other items, such as candles to recover health, and defeat the endless hordes of enemies. Each zone is not only protected by a boss but also includes demons as well as real samurai from 12th-century Japan. Get ready for some intense one-on-one combat action.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Samurai-Ghost (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Now Production</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shanghai (Japan) [En by Dave Shadoff v0.99].pce</path>
		<name>Shanghai</name>
		<desc>Steady your nerves and concentration. You're about to play Shanghai! Shanghai is based on an ancient game that's over 25 centuries old. Over the years since, it has been a favorite of pirates and smugglers, flappers and gangsters, of working men and the well-to-do. Now you can play it too, on the Sega System. The game is simple... the strategy complex. Remove 144 tiles from a pyramid; two matching tiles at a time. But be careful. Remove the wrong two tiles and you're left with no more matching pairs... game over! It's a game everyone can play and enjoy.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Shanghai (Japan) [En by Dave Shadoff v0.99]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1988</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shockman (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Shockman</name>
		<desc>It's been two years since Arnold and Sonya were made into Shockmen. A message from the professor to return to their bodies has them head to his laboratory, but they are ambushed by a mysterious enemy along the way. After narrowly defeating the enemy, they catch a TV news flash announcing the Ryo Empire invasion. They find that the professor has been abducted and set out to rescue him.

Shockman is a side-view action shooter that has eight stages, including Action Stages, where you jump and use special techniques, and side-scrolling Shooting Stages. This game expands on the well-paced story from the previous version and contains cooperative elements like shared life and a powerful Team Shockbeam that can be used during two-player simultaneous play.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Shockman (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NCS</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Silent Debuggers (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Silent Debuggers</name>
		<desc>Make your way through a dungeon-like space station and defeat the prowling monsters in this real-time first-person shooter. You're a member of the elite Debuggers, a group of warriors who are jacks-of- all-trades. Assigned to inspect an unmanned space station, you have exactly 100 minutes to get in, destroy the monsters lurking in each block, make your way to the lowest level and deactivate the automatic detonator placed there. With each monster that slips by you, the core block becomes harder to survive in, so speed is key in preserving the facility and each separate block. Experience the thrill of survival as the timer ticks away and you uncover the truth of the events that occurred.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Silent Debuggers (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sinistron (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Sinistron</name>
		<desc>Scramble Mode Zeta; A message to Cybernaut Squadron Calisto -- Priority Alpha-San 03... An intersystem intruder has been detected in quadrant FTU-770. Dronecraft sent to get a visual discovered an extremely large monolith, biomorphic in nature. All attempts at contact ended in destruction of drones. Your mission: locate, intercept and enter the Sinistron. Use any means to destroy it!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Sinistron (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Alpha System</developer>
		<publisher>IGS</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Soldier Blade (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Soldier Blade</name>
		<desc>Vertical sci-fi shoot ‘em up from the Hudson stable. Soldier Blade sticks to the tried and tested formula of Hudson’s previous games in the 'series', while throwing in some extra graphical effects. This time, the power up system involves collecting coloured pods - you can have three pods in stock at any one time, and the colour of the 'active' pod determines your weapon style. You also have the choice of ejecting a pod at any time, which results in a weapon-specific super attack.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Soldier Blade (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Somer Assault (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Somer Assault</name>
		<desc>Here begins the story from a time and a world not our own ... A sorceress used her evil powers to fulfill her conquest to rule the world. "Go my dead slaves to trample and rule the world which will belong to us!" You are the only one who can crush her wretched plans! Each stage is controlled by a boss who portrays a sign of the zodiac. Going through a maze, you have to find and destroy the boss before your time runs out. Save the world!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Somer Assault (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Atlus</developer>
		<publisher>Atlus</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Son Son II (Japan) [En by Sgt. Bow v1.0b].pce</path>
		<name>Son Son II</name>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Son Son II (Japan) [En by Sgt. Bow v1.0b]-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic Spike - World Championship Beach Volleyball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Sonic Spike</name>
		<desc>The action sizzles in Sonic Spike, on the front line of the world's most brutal volleyball game. Blast the ball over the net -- bump, spike, dig, jump, and even quick-fake a return. Orbital lobs soar to the sun; earth-pounding spikes vibrate the ground. Score ... or eat sand! Select and create your own teams from 24 athletes pulled from six nations. Pit gals against guys in a battle of the sexes, or fight the competition of the century with Japan, Australia, Brazil, USA or USSR.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Sonic Spike - World Championship Beach Volleyball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>IGS</developer>
		<publisher>IGS</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space Harrier (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Space Harrier</name>
		<desc>You are Harrier, the resourceful extra-terrestrial warrior. And space is your battlefield. Your mission is to save the Land of the Dragons from vicious creatures led by the vile and crafty One-Eyed Mammoth. Aided by your only friends, the Dragons, you find yourself attacked again and again. Armed only with an Autolock Energy Launcher and your wits, you must fight off one heavily-armed alien after another. You must use every trick in the book. Every skill at your command. The clashes are thrilling and demanding. The combat scenes are powerful. Can you survive the intense fighting? For your sake, for the sake of the Land of the Dragons, you must!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Space Harrier (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/09/1988</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Splatterhouse (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Splatterhouse</name>
		<desc>Two college students, Rick Taylor and Jennifer Willis, take refuge from a storm in West Mansion, a local landmark known as "Splatterhouse" for the rumors of hideous experiments purportedly conducted there by Dr. West, a renowned and missing parapsychologist. At the mansion, the two are attacked by demonic creatures that drag Jennifer inside and fatally wound Rick, leaving him for dead.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Splatterhouse (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Air Zonk (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Super Air Zonk</name>
		<desc>Super Air Zonk is an Action game, developed by Dual and published by Hudson, which was released in Japan in 1993.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Super Air Zonk (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/30/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Dual</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Air Zonk (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Super Air Zonk</name>
		<desc>Super Air Zonk is an Action game, developed by Dual and published by Hudson, which was released in Japan in 1993.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Air Zonk (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/30/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Dual</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Star Soldier (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Super Star Soldier</name>
		<desc>The special attack squad, lead by the Mother Brain, has launched an all out invasion on Earth. Take your small-scale fighter, the Neo Caesar, with its arsenal of 4 regular weapons and 2 special weapons, and send them back where they belong! In addition to the Normal Game mode in this vertical-scrolling shooting game, there are 2-minute and 5-minute Time Attack modes and a mode where high-scores can be checked. Normal Game is made up of 8 different stages, and in each stage (except Stage 7), a boss awaits you at the end.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Super Star Soldier (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Inter State</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Volleyball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Super Volleyball</name>
		<desc>Command your team against the best in the world with Super Volleyball, the simulation that gives you ultimate control. You choose the teams, the players and the moves. Keep their defense off balance with a variety of serves, lightning spikes, well-placed slams and player rotations. Be ready to strike back with power blocks and acrobatic saves. You can even create your own team of super players and take them through league competition to become the international champs. For a professional challenge -- and not a walk on the beach -- get set for Super Volleyball.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Super Volleyball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>6.000000</rating>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Takin' It to the Hoop (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Takin' it to the Hoop</name>
		<desc>You're a high-scoring point guard capable of awesome vertical leaps and hangtime. Matter of fact, you can do it all! Dribble. Bounce-pass. Fake. Pivot. Jump. Shoot. Play Man or Zone. Drive the lane -- is the defender all over you? Give him a move and jam, slam in his face!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Takin' It to the Hoop (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Alcom</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./TaleSpin (USA).pce</path>
		<name>TaleSpin</name>
		<desc>Take off with those high-flying Disney heroes, Captain Baloo and Kit Cloudkicker in the action-packed adventure TaleSpin. Imagine, you're after the lost treasure of Ionia, and the Watusi Witch Doctor is after you! Can you defeat him to go on and defy the dreaded Iron Vulture and make it to the Ice Caves of Thembria? Are you brave enough to challenge Shere Khan for the treasure? Find out by playing TaleSpin, with seven thrilling levels and 150 danger-filled screens!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/TaleSpin (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Radiance Software</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tiger Road (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Tiger Road</name>
		<desc>This arcade conversion is a beat 'em up in which you (as Lee Wong) must rescue the village children from the evil Ryo Ken Oh. Many levels are horizontally scrolling, although with high ledges to jump onto and follow for a slightly different path. Magic urns containing improved weapons appear frequently. Most enemies are easy to attack and only need one hit to kill, although they come at you in large hordes. Once you get to the indoor sections you will find big enemies with the ability to kill you with one hit, in sections set on multiple levels complete with stairways.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Tiger Road (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Time Cruise (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Time Cruise</name>
		<desc>Time Cruise is a futuristic pinball game, developed by Sankindo and published by Face, which was released in 1992.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Time Cruise (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Sankindo</developer>
		<publisher>FACE</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Timeball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Timeball</name>
		<desc>Get wrapped up in this mind-bending game that will test your mental agility. The action seems simple -- just keep a ball rolling through a winding maze by shifting around pieces of tubing. But the action is intense! Race against time and the track to keep the ball from crashing. There are 100 challenging levels -- plus the unique edit feature lets you build your own puzzles!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Timeball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tricky Kick (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Tricky Kick</name>
		<desc>Flex your thumbs and tease your brain! TRICKY KICK takes brain teasing puzzle gaming into the next dimension. Six different Heroes, trapped in a mixed-up, matched-up world of obstacles, baffle their way through hostile hazards. Weave your way through 120 levels of mind-bending possibilities where wild animals, robots, spooks, and trolls try to keep you from your goal. Designed for puzzlers of all ages, TRICKY KICK will quickly become a game you'll find hard to quit.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Tricky Kick (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Information Global Services, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Turrican (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Turrican</name>
		<desc>From beyond the edge of darkness, evil incarnate is back. He is Morgul, master of all the fears and nightmares of mankind. As a world trembles in sleepless terror, a single warrior emerges - you are Turrican! Battle through the five worlds of darkness encountering thunder and storm, mechanical monsters, hidden rooms, awesome end of level guardians, reptillian beasts, and anywhere... the unexpected! Featuring 13 levels with over 1,300 screens, 10 hi-tech weapons systems, multi-directional scrolling, 20 musically excellent soundtracks, countless special effects and bonus features, and 50 different aliens and 8 gigantic end-level monsters.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Turrican (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>08/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>The Code Monkeys</developer>
		<publisher>Ballistic</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./TV Sports Basketball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>TV Sports Basketball</name>
		<desc>The arena's rockin'. Network cameras are rollin'. It's showtime! Here's ultra-real pro roundball that puts you right on the floor with an awesome on-the-court view and total control. Set your offense. Use your screen to nail a three-pointer. Roll off your pick to hit the jumper. Or post up in the paint and power slam with one second left on the shot clock! Now turn up the heat on defense. Trap and go for the steal! Do it all in the only game for up to five players with action more real than you've ever seen!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/TV Sports Basketball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Cinemaware Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./TV Sports Football (USA).pce</path>
		<name>TV Sports Football</name>
		<desc>The crowd's roaring. TV cameras are rolling. You're in a pro football war more real than you've ever played. Digitized sound lets you feel every bone-crunching hit. Call all the plays and audibles. Then control a sophisticated offense and slashing, head-bashing defense as TV announcers broadcast the game. It's fast, furious action for up to 5 players! Battle through a full season schedule to the League Championship!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/TV Sports Football (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/25/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Cinemaware</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./TV Sports Hockey (USA).pce</path>
		<name>TV Sports Hockey</name>
		<desc>The stadium organ is pumping as you faceoff against international competition. Play any position, even goalie, with total control. Experience all the stick handling, slap shots, body checks and fisticuffs of world class hockey. Make strategic goalie and line changes. If their goon slams you into the boards, drop your gloves and duke it out. Now you're flying down the ice on a power play. You wind up and crank a high, blazing slap shot, but their goalie's reaching up and...Welcome to World War III, hockey style!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/TV Sports Hockey (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Cinemaware Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Valis II (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Valis II</name>
		<desc>From the ashes of your ravaged homeland, the legendary sword Valis calls out to you. Its power transforms you into a ferocious warrior against the evil forces of King Magus. Crush Zarooga, the fearsome red dragon! Battle the unspeakable Death Pod! But beware! Magus has sworn a blood oath to destroy you and capture Valis, to possess its power forevermore. Summon all your fury to face Magus in an epic struggle over the fate of your countrymen.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Valis II (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Sin Nihon Laser Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Valis III (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Valis III</name>
		<desc>Once again, you must unleash the fury of the legendary Valis sword! Ramses, fiendish lord of the Spirit World, has begun his invasion. As Yuko, you must battle the bloodthirsty forces that world annihilate your people. But this time, you are not alone! You can transform into fierce allies with their own devastating weapons. Attack with the magic of fire, ice and thunder. Then risk death in a duel with Ramses himself, as you uncover his secret plot to possess Valis and rule the universe!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Valis III (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Veigues - Tactical Gladiator (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Veigues Tactical Gladiator</name>
		<desc>For 3 years, alien invaders have been pounding the earth into a smoldering ruin. There isn't a man alive who can stop them. But now, there's Veigues, a devastating fighting machine! Built with captured enemy technology, he's our last desperate hope for survival ... and you're in control! Trash the invaders with the Plazma Cannon! Just keep your firepower hot and fight like there's no tomorrow. Destroy the aliens or there won't be!.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Veigues - Tactical Gladiator (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Victor Musical Industries</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Victory Run (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Victory Run</name>
		<desc>Strap on this red turbo-charged beauty and punch it. Barrel through the streets of night-time Paris. Lean into the rolling countryside curves. Sweat the hot Sahara straightaway. The famous Paris to Dakar Road Rally tests driving skills, reaction time and your knowledge of the needs of your machine in various conditions. Great sights! Great sounds! If you've got the skills-hit the road, Jack. The best time wins!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Victory Run (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/19/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Vigilante (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Vigilante</name>
		<desc>Some New York City punks have kidnapped a girl. Your girl. Throwing your muscle around is not your normal style, but these are mean streets! If it has to be you versus these big city greaseballs and junkyard dudes -- bring them on! They won't come at your one at a time, so it's a good thing you can be quick and mean. Go to it, Vigilante! Or never see her smile again.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Vigilante (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>IREM</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Wonder Boy III - Monster Lair (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Wonder Boy III Monster Lair</name>
		<desc>Wonder Boy III: Monster Lair is a quite different game to most of the games in the Wonder Boy series. You play a green-haired dude who must attack the invaders that attempt to collect weapons and use them to destroy the land. The game starts out like a simple platform game, but it's just when Wonder Boy enters the skull further on that the game is transformed into a shoot 'em up, so basically the gameplay consists of action and shooter scenes.

In the action scenes, your vitality decreases as you make your way towards the skull, but this can be restored by collecting fruit. A wide variety of weapons can be picked up, and not only does these allow you to use the weapons for a limited amount of time, but they also increase your vitality. 

In the shooter scenes, you ride your pink friend as you make your way through the scene. Here, your vitality remains static unless you are hit by an enemy passing by. As usual, there is a boss waiting for you at the end which you must defeat. Every boss changes color to show how much damage has been done to it. You have to defeat some bosses in two stages.

If your vitality gets low in each scene, you'll lose a life. You can also choose to have Wonder Girl join you, as two players can play the game.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Wonder Boy III - Monster Lair (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>4.500000</rating>
		<releasedate>08/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Westone Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>NEC Home Electronics (U.S.A.) Inc.</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./World Class Baseball (USA).pce</path>
		<name>World Class Baseball</name>
		<desc>This game belongs in the Baseball Hall of Fame. Nothing takes you out to the ballgame like World Class Baseball! It tests all your baseball knowledge and skills. Bunt. Throw a slider. A change-u. Pick runners off base. Call in a relief pitcher. Hear the roar of the crowd and the crack of the bat. Play another player. Play against the computer. Play the Turbo Champs. Knock the dirt from your spikes. You're up!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/World Class Baseball (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./World Court Tennis (USA).pce</path>
		<name>World Court Tennis</name>
		<desc>It's your serve. WHOP! The ball clears the net at 100 MPH and raises a little dust just inside the chalkline. An ace? no. WHOP! Your opponent returns with a powerful backhand that kills your plan of charging the net. No matter how you play - with up to 3 friends, singles, doubles, or against the computer - World Court Tennis will tax your endurance and test your skill with action that's fast and furious. Just don't scream at the line judge. He's never wrong.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/World Court Tennis (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./World Sports Competition (USA).pce</path>
		<name>World Sports Competition</name>
		<desc>Top Athletes Battle for Glory!

You create an athlete who runs, jumps, and throws! Aim for the world record...and never give up!

With 18 events to choose from...
With 6 categories, and a total of 18 exciting events, you'll have a wide choice to train for. Then go on to challenge Olympic Mode in your chose event. you too can be a world record holder!

Excitement x 5!
Exciting alone, unbelievable with friends! Up to five players can compete at once, for some serious adrenalin action!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/World Sports Competition (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Yo, Bro (USA).pce</path>
		<name>Yo Bro</name>
		<desc>Ratz attack! Ratz attack! The city of Los Angeles is being invaded! Only Lil Bro', Camp California's rad skateboarding dude, can save it. The evil Ratz gang is unleashing a barrage of killer creatures and devices. Find incredibly cool weapons to fight back. Wipe out their earthquake machines and nasty man-eating plants with rocket grenades. Fight off wicked space aliens and launch your bonus attacks. It'll take everything you've got to send the Ratz packing.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Yo, Bro (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>5.500000</rating>
		<releasedate>01/31/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
		<publisher>NEC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ys Book I &amp; II - Ancient Ys Vanished (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Ys Book I &amp; II</name>
		<desc>Journey through the Ancient Land of Ys, a once peaceful and prosperous country suddenly thrust deep into an empty abyss of isolation. The secret to restoring peace rests in the six books of the wise priests. 700 years have passed, and now you have a chance to unlock the mystery. Stunning graphics, intense stereo sound and profound gameplay make this a CD adventure you'll never forget ... and may never return from.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ys Book I &amp; II - Ancient Ys Vanished (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Nihon Falcom</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ys III - Wanderers from Ys (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</name>
		<desc>As Adol, hero of Ys Book I &amp; II, your most fearsome new adventure is about to begin! The curse of the monster Demanicus terrorizes your friend Dogi's homeland. Chaos rules as blood-thirsty creatures threaten innocent lives. Only you have the courage and strength to defeat them! Gather your fiercest swords and deadly amulet to battle these horrific creatures with a thrilling new action view. Survive the fiery depths of Alcaino. Conquer the terrifying Nekevil. But stay alert, brave Adol! The fury of Demanicus awaits your final epic struggle!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ys III - Wanderers from Ys (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Nihon Falcom</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
	</game>
</gameList>
