<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Accele Brid (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Accele Brid (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project
Accelebrid is a chase-view shooter. I guess it might be compared to Iridion 3D, but as I haven't played Iridion 3D, I wouldn't know. Basically, you play as this guy named Ginei, who happens to be the pilot of the Silver Mare, an eight-or-so foot tall, high-powered suit of armor, armed to the teeth, which he races. The upcoming race is the 13th famed Accelebrid, and it's being held at the G. Bowman circuit. During the race, however, a group of terrorists attacks, hijacks the tracks built-in obstacles, and kidnaps the owner of Ginei's team (who also happens to be his girlfriend or something.) Armed with nothing but vengeance and his high-powered combat suit, Ginei leaves in hot pursuit. You've got a radar at the bottom of the screen which you will NEED to get used to using if you want to survive. The game also sports six different weapons with which to arm the Silver Mare, as well as multiple possible endings to the game. Translation's totally taken care of (not like you need it to play the game, but still.) Have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Accele_Brid_Cover_Art.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>November 26, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Tomy</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ActRaiser (J) [T+Eng Aeon Genesis Retranslation].smc</path>
		<name>ActRaiser (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project
 Retranslation
 Shame on you if you´ve never played Actraiser before! This version, other than having an amazingly badass logo, is actually a lot harder than the US release of the game. Even in Fillmore 1, there are more brambles, more monsters, more everything. It´s crazy great. Ian Kelley wanted to retranslate the game, so here it is! Far be it from me to deprive one of my star translators from an awesome request or two!

If you´ve never played it, now´s your chance. The translation is complete and, to my knowledge, bug-free. Enjoy!
 </desc>
		<image>./images/actraiserj.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 16, 1990</releasedate>
		<developer>Quintet</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Action/Simulation/RPG Mixture</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Adventure of Hourai High - Transfer Student (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Adventure of Hourai High - Transfer Student (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project
This is a rather silly RPG about an exchange student. Example: during the introduction sequence it is revealed that his flight is running late, so in order to make sure that he´s on time for the opening ceremonies at the school, the stewardess pushes him out of the plane with a faulty parachute. Hourai features plenty of penguins, wacky clubs, and crazy school hijinks. It also features a class system similar to FF5´s, or so I hear - you join clubs, and as you rank higher in the clubs you gain more abilities.

satsu´s translated this one. It´s been a long slog the last several months, but the patch is finally ready to go! Be sure to check out the before-and-after snaps in the Extras section to the right!
</desc>
		<image>./images/2371926-c.png</image>
		<releasedate>April 16, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>J-Wing</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Aim for the Ace! (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.2_RPGOne].smc</path>
		<name>Aim for the Ace! (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.2
Translated by RPG One

The only game made based on the characters from the Aim For The Ace movie and OAV series.

As you'd expect from it's source material the Ace Wo Nerae! game is a tennis sim, featuring the characters from the anime.

Despite being an anime license this game is actually quite a solid sports title with quite a few options and play modes. The controls are pretty simple but the erratic, wobbly camera shakes around worse than NYPD Blue which would probably give you a head ache after too long!

There is a fixed camera mode too but using this makes the sprites really small which, in turn, makes successfully hitting the ball a lot trickier.
</desc>
		<image>./images/SFC01-EE-ACEON-01.gif</image>
		<releasedate>December 23, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Nippon Telenet</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alcahest (J) [T+Eng1.0_FH].smc</path>
		<name>Alcahest (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.0
Translated by FH

Alcahest is an action game with a top-down perspective that plays similar to The Legend of Zelda. It is divided into 8 stages that are progressed by finding items that aid the protagonist Alen on his quest, and end with a boss battle. After specific boss fights, the player gains the abilities of one of the four elemental Guardians. Alen will also find five allies that join him at predetermined points of some levels. They are the young wizard Garstein, the princess Elikshil, the knight Sirius, the android Magna and the shape-shifter dragon goddess Nevis. Though they cannot be controlled directly, allies attack and use special moves when the corresponding button is pressed.

The player's vitality decreases when attacked. MP are used to summon Guardians in battle, and SP (Special Points) are required for a partner's special attack. At the end of each stage, Alen's vitality increases. The player is also able to attack enemies using a sword, which can also be charged for a special attack, different depending on the elemental Guardian selected. Items can also be found those that restore Alen's stats.

The player gains points by defeating enemies and bosses. After gaining a certain number of points, the player earns an additional continue. The player is given passwords at the beginning of each new stage.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Alcahest (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 17, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Hal Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20160408T104126</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ancient Magic - Bazoo! World Of Magic (J) [T+Eng 100% AeonGenesis].smc</path>
		<name>Ancient Magic - Bazoo! World Of Magic (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

In Ancient Magic, you play a young boy (or girl) whose father, Ricardo, was a powerful mage. Determined to follow in your father's footsteps, you make a vow to your mother to attend the Magic School in Selas. You are joined on your journey by Feyr, a bard, Romal, a knight, Lot, a priest, and many others. As you progress as a mage, you are sent on quests to explore ruins and uncover spells. Meanwhile, a mysterious man named Kuroizel and the evil Veranede Tribe are plotting something, and it's up to you to find out what. This old school rpg is strictly fantasy, and has the nostalgic feel of a Dungeons and Dragons campaign.

All done, lord willing! Enjoy.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Ancient Magic - Bazoe! Mahou Sekai (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 23, 1990</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Hot-B</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Angelique (J) [T+Eng0.02_Marfisa].smc</path>
		<name>Angelique (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng0.02
Translated by Marfisa

Basically, you’re in line to be Queen of the Universe, but you first have to prove yourself by being all nice and cuddly with the Guardian Sages, who all happen to be very eligible bachelors. Despite the game being intended specifically for girls, it would be a pretty neat game if the language barrier weren’t so amazingly high. How the hell do you save your game?
</desc>
		<image>./images/angelique-super-famicom-used-good-condition-en.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 23, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Marfisa</publisher>
		<genre>Dating Sim</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Arabian Nights - Desert Spirit King (J)[T+Eng 100% LostTemplar].smc</path>
		<name>Arabian Nights - Desert Spirit King (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Borderline

Arabian Nights: Sabaku no Seirei-ō  is a 1996 Japan-exclusive Role-playing video game developed by Pandora Box and published by Takara for the Super Famicom.

The King of Djinns Ifrit is defeated by a man named Suleiman and made his servant. Then some anonymous magical being destroys Suleiman's house and weakens Ifrit. To grant Ifrit freedom, Suleiman seals him in a Contract Ring and shall be free after a thousand wishes have been granted by a thousand hands.

One century later, in the town of Bazaar, an orphan girl named Shukran finds the Contract Ring and unleashes Ifrit. With 999 wishes used throughout last the century, Shukran uses the last wish for peace in her homeland. Ifrit however cannot stray far from his ring, so Shukran and Ifrit travel the land together to make this possible.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Arabian Nights - Sabaku no Seirei Ou (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 14, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Takara</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Assault Suits Valken (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Assault Suits Valken (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Assault Suits Valken is an amazing action game by NCS/Masaya. Easily one of my favorite SNES games of all time, Valken puts you into the cockpit of a gigantic robot that gets to stomp over everything in its path. The levels are extremely well varied and I have yet to really get sick of it. In fact, looks and feels very similar to Front Mission: Gun Hazard. I may go so far as to say it inspired Gun Hazard, but I really can´t confirm that one way or the other. Assault Suits Valken one hell of a lot of fun, and it´s got really good story to back it up, too -- quite a lot of which was unfortunately lost on Konami, who released it as "Cybernator" in the US. They removed a good 30-60% of the text, a lot of text sequences, character portraits in the dialogue, reduced one character to simple cannon fodder, deleted a whole bunch of other characters, axed a cutscene in the final level, and generally made a mess of it. I have, in large part, fixed all that.

In the current version, the only thing that should not be working is name customization, so you´ll have to make do with the default of "Jake" for now unless you feel like messing with the half-hacked name entry screen. Otherwise, it should be fully functional! Hope you have a blast!
</desc>
		<image>./images/valken.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 19, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>NCS/Masaya</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bahamut Lagoon (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.3-Emu_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Bahamut Lagoon (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.3-Emu
Translated by DeJap

Bahamut Lagoon combines RPG mechanics with squad-based combat. Characters have HP, MP (SP for fighter characters), EXP, equipment, stats and class-specific, SP-draining special elemental abilities very much like traditional console RPGs. The player can explore his surroundings, talk to people and visit shops when not in battle, though to a limited degree as there is no world map and no way to leave the current area.

The game's core is its turn-based battles fought on a 2d grid. Characters are assembled into parties of four and the player allowed a maximum of six parties, which are usually well outnumbered. The two opposing sides act in alternating turns so that each party can move once and/or attack once a turn. Attacks are divided into distant and close-up combat. In the former, a party uses a special ability (e.g. casting fireballs, throwing lightning, healing allies) of one of its members at a distance. The range and possible area of effect damage vary per ability. If the attacking party has two or more characters with the same ability, they join in the action to multiply its effectiveness. Distant combat results in less money and generally less damage, but the target cannot retaliate. Distant attacks can also affect the field; fire and ice ignite or extinguish forests and melt or freeze ice, etc. Close-up, each unit in two adjacent opposing parties can act once. Very much like Final Fantasy SNES combat, they can attack an enemy, use an item or a special ability (though these can't be combined and most only affect one target instead of all) or defend.

Dragons have their own stats and gain experience like normal characters do. In battle, each party has a dragon attached to it and draws a large portion of its strength from that of its dragon: if a party's dragon is slain, the party will lose the ability to use special attacks and class-specific abilities for the remainder of the map. The beast acts as a very powerful autonomous unit that moves after its party does and it cannot be controlled beyond very simple commands, e.g. "Come!" Out of battle, dragons will eat anything and raising them by feeding them items is an important part of the game. Feeding can improve their stats as well as affect their behavior on the field, and the dragons develop into new forms as they grow.

The player can change the characters in each of the parties, their formation as well as what dragon represents them at will.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Bahamut Lagoon (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>Februrary 9, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Squaresoft</developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical role-playing</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ball Bullet Gun (J) [T+Eng 100% Aeon Genesis].smc</path>
		<name>Ball Bullet Gun (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Ball Bullet Gun is a strategy game, a simulation of Japanese "survival games" (read: war games.) The closest American approximation is paintball, but that´s not quite right. The game itself is fairly cute, but there are a lot of things to take into account when planning your strategies, and it provides a surprising amount of depth for a deceptively simple game. There really isn´t any story to speak of, at least not that I know of, but if you´re looking for a decent strategy game, this should work wonderfully.

Insofar as progress is concerend, this is a bit of an interesting story. A year or two ago (I honestly don´t remember how long ago, this is the closest approximation I can give) I´d dumped the scripts and the (in?)famous Tomato translated ´em for me. It was the last project he´d done before his computer blew up or died or whatever, but I hit a brick wall with some of the routines and the project was effectively stalled. As of this writing, I´ve been working on it again for less than a full day and I´ve already managed to hack a bunch of font routines, text routines, name entry screens, the works! Seven of eight English text files are inserted and working approximately correctly, and I´m guessing that the final one won´t pose any real problems either!


</desc>
		<image>./images/Ball Bullet Gun - Survival Game Simulation (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 1, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>I'MAX</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy/Simulation</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bastard!! - Ankoku no Hakai-shin (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Bastard!! - Ankoku no Hakai-shin (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0
Translated by DeJap

Bastard!!, if you need an introduction to it, is a marvelous anime and manga series based in a world turned feudal after a large disaster tore it apart.  It centers around an 'immortal' wizard named Dark Schneider, who 15 years ago tried to conquer the world, but now fights to save it.  The anime consists(So far) of six marvelously animated OVAs, while the manga lasts for far longer, and reportedly gets very bizzare. ;)  While a very good show on its own, you can also have yourself a little fun on the side trying to spot all the various heavy metal references in the names and spells(And there are a -lot-).
Guys and girls both may enjoy the series, as it has as much fan service with the male characters(Probably more actually) as the female ones, and has elements which can cater to all tastes, from the high-action lover, to fans of dramatics, to those who like slapstick humor.

Unlike most fighters, Bastard!! takes place on a scrolling battlefield, 
in a 3rd person perspective looking from -behind- one of the fighters, 
as opposed to from their sides(Like SF2).
</desc>
		<image>./images/24215_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>January 28, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Cobra Team</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battle Soccer - Field no Hasha (J) [T+Eng1.0_Hurkey].smc</path>
		<name>Battle Soccer - Field no Hasha (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.0
Translated by Hurkey

Battle Soccer: Field no Hasha is a soccer video game, developed by Pandora Box and published by Banpresto, which was released exclusively in Japan in 1992.

This game features many popular Japanese franchise characters like Godzilla, Ultraman, Kamen Rider, Gundam, and among a few others.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Battlesoccersfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 11, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Pandora Box</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Brandish 2 - The Planet Buster (J) [T+ENG 100% by Synchronicity v1.0].smc</path>
		<name>Brandish 2 - The Planet Buster (J) </name>
		<desc>T+ENG 100% by 
Translated by Synchronicity

Brandish is a top-down view dungeon crawler game. The original version of the game uses mouse controls from a real-time overhead view, where the player can move the warrior character Ares (known as Varik in the original English version) forward and backward, turn, strafe, and attack by clicking on boxes surrounding the player character. The player's objective is to escape from a labyrinth of over 40 floors filled various monsters, traps and puzzles.

Brandish: The Dark Revenant turns the game's female antagonist Dela into an optional alternate player character. Dela, a magician, plays differently from the protagonist Ares the warrior. The game's "Dela Mode" is shorter (lasting about 10 hours as compared to some 20 hours with Ares) but harder than the main scenario.[5] Xseed Games' localization blog compared The Dark Revenant to Etrian Odyssey series with "the tough but fair difficulty of Dark Souls."
 v1.0</desc>
		<image>./images/Brandish 2 - The Planet Buster (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 17, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>NEC</developer>
		<publisher>Koei</publisher>
		<genre>Action Role Playing</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./BS Chrono Trigger - Music Library (J) [T+Eng1.00e_Terminus].smc</path>
		<name>BS Chrono Trigger - Music Library (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00e_
Translated by Terminus

It's the entire soundtrack of Chrono Trigger crammed into a single Snes rom! BS Chrono Trigger Music Library was meant to be a downloadable bonus for Satellaview players in Japan but now emulation is the only way to get it since the Satellaview was shut down long ago. 

All of the songs from Chrono Trigger are included in BS Chrono Trigger: Music Library. Many of them loop, however, making them longer than the versions in the original game.
A Premonition (0:34)  
Chrono Trigger (2:01)
Waking Up in the Morning (0:58)
Peaceful Days (2:48)
Memories of Green (3:51)
Guardia Kingdom Millennial Fair (3:17)
Gato's Song (0:42)
A Peculiar Happening (1:43)
The Wind's Yearning (3:22)
Goodnight (0:08)
Secret of the Dense Woods (4:46)
Battle (2:29)
Guardia Castle ~Courage and Pride~ (3:28)
Huh!? (0:05)
Manoria Cathedral (1:13)
A Prayer to the Travelers (0:11)
Silent Light (2:23)
Boss Battle 1 (1:58)
Frog's Theme (1:49)
Fanfare 1 (1:16)
The Kingdom Trial (3:44) 
Hidden Truth (0:59)
A Tight Squeeze (2:39)
World in Ruins (3:24)
Mystery of the Past (0:07)
Dome-16's Ruins (1:34)
People Who've Abandoned the Will to Live (3:07)
Lavos' Theme (5:10)
World's Final Day (1:25)
Johnny of the Robot Hotrod Squad (2:21)
Bike Chase (1:35) 
Robo's Theme (1:32)
Remains of the Factory (3:09)
Battle 2 (2:10)
Fanfare 2 (0:07)
The Brink of Time (2:31)
Delightful Spekkio (2:48)
Fanfare 3 (0:05)
Underground Sewer (2:24)
Boss Battle 2 (2:41)
Primitive Mountain (3:07)
Ayla's Theme (1:24)
Rhythm of the Wind, Sky, and Earth (1:51)
Burn! Bobonga! (2:12)
Magus' Castle (0:29)
Insane Melody (1:40)
Battle With Magus (3:30)

</desc>
		<image>./images/972882-bs_chrono_trigger___music_library__j_.001.png</image>
		<releasedate>August 16, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Squaresoft</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Music</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Burning Heroes (J) [T+ENG 100% V1.00 Dynamic Designs].smc</path>
		<name>Burning Heroes (J) </name>
		<desc>T+ENG 100% V1.00 
Translated by DynamicDesigns

By nearly every criterion, this game is absolutely sumptuous! Playing it will make any person with a good heart want to cheer, especially for those triumphal spirits who steadfastly remain grounded in senses of duty, honor, and decency. People who treasure virtue above all other human traits will find their values reaffirmed while playing this saga - despite the convoluted roads that many of our burning heroes must navigate.

Regardless, each scene of every journey shares valuable, timeless lessons, but the story is what makes this vintage RPG even more special. Beware anyone who wallows in misery or predators who revel in lurking down crooked corridors. Lost souls may vicariously discover alternative paths that point toward a direction of their possible absolution. Is this just a video game, or is it a solid depiction of art imitating life?

If we could change just one design feature in Burning Heroes, we would eliminate the modest amount of repetition in the eight scenarios. Other than that, this game is just about perfect.

There’s a total of eight playable characters, each with their own scenario, SaGa Frontier-style!
</desc>
		<image>./images/NTBHeroesReviewFront.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 17, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Burning Pro Wrestling (J) [T+Eng 100% V1 Phil].smc</path>
		<name>Burning Pro Wrestling (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by Phil

In 1995, Bullet Proof Software entered the realm of Wrestling Video games with it's eye set on making the best Wrestling game possible.

That game was Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling. Released only in Japan back in 1995, Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling featured a staggering,  encyclopedic 129 Wrestler roster, plenty of modes to choose from and a insanely customizable array of options to set up match types that was unseen in any other Wrestling game at the time.

The Wrestlers featured in Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling span across a multitude of different Wrestling promotions With a diverse cast of recognizable faces all disguised under different aliases including Wrestling Legends,  Mixed Martial Artists, Shoot Fighters, Puroresu Megastars, and even Mexican Luchadors not featured in any Fire Pro game (up to 1995, at least).

Yet, Gekitou's greatest features were marred by one simply unavoidable conflict which prevented the game from attaining critical acclaim and a respectable series of future installments. Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling looked and felt much too similar to the Fire Pro Wrestling series. 

Everything from Gekitou's gameplay, modes and even the graphical style of the Wrestlers themselves bared a striking resemblance to the Fire Pro Wrestling series (especially, Super Fire Pro Wrestling Special which was released one year prior to Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling...in 1994). 

But, even with this very glaring incovenience, Burning Pro Wrestling is still an interesting and worthwhile experience for the hardcore  wrestling fanatic looking for an alternate take on the Fire Pro Wrestling series. Afterall, Immitation is the sincerest form of flattery.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling Box Art.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>06 October 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Ukiyotei</developer>
		<publisher>Bullet Proof Software</publisher>
		<genre>Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Captain Tsubasa III - Koutei no Chousen (J) [T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Captain Tsubasa III - Koutei no Chousen (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        Captain Tsubasa 3 Challenge of Rivals was released in 1992 by Tecmo for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System console. A graphical update of the previous Family Computer video games, it also includes new features like a map of the pitch at the bottom of the screen. The video game was never released outside Japan so English versions of the game are very hard to find.
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/CaptainTsubaba3BoxShotSNES.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 17, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Tecmo</developer>
		<publisher>Tecmo</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Captain Tsubasa V - Hasha no Shougou Canpione (J) [T+Eng_Evil Crusaders].smc</path>
		<name>Captain Tsubasa V - Hasha no Shougou Canpione (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng_Evil 
Translated by Crusaders

Captain Tsubasa 4: Pro no Rival Tachi is the fourth sequel of the original Captain Tsubasa videogame series by Tecmo. It's a direct sequel of Captain Tsubasa 3: Koutei no Chousen and released exclusively in Japan for Nintendo's Super Famicom on April 3, 1993.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Captain_Tsubasa_4_-_Pro_no_Rival_Tachi_cover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>April 3, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Tecmo</developer>
		<publisher>Tecmo</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Clock Tower (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Clock Tower (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Clock Tower SFC is the prequel to the game we know in the states as Clock Tower. And while technically "The First Fear" is not the proper subtitle for the game (it doesn´t actually have a subtitle), the game was rereleased for the PlayStation under the title Clock Tower - The First Fear, and I´ll be using that name to differentiate between it and the US version (instead of calling this Clock Tower Zero or some bullshit like that.) You play as Jennifer Simpson, fleeing from the insane psycho killer Bobby Barrows (AKA "the scissorman") in the Barrows Family Mansion. It´s also a puzzle game sort of along the lines of the Discworld games, but the puzzles are a lot less nonsensical :P Translation´s complete, have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Clock Tower (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 14, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Human Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Horror Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Crystal Beans From Dungeon Explorer (J) [T+Eng 100%].smc</path>
		<name>Crystal Beans From Dungeon Explorer (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100%
        Despite the downgrade from CD to cartridge, Crystal Beans From Dungeon Explorer is a very complete and neat package; it's just a shame that by 1995 the western SNES market was already flagging, with players migrating from 16-bit consoles to new CD-based home systems like the PlayStation and Saturn. For this reason, Hudson's effort - like a great many other late generation Super Famicom games - remained exclusive to Japan.

        Crystal Beans From Dungeon Explorer is arguably the Super Nintendo's best alternative to the beloved Gauntlet and due to this, dungeon crawler fans shouldn't think twice about adding it to their collection. The game picked up renewed interest when a complete English translation patch was released back in 2012, clearing the language barrier for Western gamers. 
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Crystal Beans from Dungeon Explorer (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 27, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<genre>Action RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cu-On-Pa SFC (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Cu-On-Pa SFC (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Cu-on-pa is a puzzle game. I’m finding that as I get older and older, I’m having less patience for these types of games. But Cu-on-pa is different. It’s just not as annoying as some of the other stuff out there. Maybe that’s just because it isn’t a rehash of another puzzle game that’s already been done to death 1500 times (see Tetris and all the crappy block-a-riffic games that spawned). Either way, I could actually get into this game a little bit, which is rare for puzzle games these days.

Anyhow, in Cu-on-pa, you control this cube which has various colors on all its faces. On the ground are colored blocks which you must destroy. To destroy them, you simply roll on them so that the like-colored face of the cube is face-up while you’re on the block. Yeah, this does sound annoying, but it’s not as difficult as it sounds, trust me. You’ll enjoy yourself. And if you don’t, I’ll send some thugs to your place and have them beat the enjoyment into you.
</desc>
		<image>./images/11232_original_large.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>December 20, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>T+E Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cyber Knight (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Cyber Knight (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Cyber Knight is a science fiction Super Famicom and PC Engine role-playing video game that combines the exploration of Star Trek with strategic robot combat. This game is intended for experienced role-playing gamers only. The random encounters are high even for a Japanese role-playing game with a mid-to-late 1992 Super Famicom release date (i.e., Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride) and the combat sequences (using melee attacks in addition to missiles and guns) are extremely slow.

n the 24th century, mankind has expanded into the reaches of outer space. Meanwhile, the Earth had already disappeared as the center of human civilization. Each star system served as independent nation; war had occurred between these "countries" several times in the past. This led to a high demand for mercenaries to fight these wars for money. Some of these mercenaries went on to become space pirates due to their insatiable demand for wealth.

The crew of the starship Swordfish are in an engagement with space pirates. Suddenly, the battle takes a turn for the worse and the crew activate their jump drive without a destination. They end up flung across the galaxy to the galactic core. The Swordfish however is badly damaged with many casualties.[2] Even the captain was killed while en route to the mysterious destination. Only 26 of the crew survive, and only six of them are qualified for combat operations: the commander, two soldiers, a mechanic and a doctor. They are responsible for using the six giant "Module" mechanized suits available for them after the fight with the space pirates. They discover a human colony that is under attack by a relentless mechanical aliens dubbed "Berserkers".

The crew must fight back against the new alien threat and explore the galaxy in order to find a way to return to Earth.

The object is to power up the human crew members and their mechs through combat experience points, explore strange new worlds using tools/weapons, and solve the problems of each alien civilization. The first mission involves saving an Earth-like planet of big people with a circa 1992 technology level from robots who want to wipe out humanity. On that planet, the president and his wife assume the throne positions of that of a king and a queen, even though their planet is assumed to be a democracy. Other quests involving trading stuff for a universal translator, braving a lava planet, and even using hyperdrive to get from planet to planet.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Cyber Knight (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 10, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Group SNE</developer>
		<publisher>Tonkin House</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cyber Knight II - Chikyuu Teikoku no Yabou (J) [T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Cyber Knight II - Chikyuu Teikoku no Yabou (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Cyber Knight II: Chikyū Teikoku no Yabō ("Cyber Knight II: Ambitions Of The Terran Empire") is a role-playing video game that deals in sci-fi components

After returning to Earth to find it being taken over by a military dictatorship, the crew is jailed but escape to be recruited into the resistance. They must travel the galaxy in their new spaceship, the Galvodirge, in order to help other human civilizations resist the attacks of the Earth's army. Like the first game, most of the planets are "dead" and serve no purpose in the game. Players even get to explore sewer systems, towns, and giant mazes.

This game is a sequel to Cyber Knight. A patch for Cyber Knight 2 was released in 2005 that allows players to play this game using the English language.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Cyber Knight II - Chikyuu Teikoku no Yabou (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 26, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Atelier Double</developer>
		<publisher>Tonkin House</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Cyborg 009 (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0_J2e+AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Cyborg 009 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0_J2e+
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Cyborg 009 is an action-adventure platformer/shoot' em up that was released for the Super Famicom on February 9, 1994 by Interbec. (30 years after the release of the original manga)

Players can select 3 of 8 cyborgs per mission and rotate through then to clear certain areas in the levels. Players use their Supergun, jumping and cyborg abilities to navigate and clear each level. However, the cyborg abilities are limited by an energy gauge and must be used wisely to clear each stage. The HP can only be replenished by special power-ups hidden throughout the levels and the SP gauges replenish slowly or by a power-up.

Each cyborg's powers help advance players through the stages:

009: Super-speed to evade attacks and outrun obstacles.
008: Able to swim in the water to get past certain areas.
007: Can copy the form of enemies
006: Fire Breath can be used to destroy certain objects or use as a ranged attack.
005: Can smash walls that obstruct the players path.
004: Uses his guns and rocket launcher to take out enemies
003: Uses her super senses to guide the player through dark rooms and caverns.
002: Uses his flight power to obtain hard to reach power ups and navigate certain areas.

001 is an NPC in this game.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Cyborg 009 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate> Feb 25, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bec</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dai-4-Ji Super Robot Taisen (J) (V1.1) [T+Eng025_Fraka].smc</path>
		<name>Dai-4-Ji Super Robot Taisen (J) (V1.1) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng025
Translated by Fraka

Gameplay of 4th Super Robot Wars is literally similar to its predecessor, Super Robot Wars EX which uses battle sprites for animations. When a stage begins, the character receives introductory dialogue between playable characters, leading to the scenario on the battle field. To complete a scenario, the player must accomplish scenario objectives. Some scenarios are longer, with multi-part missions or have new objectives added as the story unfolds. On battle field, the player and enemy take turns to order their units with commands available, such as movement, attacking, forming squads and casting "Spirit Commands", a set of magic-like spells unique to each pilot. Once the scenario is cleared, more dialogue is exchanged between characters before the player is taken to an intermission menu. Here, units can be upgraded or optional parts installed, characters' stats and skills can be changed or upgraded, and other maintenance actions can be performed before the player continues on with the game.
</desc>
		<image>./images/33415-Dai-4-ji_Super_Robot_Taisen_(Japan)-1459184862.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 17, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Banpresto</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dark Half (J) [T+Eng.25_KleptoSoft].smc</path>
		<name>Dark Half (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.25
Translated by KleptoSoft

Dark Half is a rather unique RPG. Published by Enix in 1996, Dark Half follows both the hero and the villain during the final days of the game´s world. The player alternatively controls the villain and the hero, slaughtering whole villages as the devil Rukyu and saving their souls as the paladin Falco.

Combat takes place on a grid. Rukyu can trap monsters, in so doing leveling up his magic and acquiring minions he can hide behind. Falco levels in a more traditional RPG style, and acquires magic as consumable items after most fights. There´s a crafting element for Falco´s equipment as well.

This project is actually a continuation/reboot of the work done by SirYoink on the game over the last fifteen years or so. While the hacking is all new and done by yours truly, the script translation was done by Eien ni Hen (Ancient Magic, Romancing SaGa 2) who worked with SirYoink on this. The project has SirYoink´s blessing as well.

While this was not a simple project it progressed smoothly, the end result is the polished, high-quality, and hopefully bug-free translation available now! This one has been a long time coming, so please enjoy it!
</desc>
		<image>./images/darkhalf.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>May 31, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Westone</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dark Law - Meaning of Death (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dark Law - Meaning of Death (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Dark Law is the sequel to Dark Lord, the third part in a trilogy of tangentially-related games (think Soul Blazer/Illusion of Gaia/Terranigma.) Whereas the second game in the series, Wizap!, kind of stinks, Dark Law is fully of all kinds of awesome. Combat plays similarly to Treasure Hunter G, if you´ve played that, except it´s not grid based - you have a power bar that decreases as you move, and the more it has left in it the more attacks you can make in a single turn. It´s also got multiple endings!

Dark Law is essentially the Japanese interpretation of the pencil-and-paper RPG into a videogame format. The focus is rather heavy on exploration and light on combat, with copious amounts of storytelling thrown in for good measure. It, like Dark Lord before it, is told through a series of short stories ("Scenarios") which tie together by the final conclusion. It's a pretty cool game, on the whole.

I´ve inherited this project from Haeleth, the wonderful script. It's taken a lot more effort than I expected to have to give it, but it's done and it looks mighty fine! Enjoy!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dark Law - Meaning of Death (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 28, 1997</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>RPG/StrategyRPG Hybrid</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Der Langrisser (J) (V1.1) [T+Eng 100% V1.02].smc</path>
		<name>Der Langrisser (J) (V1.1) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.02
        Der Langrisser was one of the first tactical RPGs to allow the player a choice of story paths. Depending on the player's choices, the protagonist of the game, Erwin, can switch allegiances between three factions: the Descendants of Light, the Rayguard Empire, and the Demon Tribe. Alternatively, he can choose to create his own faction in opposition to the other three.

Erwin begins the game on the side of the Descendants of Light, fighting against the Rayguard Empire, which has enlisted the aid of the Dark Lord Böser in the interest of unifying the continent and putting an end to the wars which plague it, unawares that Böser is chiefly responsible for the conflicts. To unify the continent, the Empire needs the power of the two legendary swords, Alhazard and its anti-type, Langrisser. Determined that the two swords should not serve one master, the Descendants of Light, led by Jessica, pledge to stop the Empire from finding Langrisser. Erwin commits to discovering Langrisser before the Empire.

Erwin's rival for Langrisser, Leon, is the leader of the Empire's Blue Dragon Knights and a frequent obstacle to Erwin's progress. By chance, however, the two find themselves participating in a common cause, and begin to suspect that the differences between them are not as great as they imagined. Leon suggests that Erwin side with the Empire, the choice of which is left to the player's discretion. If Erwin sides with the Empire, the roles of protagonist and antagonist are reversed: Jessica's Descendants of Light side against Erwin and the player, and the Rayguard Empire allies itself to Erwin. Former allies become enemies, and previously defeated enemy commanders become allies. The choice of sides carries significant weight to the story, because Erwin will ultimately have to kill the opposing side's commanders to bring peace.

If the player refuses Leon's offer to change sides, Erwin will remain with the Descendants of Light until the Empire is completely crushed. If the player accepts, Erwin remains with Rayguard until Langrisser is found, at which point the player may choose to betray the Empire if Erwin takes Langrisser before Leon. If Erwin betrays the Empire, he commits himself to the destruction of both the Empire and the Descendants of Light. The Prince of Darkness Böser, sensing Erwin's strength, himself betrays the Empire and places his forces under the player's command. Erwin remains with Böser until the unsealing of Alhazard, at which point he may leave it to the player's discretion whether or not to continue on with Böser or to betray him. If Boser is betrayed, Erwin will commit to a totally independent path of absolute peace for demons and humans, ultimately setting himself in opposition to the Goddess Lushiris herself. If Erwin remains loyal to Böser, he commits to destroying the Demon Tribe's enemies and taking power for himself, assuming the character of a sociopath.
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Der Langrisser (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 26, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Masaya Games</developer>
		<publisher>Nippon Computer Systems</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dezaemon - SFC (J) [h1][T+Eng1.0_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dezaemon - SFC (J) </name>
		<desc>
    Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

    The SFC version of the NES create your own shooter game. It´s been improved on in so many ways, it´s almost impossible to describe them all. Overall, it´s a great game, I highly recommend it if you want to create your own game or even just play the sample game, Daioh Gale!    
    </desc>
		<image>./images/Dezaemon SFC.png</image>
		<releasedate>September 20, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Athena</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter (Creation Kit)</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Digital Devil Story 2 - Shin Megami Tensei II (J) [T+Eng1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Digital Devil Story 2 - Shin Megami Tensei II (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Shin Megami Tensei 2 is a direct sequel to the original SMT. It takes place some 20 or 30 years later. According to the "official" story, the hero in SMT1 followed the neutral path, defeated both the Asura Lord and the seraph Michael at the Cathedral, and established a neutral government where followers of both the Law and Chaos ideals could live freely. It doesn´t last very long. The Mesia faith usurps power, begins expanding the old Cathedral into a new, massive, fully-functional artifical enclosed environment, code-named Millenium. The Gaians rise up, but their rebellion is quickly put down by the Mesians´ elite warrior class, the Temple Knights. Meanwhile, the environment is steadily becoming more and more unlivable, and sometime after the year 2060, a massive migration to Millenium occurs. Some years later, an old, retired arena fighter named Okamoto discovers a man fighting for his life against a demon. He rescues that man, who doesn´t even remember his own name, and trains him to fight in the arena so they might both go on to a better living in one of the upper-class areas of Millenium...

The gameplay has improved since SMT1. You now can now access your automap at the touch of a button, demon conversations are more complex, sword fusions are more complex, fusion errors occur, and fused demons will "inherit" spells and abilities of their "parent" demons, too. The music, in my opinion, isn´t quite as good as SMT1´s, although the graphics are much better. The current release has one or two minor fairly minor issues, please see the readme for complete details. It´s very much complete, though!

Please note that the unhack patch will fix your game if you find yourself being boosted to level 99 instantly and don´t want this. As with the main patch, apply it to a ROM without a header.

</desc>
		<image>./images/MTIIJapan.png</image>
		<releasedate>March 18, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Atlus</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Do-Re-Mi Fantasy - Milon no Dokidoki Daibouken (J) [T+Eng 99% .99_Gaijin].smc</path>
		<name>Do-Re-Mi Fantasy - Milon no Dokidoki Daibouken (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 99% .99
Translated by Gaijin

DoReMi Fantasy: Milon's DokiDoki Adventure ("DoReMi Fantasy: Milon no DokiDoki Daibouken"?) is a 1996 game released only in Japan for the Super Famicom by Hudson Soft. The game is a sequel to the 1988 NES game, Milon's Secret Castle.

It was re-released for the Wii's Virtual Console in North America on March 10, 2008, under the "Import" category, and in Europe as part of the 3rd Hanabi Festival on September 5, 2008. This version is virtually identical to the original version, and was not translated

In the game, Milon, a young boy, heads in a mission to restore the music from the forest of his hometown and rescue his friend, the fairy Alis, from an evil wizard known as Amon, who is also responsible for the music's disappearance.

DoReMi Fantasy is somewhat different from the original Milon's Secret Castle. This game is more of a straight platformer, while its predecessor combined platforming with puzzles and exploration. The game also has a more lighthearted and whimsical tone than the original.

The game no longer takes place at a dark castle with several rooms, but in several thematic areas spread in 7 worlds, which are displayed in a world map. Each world is divided by a few levels that must be cleared one after another, with a boss at the end. Milon's basic attack still consists of bubbles, although they are now used to trap enemies in them first and pop them, before the enemies escape. There are other, more powerful attack techniques such as a charged bubble. Bubbles can still be used to destroy blocks to uncover items or open new paths in the levels. Powerups allow Milon to accomplish special moves, such as the bubblegum, allowing Milon to momentarily float when he falls in the hole. Milon can jump on enemies, but they will only be stunned. Milon's health level is reflected by the clothes he is wearing. If he hasn't been touched, his clothes are colored green. When he is hit, his clothes will changed to blue, and later, red. If he is touched while wearing red, the player loses a life. Unlike the first game, dying once does not mean game over.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Do-Re-Mi Fantasy - Milon no Dokidoki Daibouken (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 22, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Doraemon 4 - Nobita to Tsuki no Oukoku (J) [T+Eng.94b_Sgt.Bowhack].smc</path>
		<name>Doraemon 4 - Nobita to Tsuki no Oukoku (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.94b
Translated by Sgt.Bowhack

The game is based on the popular manga series Doraemon. Doraemon is a blue cat robot who came from the future to protect a Japanese boy named Nobita. Nobita always gets himself in all kinds of troubles, so his grandson in the future decided to help him by sending Doraemon to keep an eye on him. One day, Nobita and Doraemon are looking at the beautiful moon, when suddenly a strange light engulfs them. They learn that something terrible has happened in the Moon Kingdom. Now they must travel to the moon and discover what is going on.

This is a platform action game that is somewhat similar to Super Mario World. You travel on a world map and enter various platform locations. Before each level, you can choose to play as either Doraemon, Nobita, or other four available characters. You can jump on enemies' heads or shoot at them with various weapons to eliminate them. There are many items and upgrades scattered around the levels, and sometimes it is possible to power-up by using two characters simultaneously.
</desc>
		<image>./images/217-102437.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 15 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Epoch</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dossun! Ganseki Battle (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dossun! Ganseki Battle (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

It´s an SFC block puzzler, which takes pages from the books of Columns and Puyo Puyo (which both take pages from Tetris´ book.) You stack up the blocks, clearing blocks with the same type icons, dealing damage to your opponent until one of you is killed. It´s a pretty fun game, I definately recommend you checking it out if you´re at all a fan of puzzle games :)
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dossungansekisfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 16, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>I'MAX</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Hyper Dimension (J) [T+Eng 100% Twilight Translations].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Hyper Dimension (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Twilight Translations

Dragon Ball Z: Hyper Dimension (Doragon Bōru Zetto Haipā Dimenshon) is a Dragon Ball Z fighting game released for the Super Famicom in Japan on March 29, 1996, and the Super Nintendo in Europe on February 1997. It was the last Dragon Ball Z game to be released for the console.

Hyper Dimension features a story similar to that of the Dragon Ball Z anime, taking place from the late Frieza Saga through the Kid Buu Saga. The only prominent difference is that select characters losing certain battles does not impede on the progression of the plot. Other characters deaths, usually those of Goku or Gohan, require the use of a credit, appropriately a Senzu Bean, to continue playing. Also, the story mode of Hyper Dimension is not like other fighting games of its time, such as Street Fighter, Tekken, or Mortal Kombat where the plot focuses on the character selected by the player. Scenarios during the game start with focus on one character and generally end with the focus of another. The story mode is also quite inaccurate to the true story; mostly due to the lack of characters during various points in the story. Examples include Piccolo fighting Frieza in his final form and Goku being the one to defeat Cell as a Super Saiyan 2.

The amount of life for characters is measured by a number system from 1 to 999, which can be charged at any time during the match. When the life reaches a level below 80, the characters are able to perform "desperate moves", which cause significantly higher amounts of damage. The characters fight on a multi-tier stage, which allows opponents to hit each other to other stages.

In addition to Story Mode, the game features Versus, Tournament and Practice Modes. The Versus Mode allows a player to fight a computer-controlled character, or for two players to fight each other. The Tournament Mode allows up to eight players to compete against each other, or computer-controlled characters, similar to the previous Butōden games. Practice Mode allows a player to fight a player-controlled character, but no damage is dealt. This mode is useful for mastering combos or experimenting with the fundamental controls of the game.

Used to listen to background music and sound effects. Although the Story Mode is not included in the French version of the game, the BGM tracks related to it can still be heard here.

</desc>
		<image>./images/HyperD.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 29, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Legend Of The Super Saiyan (J) [T+Eng 100% Klepto Soft].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Legend Of The Super Saiyan (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by KleptoSoft


Dragon Ball Z: Super Saiya Densetsu (Doragon Bōru Zetto Supā Saiya Densetsu; lit. "Dragon Ball Z: Legend of the Super Saiyan") is a role playing video game and the first Dragon Ball game for the Super Famicom. It was released only in Japan on January 25, 1992.

Super Saiya Densetsu is a remake combining two earlier Famicom games of the Gokuden series: Dragon Ball Z: Kyōshū! Saiyan and Dragon Ball Z II: Gekishin Freeza, but without the movie characters and anime filler elements that were featured in them.

The game follows the rough outline of the Vegeta, Namek, and Frieza Sagas, with various add-ons and edits to make the story fit within the RPG guidelines, such as the inclusion of multi-colored Saibamen and re-colors of Frieza's henchmen and the Ginyu Force members as common enemies.

Playable characters consist of (in order): Goku, Piccolo, Gohan, Krillin, Yamcha, Tien Shinhan, Chiaotzu, Dende, two Namek Warriors (Maima and Tsumuri), Vegeta, Nail, and Captain Ginyu (through body exchange). By using Captain Ginyu, you can manage to take the body of any character, though this returns to normal at the end of a fight.

Enemies in the game include: Blue, Orange, Green, Black, Purple/Cyan, and Gray Saibamen. Once on Namek, there are two of Frieza's henchmen (Banan and Appule), who get two color edits as separate enemies. After they are defeated, Cui, Dodoria, Zarbon, and the Ginyu Force all get two re-colors as individual enemies that are roughly half as strong as their originals.

Bosses in the game include: Raditz (Black Saibaman double), Raditz, Green Saibaman and Nappa, King Kai, Vegeta, Cui (can be fought before encountering Frieza for the first time, or fought after collecting the cave Dragon Ball), Dodoria, and Zarbon in both forms. Guldo and Recoome fight as a pair as well as Jeice and Burter. Depending on which one you kill the other runs away and brings back Ginyu. Frieza is fought several times, first as a Black Saibaman clone. After defeating his 2nd form, he runs away protected by Ginyu Force Recolors. Frieza is randomly encountered in his 3rd form, and during his 4th form, he can "power up" to his maximum. If the player sacrifices an ally to make Goku become Super Saiyan, and keeps Goku alive for the fight, a Super Saiyan Vegeta encounters the group for a secret final battle after the end of the credit roll.

Bulma also joins the crew for most of the game, providing a place to rest while on Earth and Namek. Master Roshi only appears once to support the players against Raditz. Grand Elder Guru appears on Namek powering up all characters in the party. There are a few surviving Namekians who will talk to you and give you information. Also there are two fairies on Namek that allow you to collect a Dragon Ball and pass into Guru's domain.

The fighting system is based on a variety of symbols, numbers (represented by dots), and the card itself. The player has a total of 5 cards (5 attacks) for most situations, randomly generated. The player can use item cards like Oolong to re-exchange them, or King Yemma or Chi-Chi to max out a card's potential.

Normal Attack Cards: White cards with a School Character (Turtle School, Demon, Kami, Alien). A character has a preference (Piccolo's preference is Demon) and that will initiate an "attack all."
Strong Attack Cards: Yellow cards. Piccolo's preference switches to these after an optional super-fusion with Dende and Two Nameks.
Ginyu Attack Cards: Black Cards with Ginyu Force symbol. Basically the same as Normal Attack Cards.
Ki Attack Cards: Blue Cards. Each Ki Card uses one Ki Attack or Ability.
The number of stars on the top-left Dragon Ball references the attack power (one star being weakest, Z being strongest). There are eight ranks of strength.

The character on the bottom-right Dragon Ball icon determines its defensive power. This also has eight ranks, with a single wavy line (representing one) being the weakest defense, and Z being the strongest. If two attacking characters of equal power attack enemies of equal power with cards of equal type and attack power, the enemy with a weak defense power will take more damage than one with a higher defense.

Attack speed is determined by the attack power of a card. Strongest attack power always goes first (unless Vegeta interrupts), followed, in descending order, by the next strongest cards. If, however, two or more cards have the same attack power in a single turn, attack speed is then based on defense power. (Goku, Piccolo, and Tien use Z-Attack cards, but Tien has Z-Defense, while Goku and Piccolo have lower defense, so Tien goes first). If, though, the attack and defense of a card are BOTH equal amongst two or more people, the character's Power Level is used to determine attack speed.

There are two major stores in the game. One is Baba's house, easily noticed as being dark gray with bricks. Fortuneteller Baba will buy/sell item cards to a player in exchange for zeni. Baba's store is replaced by a Namekian salesman when the story advances to Namek.

The other place is a training center. Players can improve the Ki number of the character by powering up and destroying a rock. Also at the training center, the player can fight waves of enemies for zeni, though by doing this they do not receive experience.

Story related items do not have a zeni cost beside their picture. Story items include Dragon Balls and the Dragon Radar, as well as cards such as Enraged Gohan, the Moon, and Vegeta.

The basic cards heal HP and Ki. Other cards can change combat cards, and improve the power of the character by 25% or even 50%. The Grandpa Gohan card is unique, as it stuns an opponent for several turns. Scouters can be purchased or won in battle as well, and depending on its strength can show how strong an opponent is numerically.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Picado_2.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>January 25, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Super Butouden (F) [T+Eng.98_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Super Butouden (F) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.98
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Dragon Ball Z: Super Butōden (ドラゴンボールZ 超武闘伝, Doragon Bōru Zetto Chō Butōden; lit. "Dragon Ball Z: Super Fighting Story") is a fighting game and the first installment in the Butōden video game series. It was released for the Super Famicom (Super Nintendo) in Japan on March 20, 1993, and in France and Spain on November 30, 1993.

Super Butōden starts with 8 playable characters, and 5 other characters are unlockable characters, for a total of 13 playable characters in the game. Its story mode spans from the Piccolo Jr. Saga to the conclusion of the Cell Games Saga.

The game features massive stages divided by a color-coded split-screen border which tells the players how close they are to their opponent. Combat can take place on the ground or in the air. A radar located below the health and power bars tells where the characters are in the stage. There are also unique special moves and "super moves" for each character (Goku's Kamehameha, Vegeta's Final Flash, Android 16's Hell's Flash, etc.). Players can counter super moves by dodging, blocking, or engaging in a beam struggle.

Knock-down recovery takes a fairly long time and leaves the characters open to further attack. Unlike the following games of the series, Ki is charged manually by holding down while flying. In later Super Butōden games, ki is charged by holding B+Y, and this can be done on the ground as well as in the air.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon_Ball_z_caratula.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 20, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>1-on-1 Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Super Gokuuden Kakusei Hen (J) [T+Eng308_KakkoiiTranslations].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Super Gokuuden Kakusei Hen (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng308
Translated by Kakkoii Translations

Dragon Ball Z: Super Gokuden: Kakusei-Hen ("Dragon Ball Z: Super Legend of Goku - Chapter of Awakening -") is the second and last video game of the Super Gokuden series. It was released only in Japan on September 22, 1995, for the Super Nintendo.

Super Gokuden: Kakusei-Hen follows the story of Goku from his fight with Piccolo at the 23rd World Martial Arts Tournament in the Piccolo Jr. Saga to his final battle with Frieza after Goku had reached the Super Saiyan state in the Frieza Saga. Gohan is also playable in the game. In this game, like its predecessor, the characters are seen fighting by their side.

The game features a different overview combat system, where your character flashes before he can attack, to advance in the game the player has to answer different quizzes in the game according of what happened in the manga in certain quizzes there are two correct options selecting the one said in the manga the story will proceed but selecting the other reveals a new ending like Kami killing Piccolo in the Piccolo Jr. Saga or Frieza obtaining his immortality in the Frieza Saga. It also features battles using different buttons to do certain actions like: using A to use a Ki Blast, B to use a Punch Attack, X to use a Powerful Attack and Y to Counterattack, it also features Special Attacks using A+X like a Kamehameha or Special Defense Actions using X+Y like a Solar Flare.

Playable characters
Goku (Base, Super Saiyan)
Gohan
Bosses
Chi-Chi
Tien Shinhan
Piccolo
Raditz
King Kai
Saibaman
Nappa
Vegeta
Krillin
Cui
Appule
Dodoria
Zarbon (Base, transformed)
Virtual Vegeta (仮想ベジータ)
Guldo
Recoome
Burter
Jeice
Captain Ginyu (Base, Goku's body)
Frieza (2nd Form, Final Form, 100% Power)
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon_ball_z_super_gokuden_2_japon.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 22, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Super Gokuuden Totsugeki Hen (J) [T+Eng100_Ginew].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Super Gokuuden Totsugeki Hen (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng100
Translated by Ginew

Dragon Ball Z: Super Gokuden - Totsugeki-Hen (ドラゴンボールZ 超悟空伝 -突激編-; lit. "Dragon Ball Z: Super Legend of Goku -Chapter of Assault-") is a video game released on March 24, 1995 for the Super Famicom console only in Japan. Its sequel is Dragon Ball Z: Super Gokuden: Kakusei-Hen.

Super Gokuden: Totsugeki-Hen chronicles the adventures of Goku and his friends through the start of Dragon Ball all the way to the final battle with King Piccolo.

The game features a different overview combat system, where your character flashes before he can attack. To advance in the game the player, has to answer different quiz according of what happened in the manga. The game also features battles using a Rock-Paper-Scissors battle system.</desc>
		<image>./images/564400_4431_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 24, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Action / RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Ultime Menace (F) [T+Eng1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Ultime Menace (F) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Dragon Ball Z: Super Butōden 3 (Doragon Bōru Zetto Chō Butōden Surī; lit. "Dragon Ball Z: Super Fighting Story 3"), called Dragon Ball Z 3: Ultime Menace in France, is a fighting game released for Super Nintendo on September 29, 1994, in Japan and on March 1995 in France and Spain. It is the third installment in the Butōden video game series.

Super Butōden 3 features ten playable characters based on the Majin Buu Saga. Unlike its predecessors, there is no story mode in the game. Instead, the Tournament Mode seems to double as the story mode for the game as when a character is crowned the champion, the credits start rolling.

In comparison with several seconds of charge time in Super Butōden 2, charging Ki takes only a couple of seconds in Super Butōden 3.

Playable characters
The game has 10 characters, 9 normal and 1 hidden. The hidden character, Future Trunks, can be unlocked with a code.

Character Selection screen, with Future Trunks unlocked
Super Saiyan Goku
Super Saiyan Goten
Majin Buu
Super Saiyan Trunks
Majin Vegeta
Super Saiyan Gohan
Supreme Kai
Dabura
Android 18
Secret character
Super Saiyan Future Trunks

</desc>
		<image>./images/564122_4426_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Ball Z - Ultime Menace (F) [T+Eng1.1_DBZ+Vice].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Ball Z - Ultime Menace (F) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.1_DBZ+
Translated by Vice

Dragon Ball Z: Super Butōden 3 (Doragon Bōru Zetto Chō Butōden Surī; lit. "Dragon Ball Z: Super Fighting Story 3"), called Dragon Ball Z 3: Ultime Menace in France, is a fighting game released for Super Nintendo on September 29, 1994, in Japan and on March 1995 in France and Spain. It is the third installment in the Butōden video game series.

Super Butōden 3 features ten playable characters based on the Majin Buu Saga. Unlike its predecessors, there is no story mode in the game. Instead, the Tournament Mode seems to double as the story mode for the game as when a character is crowned the champion, the credits start rolling.

In comparison with several seconds of charge time in Super Butōden 2, charging Ki takes only a couple of seconds in Super Butōden 3.

Playable characters
The game has 10 characters, 9 normal and 1 hidden. The hidden character, Future Trunks, can be unlocked with a code.

Character Selection screen, with Future Trunks unlocked
Super Saiyan Goku
Super Saiyan Goten
Majin Buu
Super Saiyan Trunks
Majin Vegeta
Super Saiyan Gohan
Supreme Kai
Dabura
Android 18
Secret character
Super Saiyan Future Trunks
</desc>
		<image>./images/564122_4426_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE Software Co</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Quest I &amp; II (J) [T+Eng 100% 2.0DWu1_RPGOne].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Quest I &amp; II (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 2.0DWu1
Translated by RPG One

Dragon Quest I•II came out in late 1993 in Japan, much to the delight of Japanese RPG fans who cannot get enough of Dragon Quest. Dragon Quest I•II served as a straight ahead remake of the first two Dragon Quest games, with updated sound, graphics and changes to the amount of gold and experience rewarded to reduce the need for grinding. There is some evidence that Enix may have considered it for an English translation, however it never saw the light of day. RPGOne, a fan translation group led by the late ChrisRPG, completed a fan translation of Dragon Quest I•II in 2003. They included the option of using the patch with Japanese or Dragon Warrior style naming. Another re-release of the Dragon Quest I•II came out on the Game Boy Colour in 2000 in the US (as Dragon Warrior 1&amp;2), with Japanese naming scheme. This review of the SFC version uses RPGOne's translation with Dragon Warrior style naming scheme.

The Story

Dragon Quest I and II are the first two parts of the first Dragon Quest trilogy. Dragon Quest takes place in the kingdom of Alefgard, where you play as the descendent of the great hero, Erdrick. The evil Dragonlord is causing havoc, while at the same time, a dragon kidnaps Princess Gwaelin. In a solo journey, the hero travels throughout Alefgard collecting key items to reach the castle of the Dragonlord, and saving the kingdom.

Dragon Quest II happens 100 years after the first Dragon Quest game. The descendent of the hero from Dragon Quest reside in three kingdoms, eventually joining together to battle the wizard Hargon. The world of Dragon Quest II is far larger than Dragon Quest, and Alefgard makes up only a small part of the map. Due to this, travel gates and a boat allow the heroes to travel the overworld.

Fan service remake or cash in?

Immediately after starting play of this remake, it seems incredibly obvious that little work was done to upgrade this game. Sure the graphics and sound are better than their NES equivalents, but for the most part it is just Dragon Quests I and II using the Dragon Quest V game engine. In fact, it almost looks like they downgraded from the Dragon Quest V engine, and made things look more simplistic (see below). As far as I could tell, there aren't any special bonuses. The enemies in this game are not easier than the NES games, though thankfully they drop more experience points and gold, so grinding is not necessary for the most part. When compared to contemporary turn based RPGs for the Super NES (i.e. Final Fantasy V, Lufia &amp; the Fortress of Doom, and Breath of Fire), these games are dated. Additions such as graphical effects for spells and backgrounds in battle screens seem tacked on. They could not even be bothered to give you the option of town to transport to with the Return spell. This is about as straight forward of a remake as you could get.

Of course, you cannot ignore the popularity of Dragon Quest in Japan. Dragon Quest I•II surely was a huge seller in Japan (reaching #5 in the Japanese charts, according to Super Play), and bridged a gap between the release of V and VI. The success of this game also led to the re-release of Dragon Quest III on the Super Famicom. Considering the dated look and the lack of popularity of RPGs in the US, it is not surprising this game was not ported to the US.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon Quest I &amp; II (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 18, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Enix</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Quest III (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.1 DQ Translations].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Quest III (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.1 

Translated by DQ Translations

Dragon Quest III: The Seeds of Salvation, known in Japan as Dragon Quest III: Soshite Densetsu and previously released as Dragon Warrior III in North America, is a role-playing video game developed by Chunsoft and published by Enix (now Square Enix). It is the third installment in the Dragon Quest series (known as Dragon Warrior in North America at the time of its original release) and the first released for the Family Computer (Famicom) in Japan and later for the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) in North America. The game saw an enhanced remake for the Super Famicom (the Japanese version of the Super NES) in 1996 and the Game Boy Color in 2001, and a port to mobile phones and the Wii in 2009 and 2011. A version of the game for Android and iOS was released in Japan on September 25, 2014, and worldwide on December 4, 2014 as Dragon Quest III: The Seeds of Salvation. It was the first time the game was given an official English subtitle.

The first three Dragon Quest games are part of the same story, and Dragon Warrior III is the first game chronologically, as well as the third game that features the hero Erdrick (Loto in some remakes). The story follows "the Hero" who is tasked with saving the world from the archfiend Baramos. Gathering a group of companions into a party, the Hero must travel the world, stopping at various towns and locations, and find his way to the Demon Lord Baramos's lair.

Dragon Quest III is noted for greatly expanding upon the gameplay of the original Dragon Quest and Dragon Quest II. The game uses basic role-playing video game conventions such as leveling up by gaining experience points and equipping items. Battle is turn-based like the other games in the series, though the remakes incorporate various interface changes from later titles. These include simpler door opening, a bag to store items instead of keeping them at a bank, quick item sorting with "Tidy Item" and "Tidy Bag" command, and a "Full HP" command to automate the process of casting healing and status restoring spells. And while earlier Dragon Quest games were non-linear in structure, Dragon Quest III featured an even more open-world experience. It also allowed the player to freely swap characters in and out of their party, and introduced the day/night cycle in which certain items, characters, and quests are only accessible at specific times of day

Dragon Quest III features a class system, in which each character has a certain class. At the start of the game, the player begins as a single male or female hero, but is able to recruit members at the local tavern. While the Hero always keeps the Hero class, the other characters can choose to be any of the following of either gender: Soldier (Warrior in the GBC version), Fighter, Pilgrim (Cleric), Wizard (Mage), Merchant (Dealer), Goof-Off (Jester), Sage, and Thief which was available only in the later versions. The choice of class greatly affects the character's stats and spells he or she can learn. Furthermore, upon reaching experience Level 20, a character has the option of changing classes at the temple of Dhama, found halfway through the game. A character who changes classes has their stats halved and restarts at experience Level 1, retaining their spells and, in the remakes, their personality. This allows a player to create a character that knows Wizard spells, but has the defense of a Soldier. Unlike most Dragon Quest parties, aside from the Hero, the party is not made up of characters involved in the story. Although only four characters can be in the party at a time, extra members of the party can be kept at the tavern, allowing room for new recruits. Another innovation is an arena where the player can place bets on the outcome of monster battles in order to win more gold.

In the remakes, after selecting a character, the player can change the character's starting abilities with five magical seeds, given at the tavern. Also, each character has a personality trait which affects the growth rate of their abilities. The Hero's personality is determined by the player's choices and actions during a dream sequence at the start of the game, while other characters' personalities are determined by their status at the end of the character generation process. Most personalities are available to both male and female characters, while a few are exclusive to male or female characters. A character's personality can be temporarily changed by equipping certain accessories, or permanently changed by using certain consumable books.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon Quest III - Soshite Densetsu e... (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>February 10, 1998 / 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Chunsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Quest V - Tenkuu no Hanayome (J) [T+Eng 99% 2.01F_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Quest V - Tenkuu no Hanayome (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 99% 2.01F
Translated by DeJap

Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (Doragon Kuesuto Faibu Tenkū no Hanayome?, "Dragon Quest V: The Heavenly Bride"), known as Dragon Quest: The Hand of the Heavenly Bride in Europe, is a role-playing video game and the fifth installment in the Dragon Quest video game series. Originally developed by Chunsoft and published by Enix Corporation, Dragon Quest V was the first title in the series to be released for the Nintendo Super Famicom (SFC) video game console in Japan on September 27, 1992. It has since been remade for the PlayStation 2 in 2004; which was developed by ArtePiazza and Matrix Software, and published by Square Enix only in Japan. Another remake was made for the Nintendo DS, and was released on July 17, 2008 in Japan. The remake was also released in North America and Europe, marking the first time the game had an official release in either territory. The game was released on February 17, 2009 for the North American market. A version of the game for Android and iOS was released in Japan on December 12, 2014, and worldwide in English on January 22, 2015.

Dragon Quest V was the first game in the series to not be released outside Japan, as Enix did not want to pay for the cost of the larger cartridge ROMs needed to fit English-language dialog. Poor sales of Dragon Quest II, Dragon Quest III, and Dragon Quest IV in North America were also a factor. In the absence of an official translation, several fan translations were created between 1998 and 2002, followed by a more recent fan translation of the PlayStation 2 remake.

Dragon Quest V takes place over roughly thirty years of the main character's life, from when he is born through to when he gets married and has a family. The title introduced a gameplay dynamic in which monsters from random encounters may offer to join the player's party. This concept was used in later Dragon Quest games, and in the Dragon Quest Monsters series constituted the primary way to form a party.

The game's monster-collecting concept has since become influential, appearing in many later franchises such as Pokémon, Digimon and Dokapon.[12] In turn, the concept of collecting everything in a game, in the form of achievements or similar rewards, has since become a common trend in video games. Dragon Quest V has also been credited as the first known video game to feature a playable pregnancy, a concept that has since appeared in later games such as Story of Seasons, The Sims 2 and Fable II.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon Quest V - Tenkuu no Hanayome (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 27, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Chunsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Quest VI - Maboroshi no Daichi (J) [T+Eng.90-2_NoPrgress].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Quest VI - Maboroshi no Daichi (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.90-2
Translated by NoPrgress

Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation (Doragon Kuesuto Shikkusu Maboroshi no Daichi?, "Dragon Quest VI: Land of Illusion"), Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Reverie in Europe, is a role-playing video game developed by Heartbeat and published by Enix (now Square Enix) for the Super Famicom as a part of the Dragon Quest series and as the last Dragon Quest game in the Zenithia trilogy. It was released on December 9, 1995 in Japan, developed by Heartbeat; whereas the previous Dragon Quest games were developed by Chunsoft. In July 2007, Square Enix announced a series of remakes of Dragon Quest IV: Chapters of the Chosen, Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride and Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation for the Nintendo DS, making this the first time the game in question got released on other consoles and overseas.[8] Like its predecessor, Dragon Quest VI was a Japan-only release as the larger ROMs needed for English dialog were cost-prohibitive (the game was already 32 megabits in size, the limit for SNES ROMs without using bank switching). In addition, the game's release occurred very late into the SNES's lifespan, by which time Enix had dropped support for the console outside Japan. The title was finally released overseas for the Nintendo DS in North America on February 14, 2011 and in Europe on May 20, 2011. A version of the game for Android and iOS was released in Japan on June 10, 2015, and worldwide in English on June 24, 2015.

As the sixth installment to the Dragon Quest series, the graphics and gameplay remain close to the other games, with minor additions and upgrades. The graphics were vastly improved from Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride, which was also for the SNES, but had rather unimpressive graphics due to being an early game on the console. Navigation remains largely unchanged from the previous games and the turn-based battles are still in first-person. The class system from Dragon Quest III returns, with minor adjustments.[9] The large cartridge ROM used by the game resulted in an extremely high price of 11,970 yen (about 137 dollars), Dragon Quest VI sold 3.2 million copies in Japan, becoming the best selling game of 1995. The DS version sold an additional one million copies by March 2010.

The story follows the traditional Dragon Quest "Hero" on a quest to save the world. In this particular installment, the heroes also have to endure the personal struggle of amnesia, as many of the main characters do not initially remember who they are. After completing a series of quests, the player learns that in addition to a Real World, there is also a Dream World, made up of people's dreams, and that there is a great evil that wants to conquer both. The Hero and his new party work together to save both worlds from the ever-growing threat.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon Quest VI - Maboroshi no Daichi (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 9, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Heartbeat</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dragon Squadron Danzarub (J) [T+Eng 100% V1 AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Dragon Squadron Danzarub (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Danzarb is a quirky sci-fi mecha RPG. It´s segmented into chapters or episodes, each having a minigame or puzzle for you to solve. In one, for example, you´re tasked with locating a bunch of ID card segments then you have to do a little sliding puzzle to put them together. In another, you collect clues to a time bomb defuse sequence from enemy soldiers, and you have to piece them together in a logic puzzle to decode the sequence. It´s a fairly nifty game. Now that Tom´s resurfaced, he´s translated most of the text! I also restarted the hacking work on the game, and have produced a much cleaner script solution than I had in the past. Things are looking up for the Danzarb project!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dragon Squadron Danzarb (Ingles).png</image>
		<releasedate>April 23, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Gainax/Pandora Box</developer>
		<publisher>Yutaka</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dream Maze - The Kigurumi Adventure (J)[T+Eng 100% V1.0b KingMike].smc</path>
		<name>Dream Maze - The Kigurumi Adventure (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.0b 
Translated by KingMike

Dream Maze is a first-person RPG. Possibly the most bizarre first-person RPG released on the system. In this game, you play as the hero who is destined to relive one dream over and over again until he destroys the demon Akumu, who has enslaved the four princesses and the Queen of the world of Enderia. Also, the stuffed animals and toys of the world have become possessed. If our hero hopes to destroy Akumu, he will need to beat up the stuffed animals, and take the clothes, called Kigurumi, that are left behind. When putting on a new suit, at one of the Changing Rooms located throughout the land, his offensive and defensive abilities will change, hopefully for the better. With a strong enough costume, our hero, and his two allies, will be able to fight back and rescue the princesses and the Queen from the demon Akumu.
</desc>
		<image>./images/360full-yume-meikyuu--kigurumi-daibouken-(dream-maze--the-kigurumi-adventure)-cover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>April 15, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>HECT / Axes Art Amuse</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dual Orb II (J) [T+Eng 100% V15 Transcorp].smc</path>
		<name>Dual Orb II (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V15 
Translated by Transcorp

Dual Orb II is a Japanese video game released for the Super Famicom. It is the sequel to 'Dual Orb' and it is only available in Japanese language format. Dual Orb II focuses on Aleth, a mysterious boy found by the High Priest of Garade when he was just a baby. His best friend, Lagnus, is the prince of Garade and his partner in swordplay. Aleth and Lagnus soon venture into a forbidden dungeon where they discover a "goddess" with no memory. After being scolded for violating the temple, Lagnus and Aleth are informed by a messenger, Cassius, that the nation of Kardosa is invading Garade. Together the four of them go to Garade. Once there Lagnus witnesses his father being killed and starts to turn into a world of darkness. Aleth must now find out the intentions of Kardosa, Learn who Serra really is, and stop Lagnus from plunging into a fate of hate and revenge.

Dual Orb II was scored by Nobuyuki Hara and Yu Yoshida.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Dual Orb II (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 29, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>I'Max Corp</developer>
		<publisher>I'Max Corp</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Emerald Dragon (J)[T+Eng 100% V1.1 Transcorp].smc</path>
		<name>Emerald Dragon (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.1 
Translated by Transcorp

Emerald Dragon (Emerarudo Doragon?) is a computer role-playing game developed by Glodia that was released for multiple platforms exclusively in Japan. It was first released for NEC Corporation's PC-8801 and PC-9801 home computers on December 22, 1989, followed by conversions for the X68000 (released on December 6, 1990), MSX2 (released on December 26 of the same year) and FM Towns (released on May 28, 1992). Developer Alfa System later produced console versions of the game for the PC Engine in Super CD-ROM format (released on January 28, 1994) and the Super Famicom (released on July 28, 1995). The game features characters and locations based on Zoroastrian mythology.

The game utilises a top-down overhead perspective, where players move the controllable character in two dimensions. As the player moves around in a world map, he or she may encounter battles which are turn-based with a time point system: both movements and attacks sap a bar on the top of the screen, and the character's turn ends when the bar is depleted. As this is a role-playing game, experience points are collected for defeating enemies which are used to level-up playable characters.

For the main protagonist, Atorushan, stronger attacks are made available through key items collected in the game called the Emerald Graces. These transform him into a dragon to unleash a powerful attack, at the cost of reducing his HP when used.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Emerald Dragon (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 22, 1989</releasedate>
		<developer>Alfa System</developer>
		<publisher>MediaWorks</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Energy Breaker (J)[T+Eng V1.02 Disnesquick].smc</path>
		<name>Energy Breaker (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng V1.02 
Translated by Disnesquick

Despite us all having an overflowing RPG backlog, we'll always welcome fan translations of classic Japanese exclusive adventures. Energy Breaker, the 1996 Super Famicom isometric tactical role-playing-game developed by Neverland Co and published by Taito, has been given the English localisation treatment - which can now be downloaded and enjoyed.

While most will refer to Final Fantasy Tactics or Ogre Battle as being the definitive tactical RPGs, Energy Breaker holds one huge draw over its groundbreaking siblings. Energy Breaker's scenes in between battle, or 'adventure mode' shall we say, doesn't rely on an overworld map. The RPG takes an approach similar to that of Chrono Trigger and Secret of Mana where by the area you're exploring is also your battleground.

Gameplay and genre aside, Energy Breaker's story begins with its protagonist Myra being visited in a dream by a mysterious woman known as Selphia. Myra, however, is then shocked to meet Selphia in real life the following day. Following Selphia's advice, Myra travels to Eltois, the Wind Forest, in the hope of catching up to a man who knows about her intriguing past. Upon arrival at the Wind Forest, Myra meets a scientist who’s searching for the Reincarnation, a legendary flower that holds a scent said to harbour the power to bring the dead back to life. This, however, leads Myra down a path much longer than expected with plenty of adventures ahead.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Energy Breaker (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 26, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Neverland, Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Famicom Detective Club Part II (J)[T+Eng 100% V1 Demiforce].smc</path>
		<name>Famicom Detective Club Part II (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by Demiforce

Famicom Tantei Club Part II: Ushiro ni Tatsu Shōjo ("Famicom Detective Club Part II: The Girl who Stands Behind") is a text-based adventure game released by Nintendo in 1989 for the Family Computer Disk System. The original version was released in two discs in 1989, and the game was ported to the Super Famicom and the Game Boy Advance several years later. The Super Famicom version was released in Japan for the Wii's Virtual Console on April 30, 2008, and Wii U's Virtual Console on July 31, 2013. The Famicom version was released for the Virtual Console on December 22, 2009. Neither version of the game was ever released outside Japan, although an English translation patch has been released by the translation group Demiforce for the enhanced Super Famicom version.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Famicom Tantei Club Part II - Ushiro ni Tatsu Shoujo (Japan) (NP) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>April 1 1998</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Feda - The Emblem of Justice (J)[T+Eng 100% 1.02 Stealth].smc</path>
		<name>Feda - The Emblem of Justice (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.02 
Translated by Stealth

Feda: The Emblem of Justice is a tactical role playing game developed by Max Entertainment and published by Yanoman Games that was originally released for the Super Famicom in 1994. The game centers around two soldiers forced to fight against the now-corrupted empire they used to serve. A version for the Sega Saturn, titled Feda Remake!, was released in 1996. Both versions were released exclusively in Japan.

Feda is a tactical role playing game composed of two primary play modes: exploration and battles. During an exploration stage, the player explore towns and other locations and visit shops and houses. When the player enters the overworld, the game becomes turn based and the player can move units to confront enemies. Battles are activated when the player and an enemy unit occupy the same area or in scripted event. Feda feature cinematic battle scenes similar to the Shining Force series. Depending on which character the player uses to act, the scene shows him in full picture or just a part of the character (unlike in Shining Force where the player always just sees his character from behind and the enemy in front of him). During battles, the screen switches from the player's unitto the enemy.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Feda - The Emblem of Justice (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 28, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Max Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Yanoman</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Final Fantasy IV (J) [T+Eng 100% 3.21_J2E].smc</path>
		<name>Final Fantasy IV (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 3.21_
Translated by J2E

Final Fantasy IV is a role-playing video game developed and published by Square (now Square Enix) for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. Released in 1991, it is the fourth main installment of the Final Fantasy series. The game's story follows Cecil, a dark knight, as he tries to prevent the sorcerer Golbez from seizing powerful crystals and destroying the world. He is joined on this quest by a frequently changing group of allies. Final Fantasy IV introduced innovations that became staples of the Final Fantasy series and role-playing games in general. Its "Active Time Battle" system was used in five subsequent Final Fantasy games, and unlike prior games in the series, IV gave each character their own unchangeable character class.

In Final Fantasy IV, the player controls a large cast of characters and completes quests to advance the story. Characters move and interact with people and enemies on a field map, which may represent a variety of settings, such as towers, caves, and forests. Travel between areas occurs on a world map. The player can use towns to replenish strength, buy equipment, and discover clues about their next destination. Conversely, the player fights monsters at random intervals on the world map and in dungeons. In battle, the player has the option to fight, use magic or an item, retreat, change character positions, parry, or pause. Certain characters have special abilities. The game was the first in the series to allow the player to control up to five characters in their party; previous games had limited the party to four.

With its character-driven plot, use of new technologies and critically acclaimed score by Nobuo Uematsu, Final Fantasy IV is regarded as a landmark of the series and the role-playing genre.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Final Fantasy IV (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 19, 1991</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Final Fantasy V (J) [T+Eng1.1_RPGe].smc</path>
		<name>Final Fantasy V (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.1
Translated by RPGe

Final Fantasy V is a medieval-fantasy role-playing video game developed and published by Square (now Square Enix) in 1992 as a part of the Final Fantasy series. The game first appeared only in Japan on Nintendo's Super Famicom (known internationally as the Super Nintendo Entertainment System). It has been ported with minor differences to Sony's PlayStation and Nintendo's Game Boy Advance. An original video animation produced in 1994 called Final Fantasy: Legend of the Crystals serves as a sequel to the events depicted in the game. It was released for the PlayStation Network on April 6, 2011 in Japan. An enhanced port of the game, with new high resolution graphics and a touch-based interface, was released for iPhone and iPad on March 28, 2013, and for Android on September 25, 2013.

The game begins as a wanderer named Bartz investigates a fallen meteor. There, he encounters several characters, one of whom reveals the danger facing the four Crystals that control the world's elements. These Crystals act as a seal on Exdeath, an evil sorcerer. Bartz and his party must keep the Crystals from being exploited by Exdeath's influence and prevent his resurgence.

Final Fantasy V has been praised for the freedom of customization that the player has over the characters, achieved through the greatly expanded Job System. Despite being released only in Japan, the Super Famicom version sold more than two million copies. The PlayStation version has earned "Greatest Hits" status, selling more than 350,000 copies.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Final Fantasy V (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 6, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Final Fantasy VI (J) [T+Eng1.2_RPGOne].smc</path>
		<name>Final Fantasy VI (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.2
Translated by RPG One

Final Fantasy VI is a role-playing video game developed and published by Square for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. Released in 1994, it is the sixth title in the mainline Final Fantasy series. Set in a fantasy world with a technology level equivalent to that of the Second Industrial Revolution, the game's story focuses on a group of rebels as they seek to overthrow an imperial dictatorship. The game features fourteen permanent playable characters, the most of any game in the main series.

Final Fantasy VI was released to critical acclaim and is seen as a landmark title for the role-playing genre; for instance, it was ranked as the number one RPG of all time by IGN. Its Super NES and PlayStation versions have sold over 3.48 million copies worldwide to date as a stand-alone game, as well as over 750,000 copies as part of the Japanese Final Fantasy Collection and the North American Final Fantasy Anthology. Final Fantasy VI has won numerous awards since its release.

Like previous Final Fantasy installments, Final Fantasy VI consists of four basic modes of gameplay: an overworld map, town and dungeon field maps, a battle screen, and a menu screen. The overworld map is a scaled-down version of the game's fictional world, which the player uses to direct characters to various locations. As with most games in the series, the three primary means of travel across the overworld are by foot, chocobo, and airship. With a few plot-driven exceptions, enemies are randomly encountered on field maps and on the overworld when traveling by foot. The menu screen is where the player makes such decisions as which characters will be in the traveling party, which equipment they wield, the magic they learn, and the configuration of the gameplay. It is also used to track experience points and levels.[2]

The game's plot develops as the player progresses through towns and dungeons. Town citizens will offer helpful information and some residents own item or equipment shops. Later in the game, visiting certain towns will activate side-quests. Dungeons appear as a variety of areas, including caves, sewers, forests, and buildings. These dungeons often have treasure chests containing rare items that are not available in most stores. Some dungeons feature puzzles and mazes, which require the player to divide the characters into multiple parties
</desc>
		<image>./images/Final Fantasy VI (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>April 2, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fire Emblem - Monshou no Nazo (J) (V1.1) [T+Eng005_Blaxor].smc</path>
		<name>Fire Emblem - Monshou no Nazo (J) (V1.1) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng005
Translated by Blaxor

Fire Emblem: Mystery of the Emblem is a Japanese tactical role-playing game developed by Intelligent Systems and published by Nintendo for the Super Famicom on January 21, 1994. It is the third installment in the Fire Emblem series and was released in Japan on January 21, 1994. It was the first Fire Emblem title for the Super Famicom and the first 24-megabit cartridge for the system. The game is divided into two distinct parts, or books. Book One is a remake of the original Fire Emblem: Ankoku Ryū to Hikari no Tsurugi, and Book Two is a continuation of events, following the same characters. 

Monshō no Nazo drops many of the gameplay elements introduced in Fire Emblem Gaiden, such as explorable towns and a navigable world map. However, it does carry over certain features; such as a battery RAM save feature and the use of icons for weapons along with their names. The game's most prominent new feature is the dismount command, which allows cavalier units to get off their horses and fight on foot. The limitation to this factor is that cavaliers can only wield lances when on horseback and swords while on foot. Furthermore, cavalier and airborne units are forced to dismount in chapters that take place in interior locations.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Fire Emblem - Monshou no Nazo (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>January 21, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fire Emblem - Mystery of the Emblem (J)[T+Eng 98% 0.98 RPGuy96].smc</path>
		<name>Fire Emblem - Mystery of the Emblem (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 98% 0.98 
Translated by RPGuy96

Fire Emblem: Mystery of the Emblem is a Japanese tactical role-playing game developed by Intelligent Systems and published by Nintendo for the Super Famicom on January 21, 1994. It is the third installment in the Fire Emblem series and was released in Japan on January 21, 1994. It was the first Fire Emblem title for the Super Famicom and the first 24-megabit cartridge for the system. The game is divided into two distinct parts, or books. Book One is a remake of the original Fire Emblem: Ankoku Ryū to Hikari no Tsurugi, and Book Two is a continuation of events, following the same characters. 

Monshō no Nazo drops many of the gameplay elements introduced in Fire Emblem Gaiden, such as explorable towns and a navigable world map. However, it does carry over certain features; such as a battery RAM save feature and the use of icons for weapons along with their names. The game's most prominent new feature is the dismount command, which allows cavalier units to get off their horses and fight on foot. The limitation to this factor is that cavaliers can only wield lances when on horseback and swords while on foot. Furthermore, cavalier and airborne units are forced to dismount in chapters that take place in interior locations.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Fire Emblem - Monshou no Nazo (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>January 21, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fire Emblem - Seisen no Keifu (J) [T+Eng.25_J2E].smc</path>
		<name>Fire Emblem - Seisen no Keifu (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.25_
Translated by J2E

Fire Emblem: Genealogy of the Holy War (ファイアーエムブレム聖戦の系譜 Faiā Emuburemu: Seisen no Keifu?) is a tactical role-playing game developed by Intelligent Systems and published by Nintendo for the Super Famicom in Japan. It is the fourth title in the Fire Emblem series, the second Fire Emblem title for the Super Famicom, and was the last game produced by Gunpei Yokoi. The game has received recognition from outside Japan through imports, fan translations and console emulation. It was released on the Japanese Virtual Console service in 2007 for the Wii and in 2013 for the Wii U.

Seisen no Keifu, like all Fire Emblem games, is a turn-based tactical role-playing game. The player controls a small army of units (characters) as they travel across the land, fighting enemies and liberating castles. For basic gameplay information, see the gameplay basics. There is no limit on how many player units can be deployed; this is balanced by the player receiving fewer controllable units than in other games in the series.

At the start of each chapter, the player holds a castle that must not be conquered by the enemy. In captured allied castles, units can shop, store items, repair damaged items, and fight in an arena. Each individual unit has its own money; the only units who can give money to others are thieves and units who are in love. No unit cannot trade weapons or items; The only way to "give" something to another unit is to sell the item at a pawn shop and have another unit buy it at twice the price sold. By visiting repair shops, money can be spent to restore a used weapon before it breaks. In the starting castle of each chapter, the player can promote units to a more powerful class when they reach a minimum level of 20. Rather than being reverted to level 1, the unit will remain at its current level after a promotion. To balance gameplay, there are only seven arena opponents to fight for each unit per chapter, as opposed to infinite opponents in other Fire Emblem games. The arena opponents are predetermined for each chapter and are always the same. To compensate the limited amount of enemies to fight in the arena, units cannot die when they have lost an arena battle; Instead, they remain alive at 1 hit point.

The majority of gameplay takes place on the battlefield. Seisen no Keifu is the first installment of the Fire Emblem series to implement the weapon triangle, a rock-paper-scissors-like system. In the weapon triangle, swords beat axes, axes beat lances, and lances beat swords. There is also a similar system for magic called the trinity of magic. In this system, fire beats wind, wind beats thunder and thunder beats fire. There are also Darkness and Light magic, which beat all three of those, and are neutral against each other. Higher character level and statistics can still overcome a weapon triangle disadvantage, however. Among the features of the battlefield are differing terrains, which give defensive bonuses, gates that block a portion of the map (which can only be opened by triggering a plot event), and villages (which can be attacked and destroyed by bandit enemies). Enemies can only destroy a portion of a village each turn; However, the more the player allows an enemy to tear down a village, the less gold will be rewarded for rescuing it. As opposed to other Fire Emblem games where capturing the enemy's castle ends the chapter, Seisen no Keifu features several enemy castles per chapter, all of which must be captured to proceed.

Seisen no Keifu is the first installment of the series to assign special skills to individual units. Units may also gain skills by belonging to a certain character class. Personal skills may be activated by command on the field, activated automatically under certain conditions, or activated by chance. If units in the first half of the game fall in love, they will pass on their individual skills to their children in the second half. A similar skill system is used in Fire Emblem: Thracia 776, Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance, Fire Emblem: Radiant Dawn, Fire Emblem Awakening and Fire Emblem Fates.

Seisen no Keifu introduces a romance-based game mechanic to the series. The units in the first half of the game can fall in love after accumulating a certain amount of "Lover points". Units will build Lover points automatically, but they will gain more if the player ends the turn with the units adjacent to one another, and certain pairs have unique conversations at set points in the game, which give a large amount of Lover points. If two units are paired, and the mother survives the first half, the two parents will pass their weapons and personal skills on to their children, who are the majority of playable units in the second half. Weapons will only be inherited if the child can use it in their first class, unless it is a Holy Weapon, which is always inherited. The parents also pass on their Holy Blood and their stat growths, giving the player some manner of control over their units' growth rates. If some of the female player units in the first half die or do not fall in love, substitute player units appear in their children's place. The children can also fall in love, though this does not produce a "third generation". Units in love in either generation may activate random critical hits when they stand next to their lover.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Seisen_no_Keifu.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>May 14, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fire Emblem - Thraki 776 (J) (V.ROM) [T+Eng.03_Luxifer].smc</path>
		<name>Fire Emblem - Thraki 776 (J) (V.ROM) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.03
Translated by Luxifer

Fire Emblem: Thracia 776 (ファイアーエムブレム　トラキア776 Faiā Emuburemu: Torakia Nana Nana Roku?) is a tactical role-playing game developed by Intelligent Systems and published by Nintendo, and the fifth main installment (6th overall) in the Fire Emblem series. It is the third and final Fire Emblem series title to be released on the Super Famicom.

A pre-written version of the game was originally released through the Nintendo Power service on August 28, 1999 as part of a special DX Pack. The game was later available through the Nintendo Power service as software that could be written on to an existing SF Memory Cassette on September 1, 1999. In May 21, 2000 the game was released as a standard Super Famicom game. On July 15, 2008, the game was released for Nintendo's Virtual Console for the Wii in Japan, followed by the version for Wii U Virtual Console almost five years later on July 10, 2013.

Fire Emblem: Thracia 776 takes place between Chapters 5 and 6 of the previous game, Fire Emblem: Seisen no Keifu. Several characters from Fire Emblem: Seisen no Keifu appear, such as Leif, Finn and Nanna. It takes place in the Thracian peninsula in southeastern Jugdral.

Fire Emblem: Thracia 776 uses the same skill system as Fire Emblem: Seisen no Keifu. It also introduced "fog of war" combat, also known as night combat, which obscured the majority of a map in pitch black. In fog of war chapters, torches or torch wands can be used to increase vision in around a certain spot, though it wears out gradually each turn. Like Fire Emblem: Monshou no Nazo, Fire Emblem: Thracia 776 has the "dismount" feature, including its similar characteristics, such as that Lance Knights and Axe Knights are forced to use swords when on foot and, that cavalry and airborne units are forced to dismount in interior missions.

This game is infamously known for introducing (and being the oldest game in the series to include) a fatigue system. Starting in chapter 8 of the game, whenever a unit participates in specific actions (such as attacking, unlocking chests/doors, or using staves) the fatigue meter is steadily increased. When the meter surpasses a character's max HP, they cannot participate in the next chapter, and must rest. This encourages the player to use their units sparingly, as well with using more characters. Thracia 776 also introduced the "Rescue" command, which allows a character of a higher build (renamed as "constitution" in later games) to pick up and carry another (provided they have a lower build). Once Rescued, that unit is safe from any damage (unless the carrier is killed) and the carrier's stats are cut in half. This mechanic allows players to save an important character they had unwittingly put in danger. The game also features the "Capture" command, by which playable characters can attempt to capture an enemy and seize their equipment. The reverse is also true, for enemy characters can also attempt to capture the player's units, and take their equipment.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Fe5box.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 1, 1999</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Flying Hero - Bugyuru no Daibouken (J)[T+Eng 100% V1 KingMike].smc</path>
		<name>Flying Hero - Bugyuru no Daibouken (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by KingMike

Flying Hero: Bugyuru no Daibouken ("Bugyuru's Great Adventure") is a vertically scrolling shoot 'em up with a bright, cartoony style, similar to games like Sega's Fantasy Zone or Konami's TwinBee series. The game features Bugyuru, a flying ball, whose girlfriend Pao gets kidnapped by a mysterious vampire named Biblio. Bugyuru takes off in close pursuit, flying across various worlds and taking down bizarre enemies like flying monkeys and giant rhino beetles.

The game was released exclusively in Japan for the Super Famicom and never officially localized, however a fan translation patch exists.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Flying Hero - Bugyuru no Daibouken (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 18, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Sting</developer>
		<publisher>SOFEL</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Front Mission (J) (V1.0) [T+Eng 100% 1.0b_FH].smc</path>
		<name>Front Mission (J) (V1.0) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0b
Translated by FH

Front Mission is a tactical role-playing game developed by G-Craft and published by Squaresoft, and was released in Japan on February 24, 1995 for the Super Famicom. Front Mission is the first main entry and the first entry overall in the Front Mission series. Front Mission is part of a serialized storyline that follows the stories of various characters and their struggles involving mecha known as wanzers. A direct port of the game was released for the WonderSwan Color in Japan on July 12, 2002.

Game progression in Front Mission proceeds in a linear manner: watch cut-scene events, complete missions, set up wanzers during intermissions, and sortie for the next mission. The player travels to locations on a point-and-click world map. As the player progresses through the plot, new locations are revealed on the world map. Towns and cities act as intermission points where the player can organize and setup their units for the upcoming mission. Battle zones are where the missions take place, though they become inaccessible upon the completion of a mission.

In Front Mission, players use playable units called wanzers, a term for mecha derived from the German word "Wanderpanzer", or "walking tank". Wanzers differ from the typical combat unit in that it has four modular parts: body, left arm, right arm, and legs. Each part has a specific function and its own health bar. The legs parts enable movement and evasion, the arm parts are necessary to use hand and shoulder weapons, and the body part maintains the wanzer's operability. In the event the body is destroyed, the wanzer is removed from play completely. Destruction of arm and leg parts does not remove the wanzer from play, but it severely cripples its performance. While the player fights mostly wanzers, vehicles, aircraft, and mobile weapons platforms are also featured. These enemy units generally have only one part, the body, and are much stronger than wanzers themselves.

In the customization aspect of Front Mission, wanzers can be customized with a variety of parts, computers, auxiliary backpacks, and weapons. The player has full control over customizing their wanzers and can do so as long as its total weight value does not exceed its given power output. To field a wanzer in battle, it must have a complete frame of parts: body, left arm, right arm, and legs. Parts with built-in weapons in the body or arm sections can also be equipped on a wanzer. Computers improve the accuracy of the weapons equipped on the wanzer. Auxiliary backpacks and weapons are not mandatory equipment to use wanzers, but are crucial in order to progress through the video games. Auxiliary backpacks serve to give a wanzer special features during combat; they allow a wanzer to carry support items such as ammunition reloads and increase the power output of the unit, allowing it to carry heavier gear.

In terms of weapons, there are four classes of weapons: melee weapons, short-range weapons, long-range weapons, and support fire weapons. Melee weapons are weapons used at melee range and have a tendency to strike the body part of its target. Tonfas and rods are examples of melee weapons. Short-range weapons are weapons used at close range and deal damage to all parts of a target. Machine guns and shotguns are examples of short-range weapons. Long-range weapons are weapons that have long firing ranges and are ideal for avoiding counterattacks. Bazookas are examples of long-range weapons. Support fire weapons are indirect fire weapons; they can never be counterattacked, but have limited ammunition supply and minimum firing ranges. Missile launchers are examples of support fire weapons. Lastly, shields can be equipped on wanzers to absorb some of the damage taken from incoming attacks.

Front Mission has other notable features incorporated into the game. Arena is a unique feature in which the player can fight AI-controlled enemy combatants, or face another player to earn monetary rewards. Likewise, Front Mission sports a briefing feature that details basic information about the composition of enemy forces for the upcoming mission. Missions in Front Mission are traditional tactical RPG fare, ranging from destroying all enemy targets or protecting a particular allied target.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Front Mission (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>February 24, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>G-Craft</developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Front Mission - Gun Hazard (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Front Mission - Gun Hazard (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Front Mission - Gun Hazard, is a mecha sidescroller, and spiritual successor to the Assault Suits series (of which you may recognize Assault Suits Valken/Cybernator and Assault Suits Leynos/Target Earth. Although there is a sequel to Leynos for Saturn (and I´ve heard that it´s very good), when it came time to make a Valken sequel they made a strategy game :( A remake of ASV is in the works for PS2, or so I hear!

Anyway, a bunch of the people who worked on Valken are credited to Gun Hazard´s staff as well. As such, it´s no surprise that the games play so similarly. Gun Hazard has, to its credit, a much longer, deeper, and more developed story than Valken. It sports nearly a full hundred battle maps, ally units to take into battle, RPG-style experience and levels, and lots of equipment with which to customize your wanzer, although not nearly so much as in a mainstream Front Mission. This, in my view, is a plus -- the ridiculous customizability of your wanzers in the normal FM series has you constantly going back to stores to see if anything new pops up, and when it does, you spend half an hour outfitting your machines with the stuff. It often seemed that you spent more time in intermissions than you did actually playing the game, and Gun Hazard solves that problem nicely.

Do keep in mind that Gun Hazard is not a mainstream Front Mission title -- its story does not fit with the main FM universe´s timeline. Also keep in mind that it is not Front Mission 2. FM2 was released for the Playstation in 1997. That doesn´t mean that Gun Hazard´s not an enjoyable game, as it certainly is. This patch is complete, and is the result of four years of hard work by four dedicated people. We hope you enjoy it!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Front Mission - Gun Hazard (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>February 23, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Funaki Masakatsu Hybrid Wrestler - Tougi Denshou (J)[T+Eng 100% Phil].smc</path>
		<name>Funaki Masakatsu Hybrid Wrestler - Tougi Denshou (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Phil

Released during a surge of Wrestler tie-in games throughout the
90's, Hybrid Wrestler was a very ambitious Wrestling title that
combined elements of Pro Wrestling, the 2D Fighting genre and a
truly impressive Create a Wrestler/Career mode that was the most
advanced of it's kind at the time in 1994.

Needless to say, Whether you choose to play through the standard 
versus modes, or strive to become Heavyweight Champion in the
Career mode, there is a lot of fun to be found in Hybrid Wrestler. 

It's cartoonish appeal, over the top action and cast of easily 
Recognizable faces makes Hybrid Wrestler a title worth picking
up for the hardcore Wrestling fanatic. It's just a shame that
this title was only released in Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./images/306985_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>October 21, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Technos Japan</publisher>
		<genre>Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ganpuru - Gunman's Proof (J) [T+Eng1.03_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Ganpuru - Gunman's Proof (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.03
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

This game is interesting. At first glance, it looks like a Zelda clone. Then you notice that you´ve got a score. And lives. What you end up with is an adventure title with substantially more action elements and less RPG elements than Zelda had, but it´s still quite a good game in its own right. Just don´t go into it expecting to play a Zelda game :) It´s definately worth your time, though!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Ganpuru - Gunman's Proof (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>January 27, 1997</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>Action/RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling (J) [T+EngR2_Sydra].smc</path>
		<name>Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling (J) </name>
		<desc>T+EngR2
Translated by Sydra
In 1995, Bullet Proof Software entered the realm of Wrestling Video games with it's eye set on making the best Wrestling game possible.

That game was Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling. Released only in Japan back in 1995, Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling featured a staggering,  encyclopedic 129 Wrestler roster, plenty of modes to choose from and a insanely customizable array of options to set up match types that was unseen in any other Wrestling game at the time.

The Wrestlers featured in Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling span across a multitude of different Wrestling promotions With a diverse cast of recognizable faces all disguised under different aliases including Wrestling Legends,  Mixed Martial Artists, Shoot Fighters, Puroresu Megastars, and even Mexican Luchadors not featured in any Fire Pro game (up to 1995, at least).

Yet, Gekitou's greatest features were marred by one simply unavoidable conflict which prevented the game from attaining critical acclaim and a respectable series of future installments. Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling looked and felt much too similar to the Fire Pro Wrestling series. 

Everything from Gekitou's gameplay, modes and even the graphical style of the Wrestlers themselves bared a striking resemblance to the Fire Pro Wrestling series (especially, Super Fire Pro Wrestling Special which was released one year prior to Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling...in 1994). 

But, even with this very glaring incovenience, Burning Pro Wrestling is still an interesting and worthwhile experience for the hardcore  wrestling fanatic looking for an alternate take on the Fire Pro Wrestling series. Afterall, Immitation is the sincerest form of flattery.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Gekitou Burning Pro Wrestling Box Art.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>06 October 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Ukiyotei</developer>
		<publisher>Bullet Proof Software</publisher>
		<genre>Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Glory Of Heracles III - Silence of The Gods (J)[T+Eng 100% 1.0a DQ Trans].smc</path>
		<name>Glory Of Heracles III - Silence of The Gods (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0a 
Translated by DQ Translations

Heracles no Eikō III: Kamigami no Chinmoku ("Glory of Heracles III: Silence of the Gods") is the third installment of the series.

The game's plot and setting are loosely based around various episodes included in Greek mythology. The hero begins the game in a state of total memory-loss, but discovers that he has somehow acquired a mysterious power that shields him from all bodily harm, essentially making him immortal. The only clue the hero has in discovering his own identity is a mysterious dream that he sees every night, and he begins his journey in search of the location shown in the dream.

The gameplay borrows various motifs from ancient mythology, particularly the concept of immortality. An immortal character can execute certain actions that other characters cannot, like jumping off high cliffs without being injured. The game's writer, Kazushige Nojima, composed a storyline where the hero encounters the Greek gods while trying to discover his own true identity. Like the game's predecessor, Heracles no Eikō II: Titan no Metsubō, the game focuses on its rich storyline rather than the game system, which does not differ significantly from other role-playing video games of the period.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Z0089009.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>April 24, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>Data East</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Go Go Ackman (J) [T+Eng1.00_Ackman].smc</path>
		<name>Go Go Ackman (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Ackman


Next to shooters platformers are some of the easiest games to import as any semblance of a story is merely window dressing to get you into the game. With platformers being the de facto genre of choice during the early 90s it’s hard to believe a few slipped through the cracks. The Go Go Ackman series range from really good to excellent and I’m sure if the manga had been localized these games would have come over too. That doesn’t matter however as the games are easily enjoyable with no Japanese knowledge and the first is a perfect introduction.

Anyone familiar with Dragon Ball will recognize the similarity to Trunks. Remove his nose and give him elf ears and you have a new character. Their personalities are pretty close too as both characters are mischievous except Ackman takes it a step further by actually killing people for their souls. That plot point forms the basis for the game’s story. The angel Tenshi has hatched another plot to kill his rival Ackman and enlists the aid of a higher angel to stop him once and for all. The interplay between Ackman and Tenshi is a bit looney tunes and despite the dark undertone the adventure is still pretty comical. It’s pretty hilarious to see Tenshi try his hardest and fail all the while Ackman is either oblivious or too stupid to notice. That tone helps an already pretty good game stand out.

It’s actually pretty surprising how much mileage Banpresto got out of Go Go Ackman. There are three Super Famicom games loosely based on what is essentially a one volume manga. That isn’t a slight against them and more of a testament to how good the premise for the series is. Collecting souls for the devil is some pretty dark stuff but here it is played for laughs. That cheeky tone is kept in this first video game adaptation as it sticks closer to the manga. While it’s understandable why it wasn’t released worldwide it doesn’t matter as no Japanese is required to enjoy this solid platformer.

Ackman is a pretty nimble protagonist and relies on fisticuffs to get through tight situations. Aside from punches and kicks he can wind up a punch and throw a mean sonic boom. Even the staple butt bounce makes an appearance except here it dazes enemies, allowing you to kick them into others. What’s funny to me about all this is that he has a sword strapped to his back but can’t use it or any other weapons until collecting an item. Part of that would be just how overpowered they are. Most enemies die in a single hit but the reach the boomerang, sword, and gun give will allow you to breeze through the game. I can understand limiting it in that regard but it still feels pretty cheap.

The game has all the trappings of your typical platformer such as collecting 100 coins for extra lives except here you have a little demon helper that will pick them up for you. The level design is great all around with a great deal of variety throughout. There are frequent forced scrolling segments that are actually fun as most hazards are telegraphed well in advance. Boss battles are frequent and unique if a bit simple. Their goofy designs make up for it however as this skews closer to the Dr. Slump side of Toriyama rather than Dragon Ball.

Overall the game is not too challenging and is a bit too easy. Despite beginning with a small life bar you’ll find hearts all around and will rarely be close to death. The bosses have easily recognizable patterns and if you manage to hold onto a weapon when you reach them the encounter is trivial. There is a slight ramp up toward the end but nothing too notable. The game is of medium length but the alternate paths do provide some impetus for playing through it twice at least.


Go Go Ackman is a great looking game, fitting as it was released in late 1994. Akira Toriyama’s distinctive art style easily translates to video games and is replicated here in the sprite design. The game’s colorful cast of characters are pulled from everywhere; since the game doesn’t take place in any set period they can throw in everything. There are demons, robots, hitmen, and the undead and yet it all makes sense. The backgrounds are especially pretty with up to 3 or 4 layers of scrolling giving them some depth. The music is good but not noteworthy; there were only one or two songs that caught my attention but I’d rather that than generic rock that tries too hard.

For its first video game outing Go Go Ackman is solidly entertaining. It hits all the right beats and provides a decent challenge for any level of platforming fan. The story is completely inconsequential so you shouldn’t fear importing. For those that want to experience the game in whole there is an English translation patch. Either way this is one of the better import only platformers for the system and it only got better as the series progressed.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Go Go Ackman (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 23, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gourmet Sentai - Bara Yarou (J) [T+Eng.80_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Gourmet Sentai - Bara Yarou (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.80
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

The WaKKiEsT beat ´em up of all time :) From a cooking minigame to enemies that nasally exhale sharply at you to little midget guys that bounce on your head... it´s great :) Quite a bit of it (the character bios, and enemy bios end up unlocked when you beat the game) is compressed unfortunately and will probably never get done. The story as well remains undone, but all of the important bits ARE done. mmmk.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Gourmet Sentai Barayarou (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hiouden Legend of the Scarlet King - The Demonic Oath (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Hiouden Legend of the Scarlet King - The Demonic Oath (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Hiouden is a nifty strategy game by Wolfteam -- a company composed largely of the folks who were later responsible for Tales of Phantasia, Star Ocean, and Valkyrie Profile, including famed musical composer Motoi Sakuraba. I think there are multiple endings, but I can´t be sure -- regardless, the story´s awesome, it really is. It´s done, have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Hiouden - Mamono-tachi to no Chikai (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>February 11, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Wolfteam</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Holy Umbrella - Dondera Wild (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Holy Umbrella - Dondera Wild (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Holy Umbrella - Dondera´s Wild!! is a really nifty platformer game along the lines of Violinist of Hameln. It´s just as silly, although in different ways :D The main character gets transported to an alternate world when he picks up an umbrella, and he has to save it to get home. The game is full of all sorts of cliche plot elements. It's a total camp overload, but it's a still a lot of fun. Script's been fully translated by the intrepid Hexafire, and has been edited by yours truly. It should be a lot of fun! So enjoy.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Holy Umbrella - Dondera no Mubou!! (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Natax Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jelly Boy 2 (Beta)[T+Eng 100% Kingmike].smc</path>
		<name>Jelly Boy 2 (Beta)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by KingMike

Marine and his friends went out for a day of fun at the Jelly Land Amusment Park. It was a fun day, lots of laughs. It was a real riot until a mysterious jester showed up. The Jester changed Marine and his friends into puddles of slime. Now Marine must find his way through the Jelly Land Amusment Park to find his friends, so they can battle the Jester and break his curse.

Along the way, you’ll travel through eight worlds. The player has some choice in the order to play the levels through. As you play, you’ll rescue Marine’s friends. Each of them has a special talent, which will enable you to find your way through various puzzles, in order to find all the secrets. Most of the levels are pretty easy, but the bosses will present a decent challenge trying to defeat.

This game is the unreleased sequel to the platformer game Jerry Boy.
</desc>
		<image>./images/maxresdefault.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>NA</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jerry Boy (J) [T+Eng101%_ChrisCovell].smc</path>
		<name>Jerry Boy (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng101%
Translated by ChrisCovell

This is an English translation of a fun little platform game for the SNES/SFC, called Jerry Boy. It came out in America as "Smartball"; however, the US version had had several scenes taken out of the game. The Japanese version of Jerry Boy had an introductory sequence which established the story. In addition, there are towns throughout the game that you can visit, including a desert town, angel village, ice town, and forest cabin. You go through these towns and talk to people, who carry the storyline along. There's even one scene where you can get swallowed by a huge whale and talk to the folks trapped inside. All this was taken out of the American version. X-( 
</desc>
		<image>./images/jerryboycovera.jpg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer>Game Freak</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./JoJo's Bizarre Adventure (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>JoJo's Bizarre Adventure (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

It´s an RPG based on the third JoJo´s Bizarre Adventure manga series, Stardust Crusaders. All done! Short game, too. Fans of the source property will get the most enjoyment out of it.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Snes_jojo.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 5, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Winkysoft</developer>
		<publisher>Cobra Team</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jutei Senki (J) [T+Eng1.00 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Jutei Senki (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Alright, I removed the RPG moniker from the genre because this really doesn´t have any RPG to it so to speak. It´s got an opening, an ending, still-frame pictures after each of the 20 main campaign missions, and 16 generic types units on each side of the war that level up when they get 10 kills. No real character development at all, because there really aren´t any characters at all, just the generic unit types. That said though, it´s a pretty neat game. And either I suck at it or it´s really damn hard. Once you finish the main campaign, you can go through 20 Expert mode missions, and once you´ve beaten those, you unlock 20 -MORE- Expert Mode missions. Of course, Expert 21-40 are just more-difficult rehashes of Expert 1-20, but if you´re really masochistic you should at least give them a try :)

Regardless, this patch is 100% complete. Apologies that it took so damn long for something without very much for text, but it had some really weird crap in it, and I wouldn´t have been able to hack those parts of the bugger until about this time last year at very earliest anyway. Have fun, and stuff.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Jutei Senki (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 27, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kidou Butouden G-Gundam (J) [T+Eng1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Kidou Butouden G-Gundam (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Kidō Butoden G-Gundam was the first console Gundam fighting game and that makes perfect sense because in essence, the entire G Gundam franchise was designed around the "world warrior" themed fighting games that were running rampant during the early 90s. The show was the first of the many "alternate universes" that were spawned after the conclusion of the Universal Century franchises, and was heavily scrutinized for its often boring, battle-themed plot, almost Pok?mon-esque emphasis on techniques and its over-the-top, highly stereotypical and sometimes downright offensive character designs (i.e. Gundam Mexico is known as the "Tequila Gundam", wears a poncho and a sombrero, Gundam Maxter is an assemblage of American sports and western archetypes, etc.). If you don't take the show too seriously, it's pretty funny, but it'd be a lot funnier if the show didn't only stereotype other countries besides Japan. Where's the Businessman Gundam who fights with a briefcase and tries to steal the other Gundams' panties, or the Schoolgirl Gundam that constantly giggles and eventually gets assaulted by Tentacle Gundam?

Ah well. That said, G-Gundam is exactly what you'd expect from your average fighting game of the mid-90s. Nothing special, just another cash in on the Street Fighter phenomenon. The game is played out in tournament style, with varying numbers of characters to choose from depending on which mode you select. Story mode only allows you to play as the star Gundams from the show:
</desc>
		<image>./images/ggundam.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 27, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Pandora Box</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kidou Senshi V Gundam (J)[T+Eng 100% Twilight Translations].smc</path>
		<name>Kidou Senshi V Gundam (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Twilight Translations

V-Gundam consists of 13 different missions. In each mission, you will
battle various mobile suits and Gundams, all of which must be destroyed to
complete the mission. Sounds simple, right? Well, it isn't so easy.
      You see, your enemies don't like being killed, and thus will try to kill
you before you can kill them, and since I'm pretty sure you don't like getting
killed either, you'll just have to kill them faster. To do this, you'll need
weapons, which come pre-equipped, no extra charge.
      Missions take place either while flying or while grounded. Maneuvering
while on the ground is a bit more challenging, but you can crouch under an
enemy's shots, and if you smash into an enemy, they'll be knocked on their duff
and will be stunned for a few moments (hit them now!). However, the majority of
missions take place while flying. You have greater speed and manueverability
while flying, though you can't crouch. If you die during a mission, you will
return right away; you will not abort the mission. After dying, your energy and
ammo will refill. However, when your lives run out, you will get a game over.
And you only have four lives . . .
      Your usual weaponary consists of your beam saber, your beam rifle, your
beam shield, and, of course, your vulcans. You can fire vulcans at any time by
pressing B, and you can use your beam shield at any time by pressing L. To use
your beam saber and beam rifle, however, you have to equip them. Press R to
equip either one; press Y to use the weapon you equipped. If you're done with
one, press R to un-equip it and choose the other. However, this changes during
certain missions where you must use a certain attachment. With this attachment
active, you can no longer use your beam shield, your saber has been replaced by
the M.B. Rifle, and your vulcans have been replaced with a much, much stronger
blast that would make you invincible if it could fire faster. Also, late in the
game, your armor will be upgraded causing you to take half the usual amount of
damage. You can also hold A to dash in any direction, or,
if you're on solid ground, you can fly for a VERY *short* amount of time. Note
that dashing into an enemy (after you've picked up some speed) will damage them
and knock them back. Still, you will find yourself sluggish, at best. You may
want to practice with the controls a bit, it can get confusing. If you don't
like the default settings, you can change the them in the Config menu.
</desc>
		<image>./images/26734_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 11, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./King Of Demons (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>King Of Demons (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Interesting little platformer here, with an extremely dark storyline and an equally dark setting. Play as Abel as he journeys through hell (literally) to save his daughter from the King of Demons and quite possibly loses his humanity in the process! It´s a fairly generic sidescroller with a few twists, a lot of blood, and some pretty damn cool moments, but I really can´t say anything more without taking away from the experience. Play!
</desc>
		<image>./images/kingofdemons.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>August 25 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>KSS</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kouryuu no Mimi (J) [T+Eng 100% V1 RPGONE].smc</path>
		<name>Kouryuu no Mimi (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by RPG One

Kōryū no Mimi lit. "Ear of the Golden Dragon" is a side-scrolling beat-'em-up video game originally released by VAP exclusively in Japan. This video game is based on the anime/manga of the same title.

The storyline is involving, with lots of different allies and villains running around. There are a wide variety of moves and combos that the player can pull off, and he can also get plenty of weapons to wield, and passive-looking objects to throw around. If the player can fill up his meter to wield the power of his Ring of the Golden Dragon’s Ear, he can heal some of his damage and also briefly harness the power of the Dragon. This allows him to become faster and more powerful.

Natsume Kiroemon, the 45th leader of the Natsume family, is due to inherit the Kōryū no Mimi, a tool which gives its bearer easy access to wealth and women. As a result of his father's death, he left the Italian monastery where he'd been training and rightfully took the name "Natsume Kiroemon" as well as the power of the Kōryū no Mimi. Upon his return to Japan, Natsume fell fatally in love with Kanako, one of the members of the rival Mina family. However, the evil hand of the Mina family attacked Natsume constantly and abducted Kanako. Now Natsume has unlocked the seal, making the Kōryū's power surge, and he's striking back at the Mina family. Both Koryu and Kanako's fate are in the player's hands.

Instead of limiting all the player's attack with a weapon, he has the option of attacking normally then firing with a separate button. Much like The Ninja Warriors or Kung Fu, each stage takes place on a single movement level. While the player is not allowed to fight the same amount of enemies all at once, he is often kept pretty busy. To make things harder, the player only get a single life before being sent to the continue/game over screen. There is part-time from a computer controlled partner in the airplane (third level) but there is no way to get a full-time partner for the rest of the stages.

Players will also find gaming similarities to Final Fight and River City Ransom throughout the game.

</desc>
		<image>./images/s-l300.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 22, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>VAP</developer>
		<publisher>VAP</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kunio-kun no Dodge Ball - Zenin Shuugou! (J) [T+Eng 100% V1 azel].smc</path>
		<name>Kunio-kun no Dodge Ball - Zenin Shuugou! (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1 
Translated by azel

Dodgeball, the epitome of classroom sports, is magnificently portrayed in this wonderful game.

Or not.

Kunio Kun’s Dodgeball is a sequel to the original NES and Arcade versions of Super Dodge Ball, and a prequel to Super Dodge Ball on the SNK Neo-Geo arcade system; and while those three versions were straight-to-the-point dodgeball games, this version is a bit more simulator-ish. Here, you have to either create a team using Kunio and his classmates [Riki and Todd Thornley from Crash N' The Boys, to name a few], before taking on the world. The good news: The graphics are really good. The bad news: The controls are absolutely horrid.

The game is very straightforward, but at the same time it is impossible to play without a menu translation. I spent a long time trying to figure out how to get to a match without being able to, and quit in frustration (one of the patches hosted here fixed that though). You have to build your team before taking on the world, and depending on your performance you can buy upgrades and special moves for your team. The game saves everything to a battery backup so you don’t have to write 64-character passwords. And that is it for the simulation part of the game.

Once you get to the court, the game goes downhill fast. The game skips frames a lot, it’s hard for you to get your character to run, the special moves are a pain to pull off, and you can’t change the character you use quickly enough. And to top things off, you have to press Y+B at the same time to jump. What the hell? The system had six buttons! A and X aren’t even used at all, why didn’t they map jump and special moves to them?

While the graphics are good, sometimes the stages get in the way. For example, the Japan stage doesn’t have a solid floor, but a semi-transparent net. It makes it hard to see your characters at times. Other stages, like the US, don’t suffer from this problem. The music and sound effects serve their purpose. They’re good but won’t win any awards.

You’ll take a lot of time to get used to the control… if you aren’t disgusted with the game already. Technos has done much better in the past. Good thing they didn’t make many sports games…
</desc>
		<image>./images/Kunio-kun no Dodge Ball Da yo Zenin Shuugou! (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 6, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Technos</publisher>
		<genre>Dodgeball</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kuusou Kagaku Sekai Gulliver Boy (J) [T+Eng.99_Stealth].smc</path>
		<name>Kuusou Kagaku Sekai Gulliver Boy (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.99
Translated by Stealth

Okay, where to begin… Well, in Gulliver Boy, you play as Gulliver. He gets this really nifty energy-wave-hadouken thing which is his main attack, and you eventually get spiffy Minder attacks which are basically like spells and stuff. And you also get this Edison guy who really has very limited use ‘cuz he only gets one or two bombs (at first) and he takes forever to make more. The game is also rather short (I completed it in about six hours, I think.)

The story in short: Spain is trying to take over Europe, and Judo, prince of Spain or something, killed Gulliver’s father. Now Gulliver’s pissed off and wants revenge. Who wouldn’t? And so you set off to kick ass with nothing but Edison’s bombs, Gulliver’s hadouken thing, and Gulliver’s gigantic hair. Misty eventually joins you, but ends up being dead weight at first :P Oh, and in the second part of the game, you get this badass mech thing for all of two or three boss battles.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Kuusou Kagaku Sekai Gulliver Boy (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 28, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lennus II - Paladins Quest 2 (J)[T+Eng 100% V1.04 Magic Destiny].smc</path>
		<name>Lennus II - Paladins Quest 2 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.04 
Translated by Magic Destiny

This video game is the sequel to Lennus; unlike Lennus, which Enix brought to North America under the title of Paladin's Quest, Lennus II was released only in Japan as Enix had dropped support for the SNES in North America by this time.

Lennus II was released on July 26, 1996, nearly four years after its predecessor, and a full month after the Nintendo 64; accordingly, it featured much-improved graphics and sound. The plot centers around a hero, Falus, who must find four orbs to avert apocalypse. Falus is the only character central to the player's party; other members are recruited and may be dismissed if a superior replacement is found. The music was critically acclaimed, and two of its tracks were recorded by the Tokyo Philharmonic Orchestra for release on the Orchestral Game Concert compilations
</desc>
		<image>./images/Lennus II - Fuuin no Shito (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 26, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Copya System</developer>
		<publisher>	Kōhei Tanaka</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Little Magic (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00b_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Little Magic (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00b
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Little Magic is a cute little puzzle game along the lines of The Adventures of Lolo! It stars May, a magic school student whose grades aren´t perfect and who places more value in friends and fun than studying, kind of like a certain romhacker who´ll remain nameless ;) Anyway, May is taking her final exam which revolves around lots of funky block puzzles, and once you solve them all... well, I´m not gonna give that away. It´s complete, have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Little Magic (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 24, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Altron</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Little Master - Nijiiro no Maseki (J) [T+Eng.5b_SStrans].smc</path>
		<name>Little Master - Nijiiro no Maseki (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.5b
Translated by SStrans

Each of the Little Master games is a tactical role-playing. Players control a party of characters that can be moved around a grid during battle. Battles are fought in turns, meaning that the character with the highest speed will be able to move and attack first, then the character with the next highest speed will be able to move. Characters can use physical attacks when standing next to an enemy on the battle map or they can use magic or bows to attack enemies from a distance. During battle, the player may have to solve a puzzle to complete the stage.

When a character attacks another character, the battle field disappears and only the two characters currently in combat are shown. After the attack animations, experience points are awarded to the player's character that participated in the fight. If a character is adjacent to the character he or she is targeting, the attacked character will counter with his or her own attack.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Little Master - Nijiiro no Maseki (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 30, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Live A Live (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00b_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Live A Live (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00b
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Live A Live is truly unique when it comes to RPGs. Rather than have one long continuous storyline, LAL throws a whole bunch of rather sort (but good) stories at you. Each chapter is set in a different time period, and each has unique gameplay aspects (read peoples´ minds in the Near Future chapter, sniff out monsters in the Prehistoric chapter, learn your enemies´ moves in the Present Day chapter, etc.) In the end, they´re all tied together. The story is fairly generic, but it´s told very well, and a couple of the chapters throw you some real curve-balls. Suffice to say, the game is really worth your time. Just don´t spoil it for yourself with a walkthrough!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Live A Live (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 2, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lodoss Tou Senki - Record of Lodoss War (J) [T+Eng.90_LNFT].smc</path>
		<name>Lodoss Tou Senki - Record of Lodoss War (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.90
Translated by LNFT

Record of Lodoss War, in short, is a traditional JRPG released for the Super Famicom in 1995. The game is comprised of four scenarios, each telling different pieces of the vast story of the Accursed Island. The other thing that sets it apart is that battles take place in an isometric SRPG style, where you move parties members around a 3x3 battlefield. The game is rather short, as the first three scenarios can each be completed in roughly 3 hours each, with the fourth scenario clocking in around 12 hours. For a licensed game, it follows the excellent writing behind the saga very well, and is a very enjoyable experience for fans of the anime/manga. That being said, Record of Lodoss War is not without its flaws. 
</desc>
		<image>./images/Lodoss-tou Senki (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 22, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Thinking Rabbit / Kadokawa</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchienji (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchienji (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Arle Nadja is 5 years old and is attending kindergarten, and it´s final exam time. But in order to take her final exam, she needs to locate a Final Exam Certificate... In the meantime, a letter arrives which speaks of eight magical gems. Find all eight and take them to the Wizard´s Mountain, and you will be granted one wish. Arle decides to search for the gems and wish for her final exam certificate, and along the way she´ll have to fight off a gang of local bullies and other various characters you may recognize from the Puyo Puyo series of games!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchienji (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 1, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Compile</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Magic Knight Rayearth (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_RPGe].smc</path>
		<name>Magic Knight Rayearth (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by RPGe

I played this a little when the translation first came out. Now that I have to play it again for this review, I remember why I stopped.

If you people know anything, you’ll know that Magic Knight Rayearth is a popular manga/anime series in Japan, and also here, sort of. Most people say it’s a bad game, because they all say it’s “too easy” or “too short.” This is, of course, all coming from people who have never seen the MKR anime or manga. The game follows the manga’s plot pretty much from beginning to end (I assume), so seeing the anime/manga isn’t exactly a prerequisite. But if you haven’t, then it’ll just be some short easy RPG for you. The reason I don’t like it is that the battles are painfully slow. It just gets annoying after a while, OK?

For those who are wondering, “Hey, is this anything like the Saturn version of Rayearth?” the answer is, “No, not in the slightest.” The Saturn version r0x though.
</desc>
		<image>./images/MagicKnightRayearth.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>29 September 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Pandora Box</developer>
		<publisher>TOMY</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Magical Drop (J) [T+Eng 100% .95b_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Magical Drop (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% .95b
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Magical Drop is a nifty puzzle game in the same vein as the Puyo Puyo games, just backwards. You´ll see ^_^ This game is packed with secrets, although once you figure out how to get one of ´em you´ve pretty much figured out how to get all of them. It´s pretty much complete, only one or two issues, so have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Magical_Drop_Flyer_SFC_01.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>October 20, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Data East</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Magical Pop'n (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Magical Pop'n (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

This game´s neat. It´s about this little insane hyper princess whose kingdom is being invaded by some nasty evil demon army. In the meantime, she´s (supposed to be) learning about magic and this crystal of wondrous powers from her tutor (but she´s sleeping instead) and that night, when the army invades, she naturally goes bonkers on ´em all. Fun platform-hopping action ensues! The six levels in Magical Pop´n are HUGE, and it´s a fairly difficult game too. In each area except the last you´ll find a new spell which you´ll need to complete the level. Some of them are rather one-use things, such as the flamethrower spell, but a few of them are quite helpful.

Well, everything (the opening and ending) has been translated. Note that the opening cinema occurs if you let the game sit at the title screen and that the ending won´t be nearly as cool if you haven´t seen the opening! With that in mind, have fun!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Magical Pop'n (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 10, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Pack-In-Video</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Magna Braban - The Wandering Hero (J)[T+Eng 100% Kingmike].smc</path>
		<name>Magna Braban - The Wandering Hero (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by KingMike

In "Magna Braban", you play the role of a young boy named Alex, who lives with his parents in Kurme Village in the kingdom of Anatea. One day, Alex is attacked by two monsters in the forest, and as a result, he decides to become stronger and take part in the Arena tournament. But the Arena is attacked and burnt down by the minions of the Demon King, who lives far away in a secluded tower. The king of Anatea chooses Alex and two famous warriors, the magician Gina and the viking Getz, to go on an epic journey and defeat the evil Demon King. 

Gameplay 
The game is a console-style RPG with party-based combat and random enemy encounters. The battles are viewed from an isometric perspective and are set in auto-mode. The characters will simply attack each other until you pause the battle and assign to them a different strategy. You can use melee and long-ranged attacks as well as magical spells. 
</desc>
		<image>./images/Magna Braban - Henreki no Yuusha (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>November 18, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>ASK</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Majuu Ou (J) [T+Eng1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Majuu Ou (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Majyuuou, or "King of Demons" is a pretty standard action game released by KSS for the Super Famicom in 1995. It involves a young man named Abel, who is betrayed by his friend Bayer. This Bayer guy had sacrificed Abel's family in order to revive Lucifer and become a demon - a pleasant fellow all around. During the prologue, Abel is granted power from his deceased wife in order to defeat Bayer, and go into hell to save his daughter.

The action of Majyuuou is most often as described as "Castlevania with a gun", and at least in the early stages, that's true. The opening melody of the intro stage sounds a bit like a classic Castlevania theme, and your character - a fairly generic muscular dude with a red bandanna, jeans and a white t-shirt - walks and controls like any number of the Belmont clan, although can double jump, execute jump kicks, and slightly change direction mid-air a la Dracula X. You start off with a gun, which has both unlimited range and unlimited ammo - it does not shoot any projectiles, so whatever you're aiming at will take damage when you pull the trigger. You can also hold down the button for a super Hadoken-esque blast.

At the end of each level, the boss leaves a jewel, which cycles amongst three different colors. The color you choose will determine the type of demon you play in the next stage. This aspect is a bit like the Sega classic Altered Beast - the title Majyuuou is even similar to that game's Japanese name, Jyuuouki.

The red jewel will transform you into a harpy, which attacks with wide range boomerangs. The green jewel will turn you into a lizard creature which can shoot thin laser beams out of its arms. The blue jewel will turn you into a dragon, which has a powerful breath attack. Like the human character, each demon has their own special move, activated by charging the attack button. It may seem straightforward, but there are some neat catches to this system too. If you choose the same demon three times in a row, you morph into a super powered up version. Alternatively, if you choose a new demon each level, and control each of them at least once, then you'll obtain the ultimate form at the end of the game.

Compared to Castlevania, Majyuuou is a bit on the easy side. However, you can make it harder by electing to stay in human form. Since the human's gun can only fire straight forward, it can be tough to hit enemies in the air, while demons can hit targets much easier. Since it's more difficult, it would've been nice if there were a third ending for those who elected to take on this challenge, but that's a wasted opportunity on the game's part.

The demon transformations are cool, but the grim overtones help make Majyuuou stand out from the crowd When you are granted power from your wife at the beginning, a fairy flies around with you and protects you from enemies, lunging forward at enemies every time you attack. If you die, the fairy - or rather your wife - sacrifices herself in order to revive you. This gives one a sense of urgency to save your daughter even more so since the powerup that gives you the fairy is very rare. It's also a bit creepy that you're given the choice to sell your humanity in order to increase your power, or elect to keep your human soul? It seems like a no win situation, especially since you have to turn into a demon in order to get the best ending.

The sprites in Majyuuou are pretty small, especially for a late Super Famicom game, but at least they're well animated. However, the graphic designers compensated for this with some completely outstanding background design. Many areas in this game exude a tremendous amount of atmosphere, and the levels are quite to toss you into creepy - and memorable - set pieces. In the first stage, you're chased by a gigantic multi-eyed worm, complete with extendable teeth, before running into a dead end. Just as it seems like it's all over, the floor crashes, and you fight throw the sewers. Amongst the zombies - which fall apart piece by piece as you fill their body with lead - there are faint figures in the background of tortured souls. You climb back up and face the worm again, only to be tossed into a elevator, complete with a man-eating spider.

The second stage is a ruined city, completely desolate except for some monsters and man eating plants. - some of the flowers even have creepy faces on them. This boss of this stage is a gigantic bloodshot eyeball - which rotates courtesy of the usual Mode 7 fanciness - and fires lasers from its pupil. Later on, you board a train made of bones, against the background of a blood red sunset,with all of the skull cars traveling at suicidal speed. There's even a scene of a girl in chains being flailed by evil horsemen, whom you are utter incapable of saving. In Japan, Konami dubs the Castlevania series as part of the "horror action" genre, but they're actually pretty clean compared to this. Altogether, the whole experience is visceral and bloody and mildly disturbing, especially for a Super Famicom game, a system that was generally pigeonholed as being more family oriented than its competitors.

The music was composed by Tomohiro Endo (Ys IV) and Hiroshi Iizuka (Langrisser III). While the music in isn't spectacular, some tracks are pretty catchy. This is especially true of the prologue and fire stages. It doesn't always fit the action. The only tracks that lend to the atmosphere are the train and final stage tracks, which elicits a sense urgency compared to the fire stage, which just seems too blissful.

Majyuuou is a bit on the easy side - disappointing, considering how it could've potentially been a good companion game to the Castlevania series - but the designers' portrait of hell is fascinating, especially for a 16-bit title, and it's a pretty fun game too boot. It has also been completely translated by Aeon Genesis, even though it is still totally playable in Japanese without a translation.


</desc>
		<image>./images/Majuu Ou (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 25, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>KSS</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./MegaMan &amp; Bass (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>MegaMan &amp; Bass (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Mega Man &amp; Bass, known in Japan as Rockman &amp; Forte, is a video game developed and published by Capcom. It is a spin-off title in the original Mega Man series and was originally released exclusively in Japan on April 24, 1998 for the Super Famicom. Mega Man &amp; Bass was ported to the Game Boy Advance (GBA) handheld in 2002 and was localized in North America and PAL regions the following year.

After defeating the evil Dr. Wily many times, the robotic hero Mega Man is called into action once again when a powerful being known as King steals the blueprints to the creations of Dr. Wily and Dr. Light in order to create an army for robotic dominance over humans. Having learned of the threat, Mega Man's rival Bass decides to take matters into his own hands. The game is an action-platformer where the player advances by defeating bosses and acquiring their signature weapons. Mega Man &amp; Bass lets the player choose between either of its titular characters, each of which plays differently from the other.

Mega Man &amp; Bass debuted on the aging 16-bit Super Famicom despite the series having already transitioned to the PlayStation and Sega Saturn with Mega Man 8. Artist and designer Keiji Inafune claimed Mega Man &amp; Bass was created with regard to younger players who did not yet own one of the more advanced gaming systems. The game received positive remarks from critics for its graphics and use of a tried-and-true gameplay formula, though many found the difficulty to be too steep. Although Mega Man &amp; Bass shares many traits with previous console games in the series, the ninth numbered title would not be released until 2008.

</desc>
		<image>./images/hqdefault.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>April 24, 1998</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Metal Max Returns (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Metal Max Returns (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Metal Max Returns, a remake of Metal Max (Famicom) for the Super Famicom, appears at first glance to be a fairly stereotypical RPG. Some careful observation and about half an hour´s worth of gameplay later, and it reveals itself to be much, much more. Set in a gritty, post-apocalyptic/wild west hybrid environment, a nameless youth decides to become a Hunter, one who fights monsters and cashes in on bounties, usually with heavy artillery. Enter Metal Max´s defining feature - tanks. You´ll spend a lot of time playing with your tanks - twinking them out, customizing them, even attaching little baubles to their dashboards. Most of the game is spent with your tanks, but it´s important that you don´t ignore your human characters´ development, because there will be times when you can´t use your tanks.

Metal Max is light on story, but heavy on gameplay. There´s a ton of stuff to do, such as hunting the weekly bounty head, improving your Hunter rank, toying with your tanks, exploring, getting a tattoo. It´s really up to you to figure out what you want to make of yourself in the wide world of Metal Max, but you´ll have a blast doing so!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Metal Max Returns (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Data East</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mickey to Donald - Magical Adventure 3 (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0RPGone].smc</path>
		<name>Mickey to Donald - Magical Adventure 3 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0
Translated by RPG One

Disney's Magical Quest, known in Japan as Mickey's Magical Adventure, is a Disney platform game trilogy released by Capcom. The games star Mickey Mouse and, (depending on the game version), either Minnie Mouse or Donald Duck, who must defeat Peg-Leg Pete. The gameplay is similar among all games in the series: the player must move as in a typical platform game, defeating enemies either by jumping on them or by grabbing and throwing blocks at them.

One of the most notable gameplay features of the series is the ability to change characters' outfits, which give characters different special abilities. Other gameplay elements in the series include the ability to expand the player's health meter by collecting special hearts, and to shop for items using coins that are scattered throughout the game.

The final game in the series was released for the Super Famicom only in Japan. It was later re-released for the Game Boy Advance, which was the first version of the game to be released outside Japan. In Disney's Magical Quest 3 Starring Mickey &amp; Donald, Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck try to save Donald's nephews from Baron Pete. It features four outfits and seven levels. Unlike the two earlier games in the series, an outfit now behaves different depending on if Mickey or Donald wears it.



</desc>
		<image>./images/Mickey to Donald - Magical Adventure 3 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 8, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Miracle Girls (J)[T+Eng 100% Eien Ni Hen].smc</path>
		<name>Miracle Girls (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Eien Ni Hen

Miracle Girls is a side scrolling action game published by Takara and based on a Japanese manga and animated series originally created in 1991. The game follows the adventures of two fifteen years old twin sisters, Mikage and Tomomi Matsunaga, who are not exactly your ordinary junior high school students. The two girls have a well kept secret - they are the 'Miracle Girls', and they both share extraordinary powers allowing them to communicate telepathically or to vanish into thin air and teleport themselves at will. The game begins in a school campus, just as the girls and four of their friends are about to start their lunch break. Suddenly, a glowing ball of light appears and teleport them into a distant and strange world. Furthermore, her friends have now mysteriously disappeared and the two girls embark on a long journey to find out who is behind all these strange events... The player can either play as Mikage or her twin sister Tomomi, and they both come equipped with the most unusual weapon - candies. In Miracle Girls, one can't simply damage or hit enemies; but must instead feed them candies. Foes lose all sense of aggression once they start nibbling on the sweet confections and become as docile as sheep for a few seconds. Interestingly, when in this harmless state, they can also be used as platforms in order to reach higher grounds. There are also a few items to collect in the game (such as fruits (heal the player), Golden Hearts (points), Invincibility Stars or extra lives). Additionally, three special items are carefully hidden throughout the game - the B icon that can be stored and used to kill all the enemies on the screen, the magic book that gives the player hints and clues about the game and finally the pink magic door that leads to a 'slot machine' bonus stage. As mentioned previously, the two sisters can also communicate telepathically and they do, from time to time, use this incredible ability to overcome obstacles - for instance, at the beginning of the game, one of the twin sister tells the player which colored flower to jump onto, and which one to carefully avoid ('shiroi' for white and 'takai' for red). Finally, boss battles also steer away from the norm and come in the shape of mini-games, such as Water Battles (where the player and an opponent fight with a water gun and an umbrella), Whack-a-Mole fights or Cloud Catch Contests (where each opponent try to collect as many colored clouds as possible within a time limit). Miracle Girls consists of five levels and also features a versus mode where up to two players can battle each other in one of the mini-games. 

</desc>
		<image>./images/mgi.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>October 22, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Takara</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mobile Suit Gundam - Cross Dimension 0079 (J)[T+Eng 100%].smc</path>
		<name>Mobile Suit Gundam - Cross Dimension 0079 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100%
        
        Cross Dimension 0079 uses an unorthodox system of tactical roleplaying. It sets the player with a number of mobile suits varying from one to three. In the early game the player controls only the Gundam. As the game progresses the player is allowed access to the Gundam, Guncannon and Guntank. In the late game (as the game follows the MS: Gundam film story) the player controls the Gundam and two Guncannons. Finally in the late game the player controls the RX-78XX Gundam Pixie along with two Guncannons.

The statistical values in the game are managed by a two types of points, Ability Points and Prime Points.

Ability Points (AP) act as both a sort of fuel (one AP is consumed for every space moved) and Hit Points. While it is impossible for an MS to be destroyed by consuming all its AP, it can become immobile once all AP is consumed hence rendering it nigh useless. AP depleted by enemies causes the MS to be destroyed and the player to lose (in the case of either Gundam) or the MS to retreat for the duration of the mission (Guncannon or Guntank).

Prime Points are another key component of the game. The characters start with a certain amount of these points initially and gains them through leveling. These points can be assigned to either Aim Attack (ranged weapons), Skill Attack (available/equipped special weapons, also determines what melee special attacks can be used), Close Defense (melee defense), Aim Defense (ranged defense), Skill Attack (defense against enemy special attacks), Item (maximum amount of equipable consumable items), Move (maximum movement within a single game round) and in the case of the Gundams Close Attack (melee attack damage). Unlike typical attribute point assignment these values are not fixed and can be changed either at the equip prompt between missions or at the time a character levels up.
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Cross_Dimension_0079_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate> February 10, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mobile Suit Gundam F91 - Formula Wars 0122 (J)[T+Eng 100%].smc</path>
		<name>Mobile Suit Gundam F91 - Formula Wars 0122 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100%
        Mobile Suit Gundam F91: Formula Wars 0122 (F91) was released in Japan on July 6, 1991 for the Super Famicom. This game tells the story of what happened after the end of the manga Mobile Suit Gundam F90 and the beginning of the anime film Mobile Suit Gundam F91. There was also a manga released that chronicles the same story, although I'm unsure at present if the manga was released before, after or alongside the game; my Japanese is really rusty.
The game itself is billed as a Real Time Strategy game, but don't go into the game expecting something similar to an RTS from the early 90s or you'll probably be sorely disappointed. Sure, there's a map and you move the Gundam around like an RTS, but once you enter combat with an enemy unit everything RTS-like goes out the window.
I've yet to see another game that has a battle system that's like F91's, which attempts to simulate the feeling of actually being in the cockpit of the Gundam you're piloting. Whether it truly recreates the feeling of controlling a 15 meter high death machine or not (it doesn't, spoiler alert), it is a noble attempt, which I have to give Bandai credit for.
Overall it's a great game for a Gundam fan. We've tried to maintain consistency with the established canon where possible while making the story fun to read. Hope it shows.
        </desc>
		<image>./images/5dfcbc208dea0256cb99280db0db387b.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 6, 1991</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mobile Suit Gundam Wing - Endless Duel (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Mobile Suit Gundam Wing - Endless Duel (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Duel is a head-to-head fighting game released exclusively in Japan in 1996. It was the first video game to be based on the Mobile Suit Gundam Wing anime series, and has never been released outside Japan. The developers have used the same engine as previously used in another game, Mighty Morphin Power Rangers: The Fighting Edition, but with some improvements added exclusively to this game.

In single player mode, the player fights a series of battles dependent on which Gundam they chose, although ultimately all Gundams but the chosen one will be fought against. When the player normally fights the Wing Gundam Zero, if piloting Wing Zero, the player will fight a more challenging Wing Gundam piloted by Trowa (a cheat sometimes called Heavyarms 88). After fighting Wing Zero, the player will fight against the Gundam Epyon. When using the Tallgeese, which is piloted by Zechs, who pilots the Epyon (under a different alias), Epyon is then piloted by Heero.

Upon completion of the game on the 'Hard' difficulty level, the player will learn a code to unlock Epyon in multiplayer mode. In addition to these modes, a further 'trial mode' was added, in which you can choose any Gundam (including Epyon) and fight a never-ending series of fights in increasing difficulty until the player is defeated. Afterwards the game would show the number of victories won. The maximum number of victories shown possible is 99.

Since every character is a mobile suit, during game play, it is possible to activate a booster at anytime. While jumping, a player could boost up to twice and could be used to jet forward or backwards. This along with air blocking made air combat much more significant than in other fighters of the day. After boosting in the air a player can "hover" by pressing down. The Tallgeese mobile suit has the unique trait of being able to "hover" the longest. Because of this, Endless Duel was an early example of a fighter that included vertically scrolling stages. The boosting also works on the ground as players could boost forward or backwards while blocking which made for effective advancing against an opponent with superior ranged abilities and adds an incredible sense of mobility. Also, several suits in the game can perform special and super moves in air along with air throws.

</desc>
		<image>./images/250px-New_Mobile_Report_Gundam_Wing_-_Endless_Duel_Coverart.png</image>
		<releasedate>March 29, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Natsume</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mobile Suit V Gundam (J)[T+Eng 100% Twilight Translations].smc</path>
		<name>Mobile Suit V Gundam (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Twilight Translations

I’m not sure if you can call this a game.

This is another Gundam game, but unlike its brethren, this is not a strategy game, but more of a side-scrolling adventure. Except you can barely control your mech, you have very limited ammo, you can’t jump, you only have a flimsy shield to protect yourself, and oh yeah, two enemy mechs will come at you from both sides, so even if you’re defending your front, your back is wide open.

No pun intended there, folks, but that’s what happened to me. I had a forcible entry expert there.

In short, I don’t like this game. The end.

…

Well okay, the graphics are pretty.
</desc>
		<image>./images/pa.112032.1.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 11, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>TOSE</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Monstania (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.03_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Monstania (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.03
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Monstania is a fun (if short) little strategy RPG. Gameplay is very simple, very fast (for a strategy-RPG), and very not-menu-driven. In fact, you only need to use menus during combat if you want to change your equipment or use a technique :) It´s quite a fun little game. Give it a try if you´re into strategy-RPGs, puzzle games, RPGs in general, or if you just want something to do some afternoon. You won´t be disappointed!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Monstania (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 27, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Pack-In-Video</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy/RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mysterious Dungeon 2 - Shiren the Wanderer(J)[T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Mysterious Dungeon 2 - Shiren the Wanderer(J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        
        Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer is a graphical roguelike by Chunsoft. It is the second videogame in the Mystery Dungeon series, and the first game in the series to feature all original characters. It was originally released for the Super Famicom in 1995, and has subsequently been remade for the Nintendo DS.
        
        As in other roguelikes, the player moves in a turn-based manner through a number of dungeons. While most roguelikes generate dungeons completely randomly, Shiren the Wanderer randomly chooses from a set of static dungeons. Although the player can save the game in various locations, dying resets Shiren's level to 1, sends him back to the first town, and all items not saved in warehouses are lost. The game's dungeons include a variety of settings, like caves and forests, and are randomly filled with monsters, traps, and items.
        
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/2703916-fushigishiren_sfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>December 1, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Chunsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Chunsoft</publisher>
		<genre>Roguelike</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mystic Ark (J)[T+Eng 100% V1.01 AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Mystic Ark (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.01 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Mystic Ark, commonly (and improperly) known as "The 7th Saga 2" in some circles, is an RPG by Enix that spans worlds, and embeds a lot of adventure/puzzle elements into the genre.Disnesquick did the programming for our font, and the text was translated by Ian Kelley. You'll pardon the brief description, but it's after midnight, I've been working on this game virtually every available moment for the past two weeks, and I'm really, really tired. But the patch is out, so I guess it was worth it.

A quick note about the screenshots, incidentally: The male main character's default name is Remeer but the katakana is identical to the name of the first town in 7th Saga, which was romanized as Lemele. I've been playing the game with the main character renamed as such, but the default remains Remeer.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Mystic Ark (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 14, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Nankoku Shounen Papuwa-kun (J) [T+Eng1.00_FH].smc</path>
		<name>Nankoku Shounen Papuwa-kun (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by FH

Nangoku Shounen Papuwa-kun ("Southern Boy Papuwa") is a manga and anime about a young boy and his unusual friends on a tropical island. The player character is Shintaro, a member of the Genma army, as he runs across the island to find out where a bunch of invading monsters came from.

The game is a mix of brawling and platforming. Shintaro has a quick punch move and a charged-up beam attack, and fights various sub-bosses as he makes his way through levels. He'll occasionally meet characters from the manga as well, including Tanno and Itou, who are a transvestite fish and an effeminate pink snail respectively.

Both the Game Boy and Super Famicom versions were released on the same day by Enix Corporation, which also published the manga.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Nangoku Shounen Papuwa-kun (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 25, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Enix</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Nekketsu Tairiku Burning Heroes (J) [T+Eng0.001_Deltaflame].smc</path>
		<name>Nekketsu Tairiku Burning Heroes (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng0.001
Translated by Deltaflame

 From Enix comes Burning Heroes, known in Japan as "Nekketsu Tairiku Burning Heroes". Similar to Live a Live the game starts with giving the player a choice of multiple characters at the beginning of the game with each character uniting throughout the course of the game. Having never seen the light of day outside of Japan, a well done english fan translation lets the rest of us enjoy this once forgotten SNES RPG.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Nekketsu Tairiku Burning Heroes (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer>J-Force</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Neugier (J)[T+Eng 100% V2 RPGONE].smc</path>
		<name>Neugier (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V2 
Translated by RPG One

Neugier: Umi to Kaze no Kodō ("Neugier ~Pulse of the Sea and Wind~") is an action-adventure / action role-playing game for the Super Famicom. Although the game was scheduled for release in the United States as The Journey Home: Quest for the Throne, in November 1993, the project was canceled.

Duke, the main character, fights in real-time battles on his quest to save Neugier. He can jump and equip armor in an RPG fashion. There is also an ability to push objects, or enemies, into a wall to break them.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Neugier - Umi to Kaze no Kodou (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 26, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Wolf Team</developer>
		<publisher>Telenet Japan</publisher>
		<genre>Action RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Panel de Pon (J)[T+Eng 100% Zuqkeo V1].smc</path>
		<name>Panel de Pon (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Zuqkeo


Tetris Attack was originally released as Panel de Pon which was released on October 27, 1995 in Japan. An altered version of the original Panel de Pon was also released via Satellaview in 1998 under the name BS Panel De Pon - Event '98. The original Panel de Pon was released in Japan on the Wii's Virtual Console service on November 27, 2007. Tetris Attack's gameplay remains the same but the characters were changed from Panel de Pon's original characters to characters based on Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island.

In Panel de Pon, the evil devil king Thanatos has cast a spell over the world of Popples to cause fighting amongst the fairies. The Fairy of Flowers, Lip, is unaffected due to her magic stick. Lip must defeat each of her fairy friends in a puzzle game to return their personalities to normal, then proceed to face off against Thanatos. Upon completion of Hard Mode, the player discovers that the final boss, the goddess Cordelia, is actually Lip's mother and queen of the fairies. She informs Lip that the events leading up to this moment were a test to see if Lip had the strength to become the new Queen of the next generation of fairies.

In the version of Panel de Pon released as part of Nintendo Puzzle Collection for the GameCube, similar but younger fairies take the place of the original characters, and several new characters and stages have been added. The plot is otherwise very similar; however, the ending is very different. Other changes include a password system and improved AI over Panel de Pon. While it uses some new tracks based on Yoshi's Island, all of the in-game music in Tetris Attack remains unchanged from Panel de Pon except for the track Cordelia X which is absent. The original Panel de Pon soundtrack was scored by Masaya Kuzume. The music tracks from Yoshi's Island were arranged by Fire Emblem composer Yuka Tsujiyoko. The demo theme is "Lip's Theme", which would later be remixed for Super Smash Bros. Brawl and reused in Super Smash Bros. for Wii U.

When Nintendo came to us, and said "we would like to take this Japanese game called Panel de Pon, and rename it Tetris Attack", I’m saying, "it’s not Tetris". ... In retrospect, we should never have done that. I don’t think that’s a good idea. It dilutes the brand, it’s like naming another cartoon character Mickey Mouse just cause [sic] you need the money.

— Henk Rogers, Tetris CEO
</desc>
		<image>./images/paneldepon.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>October 27, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Panic in Nakayoshi World (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_Proj.SailorMoon].smc</path>
		<name>Panic in Nakayoshi World (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Proj.SailorMoon

Panic in Nakayoshi World is a 1994 video game that was released exclusively in Japan for the Super Famicom. It features such manga series as Sailor Moon and Chō Kuse ni Narisō and Goldfish Warning!

This title is about monsters that are attacking the World of Nakayoshi. The monsters are eating up the citizens. The more they eat, the hungrier they get. Four girls must stop the monsters and defeat Daima to save the World of Nakayoshi. The game is an overhead Adventures of Lolo-style puzzle game featuring characters from various Nakayoshi-printed manga. Sailor Moon and Chibi Moon are playable characters. There are also characters from Goldfish Warning!.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Panic_in_Nakayoshi_World.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>November 18, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Tom Create</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Poitto! (J) [T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Poitto! (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        
        A pretty standard puzzle game. Aggressively match tiles to fight monsters. But it’s got cute graphics and nice music
        </desc>
		<image>./images/312013_front.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>August 5, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Takara</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Popeye - Tale of Teasing Sea Hag (J)[T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Popeye - Tale of Teasing Sea Hag (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        
        Popeye: Ijiwaru Majo Seahag no Maki (lit. "Popeye: The Tale of Seahag the Wicked Witch") is a video game for the Super Famicom game console based on the popular Popeye franchise, specifically in the comic strips originally created by E.C. Segar. It was released by Technos Japan on August 12, 1994 exclusively in Japan.
        
        As Popeye, players will have to fight their way through different villains such as Bolo, Ox, Emok, General Bunzo and his troops, Bernard the Buzzard, the boss for most levels Brutus, and the main boss Seahag.
        
        After countless defeats at the hands of Popeye, the evil Seahag has devised a fool proof plan for revenge. She turns all of Popeye's friends into stone by removing their hearts and scattering the pieces across the corresponding islands. Now Popeye must search for the hearts within each of five islands in order to revive them. It won't be easy, as General Bunzo and his troops has issued a "100,000,000G" bounty for the hearts. This prompts the likes of Bolo, Ox to try and collect the hearts for the reward. Upon reading this, Brutus decides to quest for the hearts as well in a plan to impress Olive. Thus making this a race against time for Popeye to save his friends and put a stop to Seahag's plan.
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Popeye_SFC_Cover.PNG</image>
		<releasedate>August 12, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Technos Japan</developer>
		<publisher>Technos Japan</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Pretty Soldier Sailor Moon - Another Story (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_BST].smc</path>
		<name>Pretty Soldier Sailor Moon - Another Story (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by BST

Sailor Moon: Another Story, as is the case with most RPGs, has two different well-defined parts: The first is overworld exploration. The game features several locations, the Juuban district being the biggest one, that must be explored in order to progress in the game. However, unlike most other RPGs, most of these locations cannot be accessed after the player has finished all plot-relevant events, making the gameline very linear one. To explore locations, a 2D top-down perspective and grid-based movements for characters are used. 

The second is combat and it focuses in tactics rather than action

In the battles in the game, the player uses a team of up to 5 Senshi (or less depending on where in the game the story takes place. In the later parts of the game, the player can choose between any Senshi. However Sailor Moon is almost always required to be in the party, and Chibi Moon is required quite often as well). Each Senshi has 12 MP max (which is received after a few level ups). Several of the Senshi can also use their powers in combination for new attack. For example; Mercury and Chibi-Moon can use a combo attack called Pink Sugar Illusion, which revives all allies.

</desc>
		<image>./images/sailor-moon-with-box-sfc-super-famicom-nintendo-japan-828b935cf19ff74d13a5ba72f9835d95.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 22, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Radical Dreamers (J) [T+Eng1.2_Demiforce].smc</path>
		<name>Radical Dreamers (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.2_
Translated by Demiforce

Radical Dreamers: Nusumenai Hōseki ("Radical Dreamers: The Unstealable Jewel") is a Japanese video game developed by Square in 1996 for the Satellaview add-on for the Super Famicom. It is a text-based visual novel in which the player takes the role of Serge, a young adventurer accompanied by Kid, a teen-aged thief, and Gil, a mysterious masked magician.

The game belongs to the Chrono series and is a gaiden, or side story, to the 1995 game Chrono Trigger. It was released to complement its predecessor's plot, and later served as inspiration for Chrono Cross. It features text-based gameplay with minimal graphics and sound effects, and was scored by composer Yasunori Mitsuda. Unlike many Satellaview titles, Radical Dreamers was not designed to lock after a certain number of playthroughs, so players owning an 8M Memory Pack onto which the game was downloaded can still play today.

Square tried to integrate Radical Dreamers into the Japanese PlayStation port of Chrono Trigger as an Easter egg. Writer and director Masato Kato halted this and other releases, unhappy with the quality of his work. Though the game was never officially released abroad, ROM hackers completed an English fan translation in 2003.

Gameplay consists of word-based scenarios presented to the player through the narration of the main character, Serge. As the narrative progresses, the game presents a list of possible actions and the player must choose his or her course. Depending on the choices made, the player may enter a new area, be presented with a new situation or character, or have to choose again if the previous selection was incorrect. In combat with enemies, the player must select from options such as "Fight", "Magic", "Run", and often more complex situational commands like "Run my knife into the goblin's chest!" or "Quickly slash at its hand!". Some decisions must be made before an invisible timer runs out; in combat, hesitation results in injury or death. Serge's health is tracked by an invisible point count, restored by various events (such as finding a potion). The game also tracks Kid's affection for Serge, influenced by battles and scripted events. Her feelings determine whether Serge survives the story's climactic fight.

Radical Dreamers features minimal graphics and animation; most areas are rendered with dim, static backgrounds. The game also uses atmospheric music and sounds. Like other Chrono games, Radical Dreamers contains a variant of New Game + mode. Only one scenario is available on the first play-through; after finishing it and obtaining one of three possible endings, players can explore six others. These later stories often feature comical situations or allusions to Chrono Trigger.

 </desc>
		<image>./images/radicaldreamers.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>February 3, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>Visual Novel</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Radical Dreamers Le Trésor Interdit (J)[T+Eng 100% Demiforce v1.4].sfc</path>
		<name>Radical Dreamers: Nusumenai Hōsek</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
v1.4
        Translated by Demiforce
 
 
 Radical Dreamers: Nusumenai Hōseki ("Radical Dreamers: The Unstealable Jewel") is a Japanese video game developed by Square in 1996 for the Satellaview add-on for the Super Famicom. It is a text-based visual novel in which the player takes the role of Serge, a young adventurer accompanied by Kid, a teen-aged thief, and Gil, a mysterious masked magician.

The game belongs to the Chrono series and is a gaiden, or side story, to the 1995 game Chrono Trigger. It was released to complement its predecessor's plot, and later served as inspiration for Chrono Cross. It features text-based gameplay with minimal graphics and sound effects, and was scored by composer Yasunori Mitsuda. Unlike many Satellaview titles, Radical Dreamers was not designed to lock after a certain number of playthroughs, so players owning an 8M Memory Pack onto which the game was downloaded can still play today.

Square tried to integrate Radical Dreamers into the Japanese PlayStation port of Chrono Trigger as an Easter egg. Writer and director Masato Kato halted this and other releases, unhappy with the quality of his work. Though the game was never officially released abroad, ROM hackers completed an English fan translation in 2003.

Gameplay consists of word-based scenarios presented to the player through the narration of the main character, Serge. As the narrative progresses, the game presents a list of possible actions and the player must choose his or her course. Depending on the choices made, the player may enter a new area, be presented with a new situation or character, or have to choose again if the previous selection was incorrect. In combat with enemies, the player must select from options such as "Fight", "Magic", "Run", and often more complex situational commands like "Run my knife into the goblin's chest!" or "Quickly slash at its hand!". Some decisions must be made before an invisible timer runs out; in combat, hesitation results in injury or death. Serge's health is tracked by an invisible point count, restored by various events (such as finding a potion). The game also tracks Kid's affection for Serge, influenced by battles and scripted events. Her feelings determine whether Serge survives the story's climactic fight.

Radical Dreamers features minimal graphics and animation; most areas are rendered with dim, static backgrounds. The game also uses atmospheric music and sounds. Like other Chrono games, Radical Dreamers contains a variant of New Game + mode. Only one scenario is available on the first play-through; after finishing it and obtaining one of three possible endings, players can explore six others. These later stories often feature comical situations or allusions to Chrono Trigger.

 </desc>
		<image>./images/radicaldreamers.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>February 3, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>Visual Novel</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ranma Nibunnoichi - Akanekodan Teki Hihou (J) [T+Eng1.00-Anime_Various].smc</path>
		<name>Ranma Nibunnoichi - Akanekodan Teki Hihou (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by Anime_Various

Ranma 1/2: Akanekodan Teki Hihou is a roleplaying game for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. It was the third Ranma 1/2 game released in 1993 as well as the third game overall for the SNES. Its title alternatively translates into "Ranma 1/2: Treasure of the Crimson Cat Gang" or "Ranma 1/2: Treasure of the Red Cat Gang". Of the two, the latter translation is typically regarded as the official one

While coming home late one night, the Jusenkyo Guide accidentally wanders into the Gods and Demons Graveyard, and proceeds to knock over the tomb of the dreaded Nekomaou, the Ghost Cat King. The evil spirit, returned from the grave, gathers to him the titular Red Cat Gang and sets out to gather three treasures, the Peach Gem, Sakura Sword and Forest Mirror, in order to recreate the magical Star Crystal and attain his wish of world domination. Ranma Saotome and several of his friends set out to stop this evil from occuring.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Akanekodan_Teki_Hihou_-_Box_Art.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>October 22, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Rumic Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Toho</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rapurasu no Ma (J) [T+Eng.95b_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Rapurasu no Ma (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.95b
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Laplace no Ma (literally "Laplace's demon") is a mixture of the role-playing video game and survival horror genres and set in the vicinity of Boston, Massachusetts in a town called "Newcam", it is modeled on fictional city Arkham created by H. P. Lovecraft.

The horror part of the game lies in the exploration of the fictional Weathertop Mansion, whose owner dabbled in black magic. The game's CRPG features include its character classes—Dilettante, Medium, Detective, Scientist, and Journalist—and that the player can leave the mansion to walk around the town to go to shops to buy items needed to defeat the monsters and complete the game.

</desc>
		<image>./images/rapurasu-no-ma-super-famicom-used-good-condition-en.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>May 14, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Vic Tokai</developer>
		<publisher>Vic Tokai</publisher>
		<genre>Survival Horror, RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rockman 7 - Duel of Fate - Retranslation(J)[T+Eng 100% ZynkOxhyde].smc</path>
		<name>Rockman 7 - Duel of Fate - Retranslation(J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by ZynkOxhyde

Mega Man 7, known as Rockman 7: Shukumei no Taiketsu! in Japan, is a video game developed by Capcom for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. It is the seventh game in the original Mega Man series and the first and only title in the main series to be featured on the 16-bit console. The video game was first released in Japan on March 24, 1995 and was localized later in the year in North America and Europe. The game is also available for the PlayStation 2, Nintendo GameCube, and Xbox as part of the Mega Man Anniversary Collection.

Picking up directly after the events of Mega Man 6, the plot involves the protagonist Mega Man once again attempting to stop the evil Dr. Wily, who uses a new set of Robot Masters to free himself from captivity and begin wreaking havoc on the world. Along with some help from his old friends, Mega Man finds potential allies in the mysterious robot pair Bass and Treble, who are later revealed to be in league with Wily. In terms of gameplay, Mega Man 7 follows that same classic action and platforming introduced in the 8-bit Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) titles, but updates the graphics and sound of the series for the more powerful SNES.

According to its creators, Mega Man 7 was only in development for a short time before its release. Keiji Inafune, a noted character designer and illustrator for the franchise, handed off his duties to Hayato Kaji for this installment. Mega Man 7 has received an overall average critical reception. Although many considered it a competent game by itself, a majority of reviewers either called it a simple rehash of previous entries in the Mega Man saga, or considered it inferior to the inventive spin-off Mega Man X, released on the SNES over a year earlier.
</desc>
		<image>./images/rockman7.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 24, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Romancing SaGa 3 (J) (V1.0) [T+Eng.30_ManaSword].smc</path>
		<name>Romancing SaGa 3 (J) (V1.0) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.30
Translated by ManaSword

Romancing SaGa 3 is the sixth title in the SaGa role-playing video game series developed and published by Square (now Square Enix) and released exclusively for the Super Famicom system in Japan. It was also the third and final SaGa title to be released for the Super Famicom.

The gameplay is similar to other console RPGs of the era, but with several notable differences. For example, instead of 'level ups', character stats increase individually depending on their participation in a battle. Also, a character has a certain amount of 'LP', which decreases when the character's HP is reduced below zero or when they are hit while their HP remains at zero. If the LP of a character is zero, they are removed from the party, but they can be recruited again with the exception of the main character of the current game, once the main character reaches zero LP, it results in an automatic game over.

During battle, characters can learn ("spark") new techniques which often turn the battle in their favor; the same goes for gaining the ability to evade certain enemy attacks. There is also a Commander mode, which requires at least one character more than the lead character, with the lead character on the back lines, out of the battle. If the player has less than a full party of 6 he or she may use one person smaller formations (i.e. using a four-person formation with a party of five so the main character can direct in Commander mode.) During Commander mode, techniques that involve multiple characters can be learned, depending on the formation.

When choosing to play as Mikhail, the player will start with a mini-war campaign, which continues as the game progresses. Some of these war campaigns must be won or the player loses the game. In these battles, the player controls a band of soldiers instead of individual characters. The player issues commands (forward, quick forward, rush, defend, retreat, morale up, etc.). The point of the battle is to advance to the other side of the map (the player starts on the right and must advance to the left).
</desc>
		<image>./images/Romancing SaGa 3 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>November 11, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Romancing SaGa 3 (J) (V1.0) [T+Eng.35_Dragonsoft].smc</path>
		<name>Romancing SaGa 3 (J) (V1.0) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.35
Translated by Dragonsoft

Romancing SaGa 3 is the sixth title in the SaGa role-playing video game series developed and published by Square (now Square Enix) and released exclusively for the Super Famicom system in Japan. It was also the third and final SaGa title to be released for the Super Famicom.

The gameplay is similar to other console RPGs of the era, but with several notable differences. For example, instead of 'level ups', character stats increase individually depending on their participation in a battle. Also, a character has a certain amount of 'LP', which decreases when the character's HP is reduced below zero or when they are hit while their HP remains at zero. If the LP of a character is zero, they are removed from the party, but they can be recruited again with the exception of the main character of the current game, once the main character reaches zero LP, it results in an automatic game over.

During battle, characters can learn ("spark") new techniques which often turn the battle in their favor; the same goes for gaining the ability to evade certain enemy attacks. There is also a Commander mode, which requires at least one character more than the lead character, with the lead character on the back lines, out of the battle. If the player has less than a full party of 6 he or she may use one person smaller formations (i.e. using a four-person formation with a party of five so the main character can direct in Commander mode.) During Commander mode, techniques that involve multiple characters can be learned, depending on the formation.

When choosing to play as Mikhail, the player will start with a mini-war campaign, which continues as the game progresses. Some of these war campaigns must be won or the player loses the game. In these battles, the player controls a band of soldiers instead of individual characters. The player issues commands (forward, quick forward, rush, defend, retreat, morale up, etc.). The point of the battle is to advance to the other side of the map (the player starts on the right and must advance to the left).
</desc>
		<image>./images/Romancing SaGa 3 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>November 11, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./RPG Tsukuru - Super Dante (J) [T+Eng0.90_Magecraft].smc</path>
		<name>RPG Tsukuru - Super Dante (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng0.90
Translated by Magecraft

It's RPG Maker
</desc>
		<image>./images/rpgmaker.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>March 31, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>Game Creator</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./RPG Tsukuru 2 (J) [T+Eng1.05a_Magecraft].smc</path>
		<name>RPG Tsukuru 2 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.05a
Translated by Magecraft

Sequel to RPG Maker
</desc>
		<image>./images/RPGTsukuru2Cover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>January 31, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>Game Creator</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sailor Moon R (J) [T+Eng1.00_FuSoYa].smc</path>
		<name>Sailor Moon R (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.00
Translated by FuSoYa

A sequel was produced to the first Sailor Moon game which introduced a new playable character, Chibiusa. Unlike other Sailor Moon games, Sailor Moon R was developed and published by Bandai instead of Angel. The sprites from the previous game were redesigned with more detail and more animation frames for this game and the later games. Like the Mega Drive version of the previous game, the bosses have their own theme music. By playing the game on hard mode, there is a minor change to the ending that involves Sailor Pluto.

Monsters in this game were all droids. Like the previous game, there are several different shades of them. Other differences from the first game include a special attack which allows the player to perform a special attack that destroys all on-screen enemies.
</desc>
		<image>./images/33024-Bishoujo_Senshi_Sailormoon_R_(Japan)-7.jpg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer>Bandai</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sanrio World Smash Ball! (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_Suicidal].smc</path>
		<name>Sanrio World Smash Ball! (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Suicidal

Sanrio World Smash Ball! is an action/sports video game released in 1993 for the Super Famicom. It features several playable Sanrio characters – Keroppi, Tabo, Pokopon and Hangyodon, along with the non-playable Hello Kitty. The game is a variation of Pong and air hockey - players hit a moving disc back and forth in an attempt to make it cross the opponent's goal line. The game was only released in Japan, but English, German and French fan translations exist.

Players must hit a continuously moving disc back and forth along a vertical playing field by hitting it either to the left or to the right. Holding one of the buttons while not moving will charge up an "energy meter" for a more powerful hit. The object of the game is to make the disc cross into the opponent's goal. The goal is protected by blocks that disappear when the disc hits them a set number of times. Some blocks have power-ups that increase a characters' speed, strength, or something that causes a problem to the opponent, like removing the blocks that protect the opponent's goal.

There are four playable characters: Keroppi, Tabo, Pokopon and Hangyodon. Hello Kitty makes appearances as a judge of the matches. Each character has its unique strengths and weaknesses. Keroppi is the balanced character, Tabo has weak blows but in return he is the fastest to run, Pokopon has the best defense, and Hangyodon has the strongest blows.

In single-player mode there are thirty different levels of increasing difficulty. Players can resume their games by using passwords. In multi-player mode there is a selection of twenty arenas. Each level contains new obstacles appears such as more blocks, rotating blades and balloons as well as new layouts, which either aide or hinder players.
</desc>
		<image>./images/2271118-sanrio_world_smash_ball_.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 16, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Tomcat System</developer>
		<publisher>Character Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Secret of Mana 2 - Seiken Densetsu 3 (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.01_NCorlett+LNFT].smc</path>
		<name>Secret of Mana 2 - Seiken Densetsu 3 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01
Translated by NCorlett+LNFT

Seiken Densetsu 3 (lit. "Legend of the Sacred Sword 3") is a 1995 action role-playing video game developed and published by Square (now Square Enix) for the Super Famicom. It is the sequel to the 1993 game Seiken Densetsu 2 (released as Secret of Mana outside Japan), and is the third installment in the Mana series. Set in a high fantasy world, the game follows three heroes as they attempt to claim the legendary Mana Sword and prevent the God Beasts from being unleashed and destroying the world. It features three lengthy main plotlines and six different possible main characters, each with their own storylines, and allows two players to play simultaneously. Seiken Densetsu 3 builds on the gameplay of its predecessor with multiple enhancements, including the use of a time progression system with transitions from day to night and weekday to weekday in game time, and a wide range of character classes to choose from, which provides each character with an exclusive set of skills and status progression.

The game was designed by series creator Koichi Ishii, directed by veteran Square designer Hiromichi Tanaka, and produced by Tetsuhisa Tsuruzono. Artwork was produced by manga and anime artist Nobuteru Yūki, while the music was composed by Secret of Mana composer Hiroki Kikuta. Although the game was only published in Japan, English-speaking players have been able to play Seiken Densetsu 3 due to an unofficial English fan translation, first released in 2000. Seiken Densetsu 3 received considerable acclaim from reviewers, who praised the graphics as among the best ever made for the Super Famicom and the gameplay as an improved version of its predecessor's. The plot received mixed reviews by critics, who found the overlapping stories to be interesting and to enhance replayability, but the characters and plotlines themselves to be flat and clichéd. Overall, the game is considered by some critics to be a Super Famicom classic and one of the best role-playing games of the 16-bit era.

Seiken Densetsu 3 has similar gameplay to its predecessor, Secret of Mana. Like many other role-playing games of the 16-bit era, the game displays a top-down perspective, in which the three player characters navigate the terrain and fight off hostile creatures. Control may be passed between each of the characters at any time; the companions not currently selected are controlled by artificial intelligence. The game may be played simultaneously by two players, as opposed to the three of Secret of Mana. There are six possible player characters. At the beginning of the game, the player chooses which three of them will be playable and which one they will start with; the other two playable characters will join the party when met. The remaining three characters act as non-playable characters (NPCs) when encountered.

Each character can use one type of weapon, in addition to magical spells. The effectiveness of spells depends on the magical ability of the character and the element of the spell in relation to the enemy. When in battle mode, attacking monsters fills a gauge that allows the player to use character-specific special attacks. Upon collecting enough experience points in battle, each character can increase in level to gain improved character statistics such as strength and evasion. Options such as changing equipment, casting spells, or checking status are performed by cycling through the game's Ring Commands—a circular menu which hovers over the controlled party member. The game is paused whenever the Ring Command menu is activated. Within the Ring, the player has nine slots for storing items; additional items can be placed into item storage, which is inaccessible in combat.

Character level progression is coordinated by the player, as a choice is given as to which statistic to raise by a point at every level up. A "class" system is also present. Once a character reaches level 18, the player can visit one of several Mana Stones located throughout the game and choose to upgrade them to one of two classes for each character—either a class aligned to "Light" or a class aligned to "Dark"—which provides a different set of skills and different improvements to character statistics. A second class change may be optionally performed at level 38, again split between a light and a dark choice, if the player has obtained a required rare item for the target class. The class changes do not affect the plot of the game, only gameplay.

Seiken Densetsu 3 also employs a calendar function into its gameplay. A week cycles much more quickly than an actual one, with a day passing in a matter of minutes. Each day of the week is represented by a different elemental spirit. On that spirit's day, magic of that element will be slightly stronger. An in-game day is also divided into day and night. Certain events only happen during certain times of day, such as a nighttime-only black market selling particularly rare items. Enemies encountered in the field also change during certain time periods, and some may be sleeping if the characters approach them at night. In addition, the character Kevin transforms into a werewolf when he fights at night, greatly increasing his attack power. Using an inn's services allows the player to "skip" the game's clock to that day's evening, or the following morning.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Seiken Densetsu 3 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 30, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Square</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>Action RPG</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20160410T133127</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sengoku Denshou (J)[T+Eng 100% Vice].smc</path>
		<name>Sengoku Denshou (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Vice

Sengoku, fully titled Sengoku Denshō ("Legacy of the Warring States") in Japan, is a beat 'em up arcade game. It is the first game of the Sengoku trilogy by SNK. It was ported to numerous home consoles including the Neo Geo, Neo Geo CD, Mega-CD and Super Famicom while the latter version was later canceled in North America. 

Centuries ago a cruel and insanely tyrannical warlord was defeated by the two elite Samurais but had sworn to return in the future. When he does he unleashes undead forces of feudal Japanese warriors to destroy the world and its people. The warlord is opposed only by the two protagonists, a ninja and/or a Western cowboy (named Dan and Bill in the SNES version), who turn out to be descendants of the two elite Samurais responsible for vanquishing the wicked warlord centuries ago.

A player has a maximum of six health points. When certain enemies are defeated, spirits of powerful forms are available to transform into. In the SNES version transformation cannot be toggled, but stays constant for a limited time. The three different forms are a samurai warrior, an armour-clad wolf and a more agile ninja. These forms have a limited use. Their attacks and jumps differ from the original form and their powers are enhanced by any powerups collected.

Throughout the game the player will need to survive the hordes of enemies by collecting coloured orbs as powerups. Five Green orbs heal one health point. A Red orb gives the player a single sword, a Cyan orb gives the player double sword, the Purple orb gives the player a two-handed holy sword and a Yellow orb gives the player a limited magical attack.

</desc>
		<image>./images/sengokusfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 19, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shin Megami Tensei (J) (V1.0) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Shin Megami Tensei (J) (V1.0) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

This game is amazing. The story is deep and involving (literally), the game is long (expect to spend about 50 hours on it), the graphics are amazing for 1992, and the gameplay rewards experimentation and is full of micromanagement. This is very much one of the best RPGs for the SNES that I´ve ever played. The player is a demon summoner, thrust into the middle of a war in modern-day and futuristic Tokyo. Shin Megami Tensei is unique in that rather than force you onto one side or the other, the game presents both sides´ arguments equally and leaves you, the player, to make the final choice for yourself. This game is incredible, and everyone should try go play it. NOW.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Shin Megami Tensei (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 30, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Atlus</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shin Megami Tensei II (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Shin Megami Tensei II (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Shin Megami Tensei 2 is a direct sequel to the original SMT. It takes place some 20 or 30 years later. According to the "official" story, the hero in SMT1 followed the neutral path, defeated both the Asura Lord and the seraph Michael at the Cathedral, and established a neutral government where followers of both the Law and Chaos ideals could live freely. It doesn´t last very long. The Mesia faith usurps power, begins expanding the old Cathedral into a new, massive, fully-functional artifical enclosed environment, code-named Millenium. The Gaians rise up, but their rebellion is quickly put down by the Mesians´ elite warrior class, the Temple Knights. Meanwhile, the environment is steadily becoming more and more unlivable, and sometime after the year 2060, a massive migration to Millenium occurs. Some years later, an old, retired arena fighter named Okamoto discovers a man fighting for his life against a demon. He rescues that man, who doesn´t even remember his own name, and trains him to fight in the arena so they might both go on to a better living in one of the upper-class areas of Millenium...

The gameplay has improved since SMT1. You now can now access your automap at the touch of a button, demon conversations are more complex, sword fusions are more complex, fusion errors occur, and fused demons will "inherit" spells and abilities of their "parent" demons, too. The music, in my opinion, isn´t quite as good as SMT1´s, although the graphics are much better. The current release has one or two minor fairly minor issues, please see the readme for complete details. It´s very much complete, though!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Shin Megami Tensei II (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 18, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Atlus</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shin Nekketsu Kouha - Kunio-tachi no Banka (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Shin Nekketsu Kouha - Kunio-tachi no Banka (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

It´s Kunio. It´s a beatemup. It´s fun. Whee. For those who don´t know what I´m talking about, it all started (to my knowledge) with a game called Nekketsu Kouha - Kunio-kun which was released in the States as Renegade. That game´s quite a bit less popular than its cousin which came out here as River City Ransom, also starring Kunio and Riki. This game is the sequel to the original Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun, so don´t expect the RPG elements that RCR had in this. It´s still quite a fun game, though, and it´s LONG for a beatemup.

The story, basically, is that Kunio got in a hit-´n-run accident where he ran a red light and hit a man in a crosswalk, or something. Of course, he didn´t really do it; we learn within the first few minutes of the game that there´s a Kunio lookalike parading around Tokyo, and he´s likely the one who really got into the accident. It´s up to Kunio to clear his name, but he´s stuck in the juvenile detention center!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Shin Nekketsu Kouha - Kunio-tachi no Banka (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>April 29, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Technos Japan Corp</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shodai Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Shodai Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Shodai Nekketsu Kouha is often misnomered as River City Ransom 2, but that´s not quite right. Kunio and Riki actually gain experience, RPG-style, as well as equip weapons and use items that their enemies drop, learning new moves and special skills, but there´s no money - so you can´t buy anything. That said, there´s a day/night cycle implemented into the game, and certain places are only open at certain times of the day. You can also play some minigames to earn some extra items!

The story involves Kunio´s gang from Nekketsu High being invited to a vacation in Osaka by an exchange student. On his way to the hotel, however, Kunio is ambushed by thugs! He quickly learns of the Osaka Student Union, a gang of highschoolers intent on taking over Japan! This obviously won´t do, so gut-punching ensues!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Shodai Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 7, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Technos Japan</publisher>
		<genre>Beat em up / RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Silva Saga II - The Legend of Light and Darkness (J)[T+Eng100% DynamicDesigns].smc</path>
		<name>Silva Saga II - The Legend of Light and Darkness (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng100% 
Translated by DynamicDesigns

Silva Saga II: The Legend of Light and Darkness is a role-playing video game developed and published by SETA Corporation, which was released exclusively in Japan in 1993. It is a direct sequel to Silva Saga for the Family Computer.

The player will find similarities with Dragon Quest. Players search out the soldier of light who travels on a journey to defeat the Zolde, son of the Zuhl. Up to 12 mercenaries and deity statues can be combined as well as organized.

The story starts a few days before Silva Saga's ending. The main character is an amnesiac who goes on a quest to discover his identity and to try and save Kyral, the Light Warrior and main protagonist of the prior game from the games main antagonist, Zolde.

Although the game shares similarities with the Dragon Quest series, there are some noticeable differences. That being the mercenary and idol battle system. In the game, the player is given the chance to buy mercenaries (up to four) and find idols (up to four as well) to add to your party. In battle, the player is allowed to trade out the main party to bring in the mercenary party or idol party. The mercenary party cannot use spells but are very strong offensively and defensively. Unlike the mercenary party, idols are weak in both offense and defense but are very powerful with magic. Both parties cannot be controlled manually by the player.

Silva Saga 2 is the third game in a trilogy of role playing games. The series started with Minelvaton Saga: Ragon no Fukkatsu, continued with Silva Saga, and ended with Silva Saga 2. Unlike many other role playing games, the Minelvaton series takes place within one world, Minelvaton, and players are able to re-explore towns and dungeons from all three titles.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Silva Saga II - The Legend of Light and Darkness (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 25, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>SETA</developer>
		<publisher>SETA</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Slayers (J)[T+Eng 100% 1.01 DynamicDesigns]].smc</path>
		<name>Slayers (J)]</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.01 
Translated by DynamicDesigns

Slayers is a role-playing video game adaptation of the Slayers light novel series developed by BEC and published by Banpresto for the Super Famicom (SNES) exclusively in Japan in 1994. It is not to be mistaken for another Slayers game that was published by Banpresto for the NEC PC-9801 that same year. An English fan translation for the SNES game was completed in 2010.

The game system is similar to the early Final Fantasy games and other classic Japanese role-playing games of that era. In the main part of the game, the player and her party navigates different areas from a top-down perspective much like in other SNES games. When in an area, the player can call up a start menu to access items, perform healing spells, search the immediate area for hidden items, and such. The player can travel between different areas (towns, cities, forests and so on) via a world map. During the battle, from a third person view, the player can tell each character in their party to do one of six things: attack with a weapon, cast of one of the character's magic spalls (for magic users), use a special technique that varies from character to character, give up the character's turn for higher defense, attempt to flee from a random encounter battles, or use one of the items from the inventory.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Slayers (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>June 24, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>BEC</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Snoopy Concert (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Snoopy Concert (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Snoopy Concert´s unique in that it´s a point-and-click title. You do a separate game for each character; some of them require you to do a little detective work, or to direct Snoopy to win a race, or to get a character to some place. It´s cute, and it´s fun! The end goal, I think, is to get everyone in shape for Snoopy´s concert, but I really couldn´t say, it´s been a while since I last looked at it.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Snoopy Concert (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>May 19, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Mitsui Fudosan</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure/Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Star Fox 2 (Beta TD)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Star Fox 2 (Beta TD)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Ah, the prototype to end all prototypes. No, Star Fox 2 was never officially released. I will not go into how the game found its way onto the internet, as that is not my place. I will say that it´s a helluvalotta fun! At the beginning, you´re presented with a map of the Lylat system, with a few different things happening on it depending on which difficulty level you select. As soon as you move your chosen pilots to a different place on the map, things start happening and will continue to happen until you either A) change pilots by pressing select, or B) complete a level. Things will even continue to happen while you´re battling through a battleship, planet, missile salvo, boss, or fighter squadron. Don´t let things get too close to Corneria, though -- if the planet takes too much damage, it´s game over!

Another really cool thing that the game does is add incentives for playing the higher difficulty levels. The normal mode seems kind of cool at first, but it gets old pretty quickly. Kick the difficulty up to "Hard" and you have more planets to rescue, more battleships to destroy, more enemies and bosses flying around the map. And by the way, the battleship and planet levels´ layouts have changed! It´s really something else. The same things happen when you kick it up to "Expert" -- even more new and changed things.

If that weren´t enough, there are huge General Pepper coins strewn throughout each difficulty level. Each one only appears once -- after you pick it up, it will not appear in future playthroughs. I´m unsure of the function of these, other than to fully heal you when you find one, but I´ve yet to find them all. My running total is 27 or 28...

Everything´s done, and there are two versions of the patch -- one which just applies the translation (the "debug" version) and one which attempts to remove the non-functional bits and debug functions, to simulate what the game would look like if it were finished. Please be aware that there are a -lot- of different versions of the game floating around; this patch will work on at most three of them, but will not function on poor, earlier versions. Also note that the game´s particularly picky insofar as emulators are concerned, so before complaining that the patch doesn´t work, try the game unpatched to make sure that doesn´t crash your emulator. It ought to work on the roms that goodsnes has labelled "Beta TD" and "J o1" (which is funny, ´cuz the so-called overdump is actually the right size :p)
</desc>
		<image>./images/Star Fox 2 (Japan) (Proto) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>N/A</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo/Argonaut Software</developer>
		<publisher>N/A</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Star Ocean (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Star Ocean (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0
Translated by DeJap

Star Ocean is a role-playing video game that is played from a top-down perspective. The player navigates a character throughout the game world, exploring areas and interacting with non-player characters. In progressing through the game, the player is able to recruit up to eight additional characters to travel alongside the protagonist; some recruitments happen automatically, while others only happen depending on the previous actions and options taken by the player. Though only 8 characters can be recruited in a playthrough, ten characters are available to be recruited, meaning that not all characters can be recruited in one playthrough of the game. Most of the game occurs in towns and dungeons, and unlike many RPGs, the game lacks a world map that connects various locations, instead having the character follow paths from one place to the next.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Star Ocean (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>July 19, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>tri-Ace</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Action RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Back to the Future Part II (J)[T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Super Back to the Future Part II (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        Super Back to the Future II is a video game released for the Super Famicom based on the film Back to the Future Part II. The game was produced and released by Toshiba on July 13, 1993 in Japan only.
        
        Marty has returned from his bizarre trip to 1955 all thanks to Doc's prized invention, the DeLorean time machine. He decides to do some skateboarding around the neighborhood and visits his girlfriend Jennifer. However, this is cut short as Doc arrives from his trip to the future. He tells them that their children's future is at stake and proceeds to take them both to the year 2015. Here, Marty assumes the identity of his son Marty Jr. and faces off with Biff's grandson Griff and then his gang members one-by-one.

With Griff and his gang arrested time changes insuring Marty's children lives stay on track. But when Marty and Doc are not looking, old Biff takes an old sports almanac, hijacks the DeLorean, travels back to 1955 and gives the book to his teenage self. Then he returns to 2015 with Marty, Doc, and Jennifer none the wiser. When the three return to 1985, they discover that everything around them has drastically change. Hill Valley now plagued with crime and pollution, Biff Tannen is now Marty's stepfather, and the Doc has been certified insane. Now Marty must go throughout Hill Valley and figure out what has happened and try put time back to the way it was.
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Super Back to the Future Part II (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer>Toshiba</developer>
		<publisher>Toshiba</publisher>
		<genre>July 13, 1993</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Bomberman 4 (J)[T+Eng 100%].smc</path>
		<name>Super Bomberman 4 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100%
        Super Bomberman 4 is a multiplayer action-party video game, developed by Produce and published by Hudson Soft for the Super Famicom, released on April 26, 1996 exclusively in Japan. It is the fourth installment of the Super Bomberman franchise for the console.

The story begins at an unknown time after Super Bomberman 3. Bagular's brain escaped the explosion of his flying saucer and has summoned the Four Bomber Kings and Great Bomber to get revenge on White and Black Bomber. The two, along with other fellow Bombermen, are sent hurtling back in time to fight through different eras and ultimately stop Bagular.

Super Bomberman 4 is an action game in which players lay bombs to destroy enemies or other bombermen. Other than laying bombs, the game includes a number of power-ups, which allows players to increase the range of a bomb's explosion, punch or kick bombs already on the ground, or pick them up and throw them at another player. The explosions of the bombs can harm anyone on the field, including the bombermen who left the bomb in the first place. There are two game modes, Normal Game (the campaign, which can be played with two players), and the Battle Game, which has three separate modes.

New to the game are a wide range of creatures which are enemies to the player, but when defeated, they turn into eggs. When the player picks an egg, they can use the creatures, which come in two types, organic and mechanical. Players can pick additional eggs to store more creatures, but only of the same type of creature that they are riding.

Certain stages contain cages with trapped allies inside. When freed, allies move around the stages mostly destroying the soft blocks. Stages also have secret warps which transport the player to a number of bonus stages. This warps can only be accessed when two players play the game together, and one player, using the Power Glove item, tosses the other player to the warp.
        
        </desc>
		<image>./images/Super Bomberman 4 (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>April 26, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Produce</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Bomberman</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Bonk 2 (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_Gaijin].smc</path>
		<name>Super Bonk 2 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Gaijin

Super Genjin 2, also known as Super Bonk 2, is a 1995 2D platform video game, developed by Red Entertainment and published by Hudson Soft for Super Famicom. It is the sequel to Super Bonk in the Bonk series, and the only platform game in the series never to be released outside Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./images/supergenjin2.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 28, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Red Company</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Fire Pro Wrestling X Premium (J) [T+EngR7_Sydra].smc</path>
		<name>Super Fire Pro Wrestling X Premium (J) </name>
		<desc>T+EngR7
Translated by Sydra

Super Fire Pro Wrestling X Premium, or SFPWXP, was released in 1996 for the Super Famicom game system as part of the Fire Pro Wrestling series. Super Fire Pro Wrestling X Premium (commonly abbreviated SFPWXP) was one of the first wrestling games with an extensive edit mode where up to 80 created wrestlers could be stored and used in the game. The game featured likenesses of over 100 real-life professional wrestlers that were included with fake names to prevent copyright infringement. Fan translations of the game surfaced online with the advent of emulators such as Snes9x and ZSNES. These translations not only converted the Japanese text to English, but also restored the names of each wrestling likeness to its real-life counterpart. Unlike the more frenzied pace and button-mashing of arcade-style wrestling games, SFPWXP focused instead on skill and specific timing. Each wrestler possesses three different 'levels' of attacks, Weak, Medium, and Strong, and must realistically wear down the opponent to use their most powerful attacks without being reversed or countered.


</desc>
		<image>./images/Super Fire Pro Wrestling X Premium (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>March 29, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Human Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Human Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Gussun Oyoyo 2 (J)[T+Eng 100% RPGONE].smc</path>
		<name>Super Gussun Oyoyo 2 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by RPG One

The core gameplay of the series is to help Gussun and his brother Oyoyo (Vic and Vinnie respectively in Risky Challenge) escape a flooding stage by building a stairway with Tetris blocks. The goal is to reach the ceiling before the water level drowns the pair. Gussun and Oyoyo move independently based on their AI, similar to the titular lemmings of Lemmings, and the player needs to anticipate their AI pathing and their habit of occasionally freaking out whenever scary things happen.

In addition, the player can often choose between Emily and George as their "cheerleader". Emily is a young woman who frequently changes scanty costumes while George (originally Yousame) is a buff bodybuilder. Later ports removed George.

</desc>
		<image>./images/sfccover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate></releasedate>
		<developer>Kan's</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Puyo Puyo 2 (J) [T+Eng1.1_J2E].smc</path>
		<name>Super Puyo Puyo 2 (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.1_
Translated by J2E

Puyo Puyo Tsu (also known as Puyo Puyo 2, Puyo Puyo Tsuu or Puyo Puyo 2: Tsuu) is the second installment of the Puyo Puyo games; the sequel to Puyo Puyo, made in 1994 by Compile. Compile put more thought into this game after its predecessor became successful, but never knew how much of a turnaround the game would bring.

Just like the first game, Puyo fall from the top of the screen in pairs, can be moved left and right, and can be rotated clockwise and counter-clockwise by 90°; if the third column from the left fills up to the top, the game is over. The game has multiple new rules. The first extended rule added to this game was called Sousai (Garbage Countering). This will allow a player to counter and negate garbage being sent by the opponent with chains of their own. Sousai can also be used to send garbage back to the opponent, known as Garbage overflow. The standard ojamas were kept with the release of Puyo Puyo Tsu, however, two new garbage types also appeared, known as Point Puyos and Hard Puyos. Point Puyos, when erased adjacently with neighbouring groups of puyos, add points to your overall score, and can also make your chains more powerful in the short-term. Hard Puyos, when they land on the field, are harder to erase than Standard Garbage or Point Puyos, and are often referred to as Steelies.

Unlike its predecessor, Puyo Puyo Tsu has three different modes for each type. The three main modes are, Single Puyo Puyo, Double Puyo Puyo, and Endless Puyo Puyo. For Super Puyo Puyo 2, and Super Puyo Puyo 2 Remix, using a Super Multitap, an additional mode known as Minna de Puyo Puyo (Everybody Puyo Puyo, also the name of a Puyo Puyo game for the Game Boy Advance), means that up to 4 players (though for Remix, including a COM player) can play. Single Puyo Puyo is a story mode. In an attempt not only to steal Arle's heart, but also to nab Kaa-Kun, Satan sets up a battle tower, in which Arle has to beat characters on each floor to climb up the tower. As Arle wins every match, she gains bonus points which add on to her total score, and this acts as Experience. As a result, the chains are weaker and do less damage, but it means the game is harder. There are five predefined rule sets available in the versus menu. The player can set custom rules. Multiplayer lets multiple players play together
</desc>
		<image>./images/puyo2box.gif</image>
		<releasedate>December 8, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Robot Wars (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Super Robot Wars (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

3rd Super Robot Wars was the third game in a series, the second in the "classic" canon, and the first on the Super Famicom, published on July 23, 1993.

The story begins six month after the war in SRW2, DC has been defeated but this not the end of them. Those war make world into chaos, after the war everything turn fine.

DC whose defeat in previous war, was begining to construct their community again in the flag of Zabi empire. Without notice, they attack a few important places and cause more disaster.

The world then aware of this problem then creates a new earth defence to replace United Nations. This new organization name Earth Union. All warriors from previous wars are joined then become a part of Londo Bell. Londo Bell was an external organization for Earth Union.

But there was a problem, because of the previous war created by DC. Earth Union did not give a full support, they controlled the supply for weapon dan equipment. With the problem of DC, they must face the lack of equipment for defence of the world.
</desc>
		<image>./images/3rd_Super_Robot_Wars.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 23, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Banpresto</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Ultra Baseball 2 (J)[T+Eng 100% VX].smc</path>
		<name>Super Ultra Baseball 2 (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by VX

This video game was released in 1994 for the Super Famicom by Culture Brain in Japan only. The game adds some new features compared to the previous titles.

This game has a new 16-bit engine with much improved graphics, lots of new batter and pitcher edit options and manager/team personalities. According to an issue of Nintendo Power[citation needed] Culture Brain had planned to release this title in North America as (Super Baseball Simulator 1000 2) but canceled its release.

In the game, there are three leagues: Sunny, Paradise and Ultra. Each league has six teams. In the Ultra League, pitchers and batters have special power-ups that boost their abilities which gives the game a surrealistic feel that is rare in the sports genre. Players can even create their own baseball teams and assign special moves to the players that they name themselves. The game can be played in exhibition, season or All-Stars modes.
</desc>
		<image>./images/250px-Subb2_cover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 28, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Culture Brain</developer>
		<publisher>Culture Brain</publisher>
		<genre>Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tactics Ogre - Let Us Cling Together (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Tactics Ogre - Let Us Cling Together (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

This is... Tactics Ogre. Not much else needs to be said, really. In all honesty, this is not a retranslation of any sort - I´ve just dropped the official Playstation script into the game, and although I will be twinking it here and there for grammar and such, it´s mostly fine. It IS done and I am frankly sick of looking at it. Enjoy.

</desc>
		<image>./images/Tactics Ogre - Let Us Cling Together (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 6, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Quest</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy/RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tales of Phantasia (J) [T+Eng1.2LowCase_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Tales of Phantasia (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.2LowCase
Translated by DeJap

Tales of Phantasia (Hepburn: Teiruzu Obu Fantajia?) is a role-playing video game originally developed by Wolf Team as the first title in Namco's Tales series. This game was originally developed by Wolf Team. It was written and programmed by Yoshiharu Gotanda, designed by Masaki Norimoto, and scored by Motoi Sakuraba, Shinji Tamura, and Ryota Furuya. The character designs were created by manga artist Kōsuke Fujishima. 

The game begins as four heroes are locked in battle with a powerful sorcerer king named Dhaos. Before he can be defeated, Dhaos uses his magic to travel several years into the future, where he is immediately met by one of the four warriors' descendants and three companions, who seal him away with two magic pendants.[10] Twelve years later, two young men named Cress and Chester return to their village to find it razed to the ground by a dark knight named Mars, whose army kills many of it inhabitants including Cress's parents and Chester's sister. While Chester stays behind to bury them, Cress leaves to meet his uncle Olson for help, who reveals that he is being forced to work for Mars before stealing his father's pendant and locking him in jail. Quickly escaping with the help of a dying woman in a nearby cell, he meets another prisoner, a young priestess named Mint, who reveals that the woman was her mother before the two leave through the dungeon's aqueducts.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Tales of Phantasia (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 15, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco Tales Studio, Production I.G</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo, Namco</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tales of Phantasia (J) [T+Eng1.2UpCase_DeJap].smc</path>
		<name>Tales of Phantasia (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.2UpCase
Translated by DeJap

Tales of Phantasia (Hepburn: Teiruzu Obu Fantajia?) is a role-playing video game originally developed by Wolf Team as the first title in Namco's Tales series. This game was originally developed by Wolf Team. It was written and programmed by Yoshiharu Gotanda, designed by Masaki Norimoto, and scored by Motoi Sakuraba, Shinji Tamura, and Ryota Furuya. The character designs were created by manga artist Kōsuke Fujishima. 

The game begins as four heroes are locked in battle with a powerful sorcerer king named Dhaos. Before he can be defeated, Dhaos uses his magic to travel several years into the future, where he is immediately met by one of the four warriors' descendants and three companions, who seal him away with two magic pendants.[10] Twelve years later, two young men named Cress and Chester return to their village to find it razed to the ground by a dark knight named Mars, whose army kills many of it inhabitants including Cress's parents and Chester's sister. While Chester stays behind to bury them, Cress leaves to meet his uncle Olson for help, who reveals that he is being forced to work for Mars before stealing his father's pendant and locking him in jail. Quickly escaping with the help of a dying woman in a nearby cell, he meets another prisoner, a young priestess named Mint, who reveals that the woman was her mother before the two leave through the dungeon's aqueducts.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Tales of Phantasia (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 15, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco Tales Studio, Production I.G</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo, Namco</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tekkaman Blade (J)[T+Eng].smc</path>
		<name>Tekkaman Blade (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng
        Story

United Century 192

Humans are on the brink of extinction...
The Orbital Ring System, a gigantic space station built by humans for deep-space exploration, has been taken over by the mysterious life forms called "Radam."
Mankind's connection to space has been cut off, trapping them on Earth and leaving them at the mercy of Radam attacks.
The Earth is scorched, cities have been destroyed and humanity is falling into ruin.
An amnesic young man, brought in by the Space Knights and dubbed "D-BOY," is Earth's last hope.
With his crystal, he's able to turn into Tekkaman Blade, the only human capable of fighting the Radam aliens.
He is humanity's last hope.

        </desc>
		<image>./images/2647070-uchuunokishi_sfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>July 30, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Interbec</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tenchi Muyou! The Game (J)[T+Eng 100% 1.1 Borderline].smc</path>
		<name>Tenchi Muyou! The Game (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.1 
Translated by Borderline


Tenchi Muyo! Game Hen (Tenchi Muyo!: Game Edition), also known as Tenchi Muyo! RPG, is a Japanese role-playing strategy game developed by Banpresto for the Super Famicom, released on October 27, 1995. It was licensed by AIC and the now former Pioneer LDC. While Tenchi Muyou! Game Hen was never officially translated and released for international consoles, the later dumped ROM image of the game was hacked and translated into English on two occasions. Lina`chan, Nuku-Nuku &amp; Filia's Translations, or LNF, released their functional iteration in 2000, albeit some bugs and textual imperfections.

Tenchi Muyou! Game Hen is a turn-based game played from an isometric perspective. The game focuses entirely on fighting monsters within progressive worlds, all of which contain linear paths with predetermined battles. As such, the player does not freely roam or interact with the world.

There are a total of 12 playable characters in the game: Tenchi, Ryoko, Ayeka, Mihoshi, Sasami, Mizuki, Ryo-Ohki, Katsuhito, Yukinojyo, Azaka, Kamidake and Washu. The player starts with the beginning four, acquires the subsequent two later, and, by visiting more varied locations, can acquire the remaining six.[1] In prototypical role-playing fashion, each character has different movements, skills, personal advantages, attacking power, health and defense. Unlike the commonly instituted experience points system, however, characters level up by the accumulated number of monsters they defeat in battles.[1] There is a cap of eight levels that each player character can earn (unlike the Final Fantasy series and Chrono Trigger where each character's level can go up to 99). Up to four characters can be brought into combat at once and matches continue until all members of either side are eliminated.[1]

Like the other mediums of the series, Tenchi Muyou! Game Hen begins on the Masaki residence, progressively branching from the property to spacecraft and other planets. The characters Mizuki and Kusumi, new to the franchise, make an only appearance in the game.

On an otherwise ordinary sunny morning, Tenchi, Ryoko, Ayeka, Mihoshi and Ryo-Ohki sit to breakfast as Sasami finishes serving food. Realizing that Washu is not present, Sasami and Ryo-Ohki go to fetch her. Shortly after leaving, the house begins to wavily glow; ghastly monsters appearing in the hall.

Fighting and defeating the intruders, the group is approached by Mizuki, a mysterious girl who explains the obscure reason for her visit: test and measure the strengths of everyone. All but Ryoko take her objective with any real care until Mizuki presents Sasami as a hostage, garnering the now dire attention of the group. Acting the sportsman however, Mizuki agrees to surrender her captive in return for any one of the group injuring her in a fight. Much to her angst, Mizuki loses; refusing to go through with her end of the deal. She offers the group a future rematch as compensation and, leaving them with her next location, teleports Sasami and herself to her outbound spaceship.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Tenchi Muyou! - Game Hen (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>October 27, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Banpresto Co., Ltd</developer>
		<publisher>Tam Tam Co., Ltd</publisher>
		<genre>RPG, Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Magical Land of WOZZ (J) [T+Eng 100% Transcorp].smc</path>
		<name>The Magical Land of WOZZ (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Transcorp

"A relatively obscure RPG that just doesn't have much to it."
"Chou-Mahou Tairiku Wozz" (or "The Magical Land of Wozz") was released in 1995 exclusively for the Super Famicom in Japan. It's not known very well at all compared to most other Super Nintendo RPG's and was mostly forgotten. I can understand why.

=[Story: 4/10]=
This game isn't meant to be taken too seriously, but even with saying that - there's almost nothing here in terms of story: 3 humans are sent to the land of Wozz to defeat the evil Balam so they can return back to their own world. That's all you're doing for almost the entire game! As you progress you'll have to get through a lot of sudden and random obstacles which only halt you, most of them are there solely to make the game last longer (and it's very tedious). 

The story does contain a few twists here and there (mostly at the end) which are actually quite interesting, but it's still nothing major. There's also the dialogue - although good - just didn't fit that well. It wasn't very compelling and I wasn't able to get attached to any of the main characters...even enemies and NPC's needed more life to them!

=[Gameplay: 7/10]=
When you start a new game, you can select a character (out of 3). No matter which one you pick, all 3 characters will stay in your party throughout the game. There are some slight variations to situations depending on which character you choose, but it's nothing major, and the main story will always stay the same.

Apart from that, it's your usual RPG system where you explore towns, caves &amp; dungeons connected through an overworld. Battles are turn-based and in an isometric perspective much like Breath of Fire, and you can have up to 4 characters in battle. You've most likely seen it all before, but there's nothing wrong with that. The battle system itself is quite clunky and slow, but you'll get used to it rather quickly, and the encounter rate is fair, it's not too high so it shouldn't bother you .

There's also an invention system, where you mix 3 different items together to create a new one. With this it's possible to create new items, weapons, armor, vehicles and even robots to aid you in travel and battle. It's quite a fun system, even if basic. Something that I found rather different from other RPG's was the 999 item cap and that MP restoratives are relatively cheap, so you've always got massive support (which definitely lowers the difficulty of an already rather easy game).

=[Graphics: 7/10]=
Chou-Mahou Tairiku Wozz is quite nice looking. A lot of detail has been put in (especially the towns) and the characters are well animated with a lot of emotions. Apart from that most caves and dungeons look the same and have the same feel (most of them all have the same music too...) so this can make quite a dull experience. 

Battle graphics are quite better, as the backgrounds can be really detailed (although some of them look a bit of a mess) and magic animations do look really nice and big. Something else to note is that the whole game is rather dark.
Enemy designs are unique, they're really alien looking at times (especially the bosses). Quite a few are re-used in a new palette throughout the game but it's really not too bad. It's better than a lot of other RPG's I've played.

=[Music: 6/10]=
There's just not that much here. There's no boss battle theme, and the town, cave, dungeon themes are re-used way too often.
But still, what there is of the soundtrack is pretty good. It ranges quite a bit, because the battle themes are great, while the cave themes get way too repetitive. The soundtrack as a whole definitely has a unique and even memorable style to it, while also being really dark (which adds a lot to the atmosphere).

=[Overall: 6/10]=
It never really does get anywhere, you're always doing the same thing over and over throughout most of the game, and with a very basic story, it can be very tedious and even feel like a chore.
But it does has fun characters, an invention system, good music and nice looking visuals. I would recommend it, but there are far more better.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Cho Mahou Tairyku Wozz (English).png</image>
		<releasedate>August 04, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Bullet Proof Software</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Violinist of Hamelin (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.0_J2E].smc</path>
		<name>The Violinist of Hamelin (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.0_
Translated by J2E

Basically you go around and shoot people with your violin as Hamel, instead of a conventional weapon like your fists or a sword, and your raven tags along with you. It sounds weird, but it's quite effective. The real laughs come from the ability to abuse your partner, Flute. You can throw her at enemies to kill them, at walls to break them, and even throw her down a pit and she'll still live because she is invincible. If falls down a pit, then your raven will fetch her. She's quite versatile and you must always reach the end of a level WITH her, otherwise you have to go back for her. 

Reaching the end of a level with her in perfect health gets you a special bonus (who can resist using her as a human cannonball though?) This may sound like a boring task of having to keep the girl safe but she manages with the help of 'kigurumi'', or costumes. You have to collect these in the levels and use them. This is quite an interesting concept, since most of these costumes are essential to get her to places that you can normally reach but she can't. Some of them are: Ostrich - lets you cross spike floors, Monkey - lets you climb walls, Curling Puck - Throw her to clear lots of enemies, etc. These costumes are always quite comical, and are needed to help you on your journey.

Another neat feature is the ability to buy supplemental items in whatever town is in the current scene, as well as the ability to rest and recover health. Instead of points, there are coins in this game to expend on things like these. You can buy things like hourglasses to give extra time after the original timer is at 0, and even powerful (but expensive) costumes for Flute. You can rest and fully recover your health when it gets low. The items change from town to town, so you can buy different things when you move from scene to scene. There are also powerups and bonuses to collect like any other action game like things that power up Hamel's violin, and 1ups to give extra lives. 
</desc>
		<image>./images/sfc-hamelin-violinn-hiki-violinist-of-hamelin.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Tommorow's Joe (J)[T+Eng 100% Vice].smc</path>
		<name>Tommorow's Joe (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Vice

Ashita No Joe is a boxing game published by K Amusement and released in 1992. The game is based on a Japanese Manga popular in the 1970s and also known in the west as Tomorrow's Joe. The player takes the role of Joe Yabuki and must fight his way through an intense boxing tournament. Seven opponents stand between him and victory and each pro-boxer is tougher to beat than the last. Two buttons are used throughout the game - one throws basic straight punches and directional button combinations allows Joe to use uppercuts and hooks. The second button puts Joe in guard and lets him block attacks. Life bars on top of the screen display the players current status and the winner is decided through Knock Out on the third fall. A two-player mode is available.
</desc>
		<image>./images/2570510-ashita_no_joe_sfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>November 27, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>K.Amusement Leasing Co.</publisher>
		<genre>Boxing</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Torneko no Daibouken - Fushigi no Dungeon (J) (V1.0) [T+Eng.75a_MagicDestiny].smc</path>
		<name>Torneko no Daibouken - Fushigi no Dungeon (J) (V1.0) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.75a
Translated by MagicDestiny

Torneko no Daibōken: Fushigi no Dungeon (Torneko's Great Adventure: Mystery Dungeon?) is the first game in the Mystery Dungeon series. This installment features Torneko (or Taloon, as he was known in North America), the merchant from Dragon Warrior IV. The game involves Torneko adventuring around in the "Mystery Dungeon" in search of items.

During the higher levels of the game, monsters tend to chase the player in multiple numbers.
The gameplay is similar to roguelike style PC games. The main similarity is the heavy use of randomized dungeons and effects. The main character of the game is Torneko, originally localized as Taloon in North America, a merchant playable character from Dragon Warrior IV.[1] The game continues Torneko's story from Dragon Quest IV, where he wishes to make his store famous and ventures into mystery dungeons to retrieve items to stock in his store.

While Torneko explores the dungeon, he collects items and fights monsters, similar to the ones found in Dragon Quest games. If Torneko leaves the dungeon, he can sell off the items he found. He can also equip certain items found in the dungeon. By saving up money, Torneko can improve his home and shop.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Torneko no Daibouken - Fushigi no Dungeon (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>September 19, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Chunsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Chunsoft</publisher>
		<genre>RPG, Roguelike</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Treasure Hunter G (J)[T+Eng 100% PB2 MetalHawk].smc</path>
		<name>Treasure Hunter G (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by PB2 MetalHawk


Treasure Hunter G is a turn-based tactical role playing game developed by Sting Entertainment and published by Square (now Square Enix). It was released on May 24, 1996. It was published on the Nintendo's Virtual Console service on December 25, 2007 in Japan.

The game was not released outside Japan. This was Square's final game for a Nintendo console, released a scant two weeks before they announced their departure from Nintendo, until the release of Chocobo Land: A Game of Dice for the Game Boy Advance in 2002, in Japan.[2]

Treasure Hunter G's gameplay is very typical of its time, consisting of two types of gameplay (adventuring and combat). Adventuring is done in a fashion very similar to Squaresoft's Super Famicom games such as Chrono Trigger and Seiken Densetsu 3 with the group exploring various locations typical to the genre such as towns, forests, dungeons, castles and a few more fantastical locations. They make new allies and enemies and embark on a quest to stop the Dark Lord's plan of reviving Bone Dino and destroying the world. Combat takes place on a grid, with movement and fighting consuming varying amounts of Action Points. Other actions include using items, spells, special attacks and traps. Action Points increase during the game allowing for greater freedom in strategy.[citation needed]

The character sprites are pre-rendered from 3D models, rather than drawn by hand. This allowed for a feature unique among similar games for SNES: the character sprites are created for eight directions instead of the usual four.[citation needed]

</desc>
		<image>./images/Treasure Hunter G (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>May 24, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer>Sting</developer>
		<publisher>Square</publisher>
		<genre>Tactical RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Treasure Of Rudras (J)[T+Eng 100% AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Treasure Of Rudras (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Treasure of the Rudras is the last RPG with a "normal" battle system that Square produced for the SNES, with the exception of maybe Chrono Trigger which might have come after it. Regardless, a fan translation was long thought impossible due to the game's system of magic - it let players enter their own words into a screen similar to the one where they name their characters, and it would generate effects based on the words that the players typed in! Well, as my screenshots demonstrate, that system has been completely conquered, to the point where I've not only englishized it, but also doubled the number of letters per spell name! And don't let the graphics deceive you - the game's stat progression plays much more like a Dragon Warrior game than it does a Final Fantasy. Don't expect an easy ride, because you are -not- going to get one! Some of the bosses are positively nasty!

The story follows three humans, each of which holds a stone called a "Jade", as they work to stop the impending destruction of all life on their planet. They only have 16 days, and time will pass as they complete events - often times their scenarios, although separate, will intersect and a scene will take place between the two parties. Once all three scenarios have been completed, a fourth scenario opens as the story reaches its climax.

The new version, released on July 4, 2006, contains numerous improvements over the initial release. The font is now variable-width, the text has been completely retooled and polished, the opening's been rehacked, the battle menu's been moved to allow for two extra letters per enemy name, and a few smaller fixes have been implemented. Suffice it to say that this new version of the patch is the definitive English-language Treasure of the Rudras!
</desc>
		<image>./images/rudras.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>April 5, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Squaresoft</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ultra Baseball Jitsumeiban (J)[T+Eng 100% V1.04 VX].smc</path>
		<name>Ultra Baseball Jitsumeiban (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V1.04 
Translated by VX

Ultra Baseball Jitsumeiban is the third game in the Ultra Baseball (Baseball Simulator in the USA) series. It was released in 1992 for the Super Famicom by Culture Brain exclusively in Japan. The game remains much the same as the previous 1991 Super Baseball Simulator 1.000 with some new additions. This title included real life players from the NPB league; the word Jitsumeiban means Real Player Version. Additionally a World Series championship and an All-Stars option was added to this version.

In the game, there are three leagues: Central, Pacific and Ultra. Each league has six teams. In the Ultra League, pitchers and batters have special power-ups that boost their abilities which gives the game a surrealistic feel that is rare in the sports genre. Players can even create their own baseball teams and assign special moves to the players that they name themselves. The game can be played in exhibition, season or All-Stars modes.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Ubbj.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>August 28, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Culture Brain</publisher>
		<genre>Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Umihara Kawase (J)[T+Eng 90% V0.90 Satsu].smc</path>
		<name>Umihara Kawase (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 90% V0.90 
Translated by Satsu

The game world of Umihara Kawase is constructed from a set of interconnected levels known as fields. Each field connects to one or more fields deeper within the game via doors.

Fields are enclosed areas containing a number of static and moving platforms, ladders, spikes, enemy sea-life and one or more exit doors. The doors are often positioned in hard to reach places and it is the player's goal to plan a safe route to one. Each exit door in a field takes the player to a different field, and the goal is to find a safe route through the fields and arrive at a final exit door (at which point the credits scroll and the game is over). Each of the Umihara Kawase games contains multiple routes through the fields and multiple final exits. Using shortcuts and optimised door routes can allow the game to be completed within minutes in the hands of a skilled player; however, enjoyment of the game typically lies not in merely making it to the first or easiest final exit door, but in exploring the game's many routes and mastering the challenging rope physics.

The Umihara Kawase games have simple controls. The protagonist is able to run, jump, climb onto ledges, climb ladders and, crucially, throw her fishing line. When thrown, the fishing line will hook onto nearly all surfaces within the games. When the line is firmly hooked onto a surface or an enemy fish the line is able to take her weight. From here Umihara is able to swing between platforms, lower herself down to other ledges and swing herself up to higher ledges. Due to the flexible nature of her line she can also catapult herself great distances by stretching the line to breaking point. The line can also be used to stun fish and reel them in, and once reeled in Umihara will store them in her rucksack and score points in doing so.

While the controls are simple and responsive, an uncompromising physics model means that graceful control of the game's swinging techniques will not come immediately. Out of this, though, comes great scope for advanced techniques through full utilization of the physics. Perfect execution of techniques such as the one- and two-step rocket jump are required both in later fields and for those who intend to improve their field completion times.

The games contain 1ups in the shape of Umihara's pink rucksack but no other collectibles are present.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Umihara Kawase (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 23, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>TNN/NHK SC</developer>
		<publisher>TNN</publisher>
		<genre>Platformer</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Villgust - Kieta Shoujo (J) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_MagicDestiny].smc</path>
		<name>Villgust - Kieta Shoujo (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by MagicDestiny

Kouryuu Densetsu Villgust: Kieta Shoujo ("Radiant/Armed Dragon Legend Villgust: Missing Girl") is a Super Famicom RPG from Winkysoft. The player is a regular schoolkid from modern Japan who has to rescue his girlfriend from a parallel fantasy universe named Villgust. He quickly encounters and befriends several warriors who are part of R.A.G.E. (Resistance Against the God of Evil) who are attempting to take back their world from evil forces.

The game was followed up with a spin-off for the Famicom: Kouryuu Densetsu Villgust: Gaiden. It was also adapted into a pair of anime OVAs that came out several months after the game's release.

Characters
Shun - The main hero. Attempting to rescue his girlfriend. Like many RPG heroes, he's the best fighter in the group and has access to the strongest equipment.
Michiko - Shun's girlfriend. She mysteriously appeared in Villgust and was quickly kidnapped. Doesn't fight.
Kui - The toughest member of the initial group of RAGE that Shun meets soon after entering Villgust. A powerful front-line attacker.
Chris - A skilled swordswoman with an acerbic attitude.
Yuta - Another warrior with limited magical ability. A man of few words.
Fanna - A female archer and the most powerful magic-user of the initial group.
Murobo - A strong wolf-like beastman. Uses a giant axe in combat.
Ryukia - A cat-like beastgirl who uses her claws in combat. Has purple hair and an optimistic outlook.
Bostov - A dexterous ninja character that can attack whole groups of enemies with his boomerang.
Lemi (Remi) - A female elf and a strong magic-user. Fights with a retractable whip staff.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Kōryū_Densetsu_Villgust_Cover.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>May 23, 1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Winkysoft</developer>
		<publisher>Bandai</publisher>
		<genre>Comedy / Action / RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Wedding Peach (J) [T+Eng.9_Chaotic].smc</path>
		<name>Wedding Peach (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng.9
Translated by Chaotic

A Super Famicom game was released only in Japan in 1995. In the game, the player plays as one of the three main girls (either Momoko, Yuri or Hinagiku) to compete with the others in a series of mini games. The ultimate goal is to win the right to ask the guy that all three girls are in love with (Yanagiba) to the school dance. The game has a three player option as well, where two other people can play the other two girls.
</desc>
		<image>./images/2257224-wedding_peach___sfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 29, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Nihon Soft System</developer>
		<publisher>KSS</publisher>
		<genre>Dating Sim</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Wizardry I-II-III - Story of Llylgamyn (J) (NP) [T+Eng 100% 1.00_AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Wizardry I-II-III - Story of Llylgamyn (J) (NP) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% 1.00
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Talk about unforgiving! Wizardry (all three of them, in this case) is an EXTREMELY unforgiving dungeon-crawler RPG which is quite reminiscient of Advanced Dungeons and Dragons (with a merciless DM) and old BBS door games. The only problem I have with this game is that it has no qualms with killing off half of your party in the first fight or two and not giving you enough cash to heal the members of your party that AREN´T dead. Aside from that, it´s a damn good game, and well worth the hours of banging your head against the wall :) It´s been brought to my attention that there -are- some bugs in the patch, so one of these summers when I have scads of free time and have all my projects completed, I´ll completely isolate myself from the rest of the world and attempt to go through at least ONE of the games in a month, heh. I seriously mean to play through this thing at some point, but it requires so much raw TIME that it´s kind of hard to do so :( Anyway, be sure to read the readme, it contains important information about the nature of this particular translation!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Wizardry I-II-III - Story of Llylgamyn (Japan) (NP) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>January 1, 1996</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Wizardry VI - Bane of the Cosmic Forge (J)[T+Eng 99% V0.99a Tico].smc</path>
		<name>Wizardry VI - Bane of the Cosmic Forge (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 99% V0.99a 
Translated by Tico

Wizardry VI: Bane of the Cosmic Forge (originally known as Wizardry: Bane of the Cosmic Forge) is the 6th title in the Wizardry series of role-playing video games. It was the first in the trilogy surrounding the Dark Savant, which was followed by Wizardry VII: Crusaders of the Dark Savant and Wizardry 8. It was developed by Sir-Tech Software, Inc. and was released on the Amiga and DOS platforms in 1990 by the same company, and for the Super Famicom in Japan in 1995 by ASCII.

Although based upon previous games in the series, David Bradley completely rewrote the system for this release. This was the first game in the series to feature full color graphics.[1] The game was mouse-driven and ran with EGA graphics. It was also one of the few games in the Wizardry series that would not allow characters to be imported from previous games. The character creation and level-up process was more detailed than in previous releases. The player can choose from eleven races and fourteen professions.[2] There are multiple skills divided into three categories, and magic is divided into six schools. Combat also allowed several different options, such as thrust or bash, depending on the weapon selected.[3]

Wizardry VI is a first person, tile-based and menu-driven RPG. Its monsters and races are made up of many mythological creatures and people, from the fictitious, to even some real life races and people. The player may meet Sirens and Charron from Greek mythology, the Amazulu (a group of African warrior women, whose tribal name is derived from the Amazons of Greek legend, and the Zulu of Africa), and even the Caterpillar from Lewis Carroll's Alice in Wonderland.
</desc>
		<image>./images/wizardry6sfc.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>September 20, 1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Sir-Tech Software Inc</developer>
		<publisher>ASCII</publisher>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Wonder Project J - Kikai no Shounen Pino (J) [T+Eng1.04_WakdHacks].smc</path>
		<name>Wonder Project J - Kikai no Shounen Pino (J) </name>
		<desc>T+Eng1.04
Translated by WakdHacks

Wonder Project J: Kikai no Shōnen Pīno is a Japan-exclusive video game published by Enix for the Super Famicom in 1994. The game was developed by Almanic, which also developed the Enix-published E.V.O.: Search for Eden.

The game is a raising simulation in which the player raises a Pinocchio-esque boy, whose default name is "Pino", to succeed in various challenges and confrontations to activate virtue circuits, with his final task to foster relations between humans and the robot-like Gijin. Its sequel, Wonder Project J2: Corlo no Mori no Josette, was released on the Nintendo 64 two years later.
</desc>
		<image>./images/Wonder Project J - Kikai no Shounen Pino (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>December 9, 1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Almanic</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Life simulation game</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ys IV - Mask of the Sun (J)[T+Eng 100% V2 AGTP].smc</path>
		<name>Ys IV - Mask of the Sun (J)</name>
		<desc>T+Eng 100% V2 
Translated by Aeon Genesis Translation Project

Whee, Ys! FUN! This game is rather unique in its combat style, which is explained well enough in the readme that I´m not going to try to describe it here. In any case, unlike its PCE-CD brother (Ys IV - Dawn of Ys) this game appears to follow the anime OAVs more than it follows the game series. Some of the characters (Norton and Vixen in particular) aren´t really introduced in any of the games, Ys Eternal included. The nice thing though is that the Port City of Minea, Minea Plains, and all the other returning areas from previous Ys games have, in general, had their town layout kept the same while the graphics were merely improved upon. While not strictly necessary, it´s a nice touch :D Anyway, once you get the hang of it, this game is really fun, so give it a try already!
</desc>
		<image>./images/Ys IV - Mask of the Sun (Japan) (Translated En).png</image>
		<releasedate>November 19, 1993</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher>Nihon Falcom/Tonkinhouse</publisher>
		<genre>Action/RPG</genre>
	</game>
</gameList>
