<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Ecco - The Tides of Time (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Ecco: The Tides of Time</name>
		<desc>The Tides of Time picked up right where the original Ecco the Dolphin left off. It turned out that the Vortex Queen was far from vanquished, and had, in fact, followed Ecco to Earth to build a new hive for herself. Ecco lost his powers from the Asterite early on, and soon after met a dolphin with unusually long fins. She was his descendant, Trellia, and had come to take him to her present in Ecco's distant future.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Ecco - The Tides of Time (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>08/25/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Novotrade International</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Final Fight CD (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Final Fight</name>
		<desc>The Sega Mega CD version, titled Final Fight CD, was ported and published by Sega under license from Capcom in 1993. This version retains nearly all the features of the arcade game (namely the 2-player game mode, the Industrial Area stage, and the ability to play as any of the three main characters), adding voice acting to the game's opening and ending sequence, an arranged version of the original soundtrack, and an exclusive time attack mode. 

The Mega CD version was still censored for the English localization with many of the same changes. Poison and Roxy were kept this time, but were redrawn with less revealing clothing (longer shorts and shirts) to hide all nudity</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Final Fight CD (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Flashback - The Quest for Identity (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Flashback: The Quest for Identity</name>
		<desc>Flashback is a platform action adventure. You navigate Conrad over the platforms, performing various moves. You can simply jump or do a longer run-and-jump, run, climb, hang off ledges, and pick up objects lying on the ground. To defend yourself, you shoot enemies with your gun and also use various objects (such as stones) to harm or to distract them.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Flashback - The Quest for Identity (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Delphine Software</developer>
		<publisher>U.S. Gold</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Heart of the Alien - Out of This World Parts I and II (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Heart of the Alien:Out of this World Parts I And II</name>
		<desc>Heart of the Alien is the sequel to the game Out of this World, also known as Another World. The story picks up immediately after the end of the first game. You begin as Lester and his alien friend, "Buddy," land their pterodactyl in the ruins of Buddy's village. Lester was knocked unconscious in their escape, so Buddy lays him down on a cot to rest. The people who used to live in Buddy's village remain enslaved, so he decides to go on a mission to free them. Thus, you control Buddy as he sets off to free the people and find a way to send Lester home.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Heart of the Alien - Out of This World Parts I and II (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Delphine</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Keio Flying Squadron (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Keio Flying Squadron</name>
		<desc>Keio Flying Squadron chronicles the adventures of Rami, the little bunny-suited member of the flying squadron tasked with the protection of the "Special Holy Object". Unfortunately as the game starts the object in question gets stolen by the evil Dr. Pon, and so Rami jumps atop her trusty dragon in pursuit of Dr. Pon.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Keio Flying Squadron (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>08/06/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Victor Musical</developer>
		<publisher>JVC</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lords of Thunder (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Lords of Thunder</name>
		<desc>In the once peaceful land of Mistral, legend holds of a brave knight named Drak who has sealed an evil god named Deoric beneath the six continents of the land. However, peace never lasts. The Garuda Empire has invaded the lands of Mistral, and the six Dark Generals, led by Sornbul, have conquered the continents. Sornbul's ambition is nothing less than to resurrect Deoric and plunge the land into chaos.

Duran, descendant of Drak, is the only one who can stop the Garuda Empire's mad plan, and with the power of Drak's mystic armors, he heads off to stop Sornbul at any cost.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Lords of Thunder (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lunar - Eternal Blue (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Lunar: Eternal Blue</name>
		<desc>Come back to the enchanting world of Lunar! Join Hiro and Ruby 1,000 years after the first adventure, as they work to unlock the secrets of the Blue Spire and the strange young girl they found within it! But be careful! Forces are at work trying to revive the evil Zophar and immerse Lunar in darkness forever! Journey to distant lands in search of the Goddess Althena, who may be the only one powerful enough to stop Zophar. Along the way, you'll meet exciting new characters, fight fully animated monsters, traverse snow-covered peaks, and crawl through slimy dungeons as you work towards the terrifying climax!</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Lunar - Eternal Blue (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>09/15/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Game Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lunar - The Silver Star (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Lunar: The Silver Star</name>
		<desc>Welcome to the world of Lunar, where dragons yet live and magic is valued above all else. Join Alex, the young adventurer as he begins a quest with his friends to save their land from the crushing advances of the Magic Emperor. Explore dungeons, fight terrifying monsters, and gather information from the locals as you advance toward the explosive confrontation with the Magic Emperor himself! Exciting, menu-driven combat will keep you challenged until the last. And thanks to the storage power of the CD, Lunar contains awesome animation sequences that'll get you involved in the story -- fast! Get ready for the ride of your life...</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Lunar - The Silver Star (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Game Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./dw-marko.CUE</path>
		<name>Marko</name>
		<desc>Welcome to the world of Marko, a world of cartoon madness. Experience the addictive blend of football skills and platform action that combine to make a superb gameplaying experience. Add the most incredible graphics ever to be seen and the result is Marko's Magic Football. It's just like playing a cartoon.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/dw-marko-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>The Kremlin</developer>
		<publisher>Domark</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./PTSM2.cue</path>
		<name>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors</name>
		<desc>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors is a Simulation game, developed and published by Absolute Entertainment, which was cancelled before it was released.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/PTSM2-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>04/01/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Absolute Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./PTSM1.cue</path>
		<name>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors</name>
		<desc>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors is a Simulation game, developed and published by Absolute Entertainment, which was cancelled before it was released.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/PTSM1-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>04/01/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>Absolute Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Popful Mail (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Popful Mail</name>
		<desc>Set in a fantasy world, the story begins with an animated sequence where the main character, Popful Mail, squares off with the criminal Nuts Cracker in a forest. Though defeated, Nuts Cracker's body manages to escape, as always, and Mail thus cannot claim any bounty. Frustrated once more, she off-putedly takes Nuts Cracker's head and wanders until she finds a town. In the town, she attempts to trade the head for cash, but fails. Instead, however, she learns of a new bounty and becomes reinvigorated when she spots a 2,000,000 gold reward poster for the wizard criminal, Muttonhead, near the store. With this, she embarks on her adventure.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Popful Mail (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>02/23/1995</releasedate>
		<developer>FALCOM</developer>
		<publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Road Rash (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Road Rash</name>
		<desc>Road Rash for Sega CD is another title in the series, this time it's an attempt to mate the classic gameplay of Genesis Road Rash games with full-motion video and avant-garde rock soundtrack.

This game was released the same time with the famous 3DO Road Rash. And it borrowed a lot of content from the Panasonic 3DO version: all the FMV videos, CD-quality soundtrack and overall menu design. The quality of FMV and music is inferior to 3DO version given the limitations of Sega CD hardware. Graphically and gameplay-wise the game is a continuation of Road Rash II for Sega Genesis.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Road Rash (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>01/01/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>New Level Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Robo Aleste (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Robo Aleste</name>
		<desc>Pilot your massive mecha Aleste in the name of the Oda clan and seek revenge against the evil Chugoku Army for their atrocities!  Robo Aleste is another title in the Aleste series by famed shoot-'em-up developer Compile where players must collect power-ups to defeat countless waves of enemies and large bosses.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Robo Aleste (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>11/27/1992</releasedate>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Tengen</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shining Force CD (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Shining Force CD</name>
		<desc>This strategy RPG is a remastered compilation of two earlier Shining force titles: Shining Force Gaiden (originally released in Japan only) and Shining Force: The Sword of Hajya, both for the Game Gear.  The two stories put players in the role of Nick, a hero of royal blood who must rescue Queen Anri of Gardiana and reclaim the kingdom of Cypress from the evil empire of Iom's clutches.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Shining Force CD (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>07/21/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Sonic! Software Planning</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Snatcher (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Snatcher</name>
		<desc>Snatcher is set in the futuristic Neo Kobe City, a city of madness and decadence. The year is 2047 (or 2042, according to the original Japanese version). Mankind is facing its gravest crisis. A mysterious bio-roid life form has appeared. Its true nature and purpose are unknown. Is it some country's secret weapon, or an alien from another world? They appear in the winter, killing people and taking their place in society. They wear artificial skin and can sweat and even bleed. They are called "Snatchers" because they "snatch" their victims before they take their place.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Snatcher (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>11/30/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic CD (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Sonic CD</name>
		<desc>Sonic's gameplay remains similar to that of Sonic the Hedgehog but with the addition of the Spin Dash and the Super Peel Out, which lets him zoom into a quick speed from a standing point.The main innovation of this chapter in the Sonic series is the manner in which the player can travel to four different versions of each zone, each a different time period of the same location: Present, Past, Good Future and Bad Future. This is accomplished by speed posts scattered around the level, bearing the labels "Past", and "Future". After running through one of these posts, the player has to run at top speed for a few seconds without stopping, to travel into the respective time period. Because these teleports are relative, there are no "Past" signs in the Past, and no "Future" signs in the Future; that is, warping to the past in the future returns the player to the "present" time and vice versa.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Sonic CD (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<rating>10.000000</rating>
		<releasedate>09/23/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Soulstar (USA).cue</path>
		<name>SoulStar</name>
		<desc>Soulstar for the Sega CD/Mega CD is a 3D shoot-'em up that combines several different types of gameplay into one game. Some levels in this game are on a fixed path, similar to Space Harrier or Star Fox. Other levels allow your space craft to hover freely around a 3D environment, and in other levels your craft transforms into a walker robot for close-up attacks.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Soulstar (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>12/21/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>Core Design</developer>
		<publisher>Core Design</publisher>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin, The (USA).cue</path>
		<name>The Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin</name>
		<desc>The Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin for the Sega CD takes the idea and basic gameplay from the Genesis version, but makes some significant changes. There are new levels, new bosses, and an expanded set of combat moves. The player now has the freedom to select the next level or boss to tackle from a map screen. Graphics have also been redrawn and expanded from the Genesis release. However, the player can no longer rest and heal at Peter Parker's apartment, or take photographs of enemies for cash; both prominent features of the Genesis version.

Animated cutscenes with voices are new to this version, as well as a new CD soundtrack. The player can also find and collect digital versions of classic Spider-Man comics, making further use of the multimedia storage space. A password system has also been added to save the player's progress.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin, The (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>11/03/1993</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Vay (USA).cue</path>
		<name>Vay</name>
		<desc>Vay is the story of Prince Sandor of Lorath, and his quest to avenge the assassination of his parents and rescue his beloved Lady Elin. On what is to be the day of their wedding, Castle Lorath is assaulted by the Danek, who have been able to partially reconstruct alien mecha technology from a millennium ago. The castle defenses are powerless against the giant robots, and the king and queen are killed in the attack. The invaders steal Elin in the midst of her wedding vows. Prince Sandor, now the king of the realm, sets out to rescue his betrothed, and find a way to defeat the fearsome alien technology.</desc>
		<image>~/RetroPie/roms/images/Vay (USA)-image.jpeg</image>
		<releasedate>04/14/1994</releasedate>
		<developer>SIMS Co.</developer>
		<publisher>SIMS Co.</publisher>
	</game>
</gameList>
